[{"answer": "3 Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost; wherefore, they speak the words of Christ. Wherefore, I said unto you, feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all things what ye should do. ", "question": "2 Nephi 32: 3"}, {"answer": "  17 And behold, I tell you these things that ye may learn wisdom; that ye may learn that when ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God.\n", "question": "Mosiah 2: 17"}, {"answer": "  30 But this much I can tell you, that if ye do not watch yourselves, and your thoughts, and your words, and your deeds, and observe the commandments of God, and continue in the faith of what ye have heard concerning the coming of our Lord, even unto the end of your lives, ye must perish. And now, O man, remember, and perish not.\n", "question": "Mosiah 4: 30"}, {"answer": "21 And now as I said concerning faith\u2014faith is not to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore if ye have faith ye hope for things which are not seen, which are true.", "question": "Alma 32: 21"}, {"answer": "  6 Now ye may suppose that this is foolishness in me; but behold I say unto you, that by small and simple things are great things brought to pass; and small means in many instances doth confound the wise.\n  7 And the Lord God doth work by means to bring about his great and eternal purposes; and by very small means the Lord doth confound the wise and bringeth about the salvation of many souls.\n", "question": "Alma 37: 6-7"}, {"answer": "  35 O, remember, my son, and learn wisdom in thy youth; yea, learn in thy youth to keep the commandments of God.\n", "question": "Alma 37: 35"}, {"answer": "45 And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.\r\n46 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not charity, ye are nothing, for charity never faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all, for all things must fail\u2014\r\n47 But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.\r\n48 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.", "question": "Moroni 7: 45-48"}, {"answer": "  5 Pray always, that you may come off conqueror; yea, that you may conquer Satan, and that you may escape the hands of the servants of Satan that do uphold his work.\n", "question": "D&C 10: 5"}, {"answer": "  10 I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise.\n", "question": "D&C 82: 10"}, {"answer": "  18 Whatever principle of intelligence we attain unto in this life, it will rise with us in the resurrection.\n  19 And if a person gains more knowledge and intelligence in this life through his diligence and obedience than another, he will have so much the advantage in the world to come.\n", "question": "D&C 130: 18-19"}, {"answer": "36 And as they thus spake, Jesus himself stood in the midst of them, and saith unto them, Peace be unto you.\r\n37 But they were terrified and affrighted, and supposed that they had seen a spirit.\r\n38 And he said unto them, Why are ye troubled? and why do thoughts arise in your hearts?\r\n39 Behold my hands and my feet, that it is I myself: handle me, and see; for a spirit hath not flesh and bones, as ye see me have.", "question": "Luke 24: 36-39"}, {"answer": "  5 Jesus answered, Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born of water and of the Spirit, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God.\n", "question": "John 3: 5"}, {"answer": "13 There hath no temptation taken you but such as is common to man: but God is faithful, who will not suffer you to be tempted above that ye are able; but will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear it.", "question": "1 Corinthians 10: 13"}, {"answer": "  17 Even so faith, if it hath not works, is dead, being alone.\n  18 Yea, a man may say, Thou hast faith, and I have works: shew me thy faith without thy works, and I will shew thee my faith by my works.\n  19 Thou believest that there is one God; thou doest well: the devils also believe, and tremble.\n  20 But wilt thou know, O vain man, that faith without works is dead?\n", "question": "James 2: 17-20"}, {"answer": "26 And God said, Let us make man in our image, after our likeness: and let them have dominion over the fish of the sea, and over the fowl of the air, and over the cattle, and over all the earth, and over every creeping thing that creepeth upon the earth.\r\n27 So God created man in his own image, in the image of God created he him; male and female created he them.", "question": "Genesis 1: 26-27"}, {"answer": "9 There is none greater in this house than I; neither hath he kept back any thing from me but thee, because thou art his wife: how then can I do this great wickedness, and sin against God?", "question": "Genesis 39: 9"}, {"answer": "18 Thou shalt not avenge, nor bear any grudge against the children of thy people, but thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself: I am the Lord.", "question": "Leviticus 19: 18"}, {"answer": "18 Come now, and let us reason together, saith the Lord: though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool.", "question": "Isaiah 1: 18"}, {"answer": "44 And in the days of these kings shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom, which shall never be destroyed: and the kingdom shall not be left to other people, but it shall break in pieces and consume all these kingdoms, and it shall stand for ever.\r\n45 Forasmuch as thou sawest that the stone was cut out of the mountain without hands, and that it brake in pieces the iron, the brass, the clay, the silver, and the gold; the great God hath made known to the king what shall come to pass hereafter: and the dream is certain, and the interpretation thereof sure.", "question": "Daniel 2: 44-45"}, {"answer": "  7 Surely the Lord God will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets.\n", "question": "Amos 3: 7"}, {"answer": "7 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, said unto my father: I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.", "question": "1 Nephi 3: 7"}, {"answer": "  15 If ye love me, keep my commandments.\n", "question": "John 14: 15"}, {"answer": "  10 Do not suppose, because it has been spoken concerning restoration, that ye shall be restored from sin to happiness. Behold, I say unto you, wickedness never was happiness.\n", "question": "Alma 41: 10"}, {"answer": "29 For verily, verily I say unto you, he that hath the spirit of contention is not of me, but is of the devil, who is the father of contention, and he stirreth up the hearts of men to contend with anger, one with another.\r\n30 Behold, this is not my doctrine, to stir up the hearts of men with anger, one against another; but this is my doctrine, that such things should be done away.", "question": "3 Nephi 11: 29-30"}, {"answer": "27 And know ye that ye shall be judges of this people, according to the judgment which I shall give unto you, which shall be just. Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.", "question": "3 Nephi 27: 27"}, {"answer": "  6 And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.\n", "question": "Ether 12: 6"}, {"answer": "  27 And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; and my grace is sufficient for all men that humble themselves before me; for if they humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.\n", "question": "Ether 12: 27"}, {"answer": "24 No man can serve two masters: for either he will hate the one, and love the other; or else he will hold to the one, and despise the other. Ye cannot serve God and mammon.", "question": "Matthew 6: 24"}, {"answer": "11 And the Lord spake unto Moses face to face, as a man speaketh unto his friend. And he turned again into the camp: but his servant Joshua, the son of Nun, a young man, departed not out of the tabernacle.", "question": "Exodus 33: 11"}, {"answer": "8 This book of the law shall not depart out of thy mouth; but thou shalt meditate therein day and night, that thou mayest observe to do according to all that is written therein: for then thou shalt make thy way prosperous, and then thou shalt have good success.", "question": "Joshua 1: 8"}, {"answer": "15 And if it seem evil unto you to serve the Lord, choose you this day whom ye will serve; whether the gods which your fathers served that were on the other side of the flood, or the gods of the Amorites, in whose land ye dwell: but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.", "question": "Joshua 24: 15"}, {"answer": "7 But the Lord said unto Samuel, Look not on his countenance, or on the height of his stature; because I have refused him: for the Lord seeth not as man seeth; for man looketh on the outward appearance, but the Lord looketh on the heart.", "question": "1 Samuel 16: 7"}, {"answer": "16 Behold, I will send for many fishers, saith the Lord, and they shall fish them; and after will I send for many hunters, and they shall hunt them from every mountain, and from every hill, and out of the holes of the rocks.", "question": "Jeremiah 16: 16"}, {"answer": "40 And the King shall answer and say unto them, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.", "question": "Matthew 25: 40"}, {"answer": "  3 And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.\n", "question": "John 17: 3"}, {"answer": "16 For I am not ashamed of the gospel of Christ: for it is the power of God unto salvation to every one that believeth; to the Jew first, and also to the Greek.", "question": "Romans 1: 16"}, {"answer": "29 Else what shall they do which are baptized for the dead, if the dead rise not at all? why are they then baptized for the dead?", "question": "1 Corinthians 15: 29"}, {"answer": "4 And no man taketh this honour unto himself, but he that is called of God, as was Aaron.", "question": "Hebrews 5: 4"}, {"answer": "25 Adam fell that men might be; and men are, that they might have joy.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 25"}, {"answer": "27 Wherefore, men are free according to the flesh; and all things are given them which are expedient unto man. And they are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil; for he seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 27"}, {"answer": "  19 For the natural man is an enemy to God, and has been from the fall of Adam, and will be, forever and ever, unless he yields to the enticings of the Holy Spirit, and putteth off the natural man and becometh a saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord, and becometh as a child, submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things which the Lord seeth fit to inflict upon him, even as a child doth submit to his father.\n", "question": "Mosiah 3: 19"}, {"answer": "  7 And, if you keep my commandments and endure to the end you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.\n", "question": "D&C 14: 7"}, {"answer": "  12 For my soul delighteth in the song of the heart; yea, the song of the righteous is a prayer unto me, and it shall be answered with a blessing upon their heads.\n", "question": "D&C 25: 12"}, {"answer": "  23 Behold, now it is called today until the coming of the Son of Man, and verily it is a day of sacrifice, and a day for the tithing of my people; for he that is tithed shall not be burned at his coming.\n", "question": "D&C 64: 23"}, {"answer": "  3 For of him unto whom much is given much is required; and he who sins against the greater light shall receive the greater condemnation.\n", "question": "D&C 82: 3"}, {"answer": "39 For behold, this is my work and my glory\u2014to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.", "question": "Moses 1: 39"}, {"answer": "  18 And the Lord called his people Zion, because they were of one heart and one mind, and dwelt in righteousness; and there was no poor among them.\n", "question": "Moses 7: 18"}, {"answer": "23 And I did read many things unto them which were written in the books of Moses; but that I might more fully persuade them to believe in the Lord their Redeemer I did read unto them that which was written by the prophet Isaiah; for I did liken all scriptures unto us, that it might be for our profit and learning.", "question": "1 Nephi 19: 23"}, {"answer": "28 O that cunning plan of the evil one! O the vainness, and the frailties, and the foolishness of men! When they are learned they think they are wise, and they hearken not unto the counsel of God, for they set it aside, supposing they know of themselves, wherefore, their wisdom is foolishness and it profiteth them not. And they shall perish.\r\n29 But to be learned is good if they hearken unto the counsels of God.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 28-29"}, {"answer": "8 And now, my beloved brethren, I perceive that ye ponder still in your hearts; and it grieveth me that I must speak concerning this thing. For if ye would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man to pray ye would know that ye must pray; for the evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray, but teacheth him that he must not pray.\r\n9 But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray always, and not faint; that ye must not perform any thing unto the Lord save in the first place ye shall pray unto the Father in the name of Christ, that he will consecrate thy performance unto thee, that thy performance may be for the welfare of thy soul.", "question": "2 Nephi 32: 8-9"}, {"answer": "7 Yea, and there shall be many which shall say: Eat, drink, and be merry, for tomorrow we die; and it shall be well with us.\r\n8 And there shall also be many which shall say: Eat, drink, and be merry; nevertheless, fear God\u2014he will justify in committing a little sin; yea, lie a little, take the advantage of one because of his words, dig a pit for thy neighbor; there is no harm in this; and do all these things, for tomorrow we die; and if it so be that we are guilty, God will beat us with a few stripes, and at last we shall be saved in the kingdom of God.\r\n9 Yea, and there shall be many which shall teach after this manner, false and vain and foolish doctrines, and shall be puffed up in their hearts, and shall seek deep to hide their counsels from the Lord; and their works shall be in the dark.", "question": "2 Nephi 28: 7-9"}, {"answer": "18 But before ye seek for riches, seek ye for the kingdom of God.\r\n19 And after ye have obtained a hope in Christ ye shall obtain riches, if ye seek them; and ye will seek them for the intent to do good\u2014to clothe the naked, and to feed the hungry, and to liberate the captive, and administer relief to the sick and the afflicted.\r\n", "question": "Jacob 2: 18-19"}, {"answer": "  31 Yea, I would that ye would come forth and harden not your hearts any longer; for behold, now is the time and the day of your salvation; and therefore, if ye will repent and harden not your hearts, immediately shall the great plan of redemption be brought about unto you.\n  32 For behold, this life is the time for men to prepare to meet God; yea, behold the day of this life is the day for men to perform their labors.\n  33 And now, as I said unto you before, as ye have had so many witnesses, therefore, I beseech of you that ye do not procrastinate the day of your repentance until the end; for after this day of life, which is given us to prepare for eternity, behold, if we do not improve our time while in this life, then cometh the night of darkness wherein there can be no labor performed.\n  34 Ye cannot say, when ye are brought to that awful crisis, that I will repent, that I will return to my God. Nay, ye cannot say this; for that same spirit which doth possess your bodies at the time that ye go out of this life, that same spirit will have power to possess your body in that eternal world.\n  35 For behold, if ye have procrastinated the day of your repentance even until death, behold, ye have become subjected to the spirit of the devil, and he doth seal you his; therefore, the Spirit of the Lord hath withdrawn from you, and hath no place in you, and the devil hath all power over you; and this is the final state of the wicked.\n", "question": "Alma 34: 31-35"}, {"answer": "12 And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall.", "question": "Helaman 5: 12"}, {"answer": "16 For behold, the Spirit of Christ is given to every man, that he may know good from evil; wherefore, I show unto you the way to judge; for every thing which inviteth to do good, and to persuade to believe in Christ, is sent forth by the power and gift of Christ; wherefore ye may know with a perfect knowledge it is of God.\r\n17 But whatsoever thing persuadeth men to do evil, and believe not in Christ, and deny him, and serve not God, then ye may know with a perfect knowledge it is of the devil; for after this manner doth the devil work, for he persuadeth no man to do good, no, not one; neither do his angels; neither do they who subject themselves unto him.\r\n", "question": "Moroni 7: 16-17"}, {"answer": "3 Behold, I would exhort you that when ye shall read these things, if it be wisdom in God that ye should read them, that ye would remember how merciful the Lord hath been unto the children of men, from the creation of Adam even down until the time that ye shall receive these things, and ponder it in your hearts.\r\n4 And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.\r\n5 And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.", "question": "Moroni 10: 3-5"}, {"answer": "  37 Search these commandments, for they are true and faithful, and the prophecies and promises which are in them shall all be fulfilled.\n  38 What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.\n", "question": "D&C 1: 37-38"}, {"answer": "  2 Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.\n  3 Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation; behold, this is the spirit by which Moses brought the children of Israel through the Red Sea on dry ground.\n", "question": "D&C 8: 2-3"}, {"answer": "42 Behold, he who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.\r\n43 By this ye may know if a man repenteth of his sins\u2014behold, he will confess them and forsake them.", "question": "D&C 58: 42-43"}, {"answer": "20  There is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated-\r\n21  And when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated.", "question": "D&C 130: 20-21"}, {"answer": "  22  The Father has a body of flesh and bones as tangible as man's; the Son also; but the Holy Ghost has not a body of flesh and bones, but is a personage of Spirit.  Were it not so, the Holy Ghost could not dwell in us.\n  23  A man may receive the Holy Ghost, and it may descend upon him and not tarry with him.\n\n", "question": "D&C 130: 22-23"}, {"answer": "  16  For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent;\n  17  But if they would not repent they must suffer even as I;\n  18  Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit - and would that I might not drink the bitter cup, and shrink -\n  19  Nevertheless, glory be to the Father, and I partook and finished my preparations unto the children of men.\n\n", "question": "D&C 19: 16-19"}, {"answer": "  5  Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.\n  6  In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths.\n", "question": "Proverbs 3: 5-6"}, {"answer": "  5 If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.\n  6 But let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.\n", "question": "James 1: 5-6"}, {"answer": "  8  For my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the Lord.\n  9  For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts.\n", "question": "Isaiah 55: 8-9"}, {"answer": "3  Who shall ascend into the hill of the Lord? or who shall stand in his holy place?\r\n4  He that hath clean hands, and a pure heart; who hath not lifted up his soul unto vanity, nor sworn deceitfully.", "question": "Psalms 24: 3-4"}, {"answer": "  25  For I know that my redeemer liveth, and that he shall stand at the latter day upon the earth:\n  26  And though after my skin worms destroy this body, yet in my flesh shall I see God:\n", "question": "Job 19: 25-26"}, {"answer": "  3  He is despised and rejected of men; a man of sorrows, and acquainted with grief: and we hid as it were our faces from him; he was despised, and we esteemed him not.\n  4  Surely he hath borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows: yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten of God, and afflicted.\n  5  But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities: the chastisement of our peace was upon him; and with his stripes we are healed.\n  6  All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the Lord hath laid on him the iniquity of us all.\n", "question": "Isaiah 53: 3-6"}, {"answer": "  17 If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.\n", "question": "John 7: 17"}, {"answer": "  16 And other sheep I have, which are not of this fold: them also I must bring, and they shall hear my voice; and there shall be one fold, and one shepherd.\n", "question": "John 10: 16"}, {"answer": "14 Ye are the light of the world. A city that is set on an hill cannot be hid.\r\n15 Neither do men light a candle, and put it under a bushel, but on a candlestick; and it giveth light unto all that are in the house.\r\n16 Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.", "question": "Matthew 5: 14-16"}, {"answer": "  9 And that thou mayest more fully keep thyself unspotted from the world, thou shalt go to the house of prayer and offer up thy sacraments upon my holy day;\n  10 For verily this is a day appointed unto you to rest from your labors, and to pay thy devotions unto the Most High;\n", "question": "D&C 59: 9-10"}, {"answer": "5 Behold, I will send you Elijah the prophet before the coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord:\r\n6 And he shall turn the heart of the fathers to the children, and the heart of the children to their fathers, lest I come and smite the earth with a curse.", "question": "Malachi 4: 5-6"}, {"answer": "  26 For behold, it is not meet that I should command in all things; for he that is compelled in all things, the same is a slothful and not a wise servant; wherefore he receiveth no reward.\n  27 Verily I say, men should be anxiously engaged in a good cause, and do many things of their own free will, and bring to pass much righteousness;\n  28 For the power is in them, wherein they are agents unto themselves. And inasmuch as men do good they shall in nowise lose their reward.\n  29 But he that doeth not anything until he is commanded, and receiveth a commandment with doubtful heart, and keepeth it with slothfulness, the same is damned.\n", "question": "D&C 58: 26-29"}, {"answer": "16 All scripture is given by inspiration of God, and is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness:\r\n17 That the man of God may be perfect, throughly furnished unto all good works.", "question": "2 Timothy 3: 16-17"}, {"answer": "  123 See that ye love one another; cease to be covetous; learn to impart one to another as the gospel requires.\n  124 Cease to be idle; cease to be unclean; cease to find fault one with another; cease to sleep longer than is needful; retire to thy bed early, that ye may not be weary; arise early, that your bodies and your minds may be invigorated.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 123-124"}, {"answer": "  10 Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God;\n  11 For, behold, the Lord your Redeemer suffered death in the flesh; wherefore he suffered the pain of all men, that all men might repent and come unto him.\n  12 And he hath risen again from the dead, that he might bring all men unto him, on conditions of repentance.\n  13 And how great is his joy in the soul that repenteth!\n  14 Wherefore, you are called to cry repentance unto this people.\n  15 And if it so be that you should labor all your days in crying repentance unto this people, and bring, save it be one soul unto me, how great shall be your joy with him in the kingdom of my Father!\n  16 And now, if your joy will be great with one soul that you have brought unto me into the kingdom of my Father, how great will be your joy if you should bring many souls unto me!\n", "question": "D&C 18: 10-16"}, {"answer": "  1 In the celestial glory there are three heavens or degrees;\n  2 And in order to obtain the highest, a man must enter into this order of the priesthood [meaning the new and everlasting covenant of marriage];\n  3 And if he does not, he cannot obtain it.\n  4 He may enter into the other, but that is the end of his kingdom; he cannot have an increase.\n", "question": "D&C 131: 1-4"}, {"answer": "6 And I saw another angel fly in the midst of heaven, having the everlasting gospel to preach unto them that dwell on the earth, and to every nation, and kindred, and tongue, and people,\r\n7 Saying with a loud voice, Fear God, and give glory to him; for the hour of his judgment is come: and worship him that made heaven, and earth, and the sea, and the fountains of waters.\r\n", "question": "Revelation 14: 6-7"}, {"answer": "13 Wherefore the Lord said, Forasmuch as this people draw near me with their mouth, and with their lips do honour me, but have removed their heart far from me, and their fear toward me is taught by the precept of men:\r\n14 Therefore, behold, I will proceed to do a marvellous work among this people, even a marvellous work and a wonder: for the wisdom of their wise men shall perish, and the understanding of their prudent men shall be hid.", "question": "Isaiah 29: 13-14"}, {"answer": "  18 And all saints who remember to keep and do these sayings, walking in obedience to the commandments, shall receive health in their navel and marrow to their bones;\n  19 And shall find wisdom and great treasures of knowledge, even hidden treasures;\n  20 And shall run and not be weary, and shall walk and not faint.\n  21 And I, the Lord, give unto them a promise, that the destroying angel shall pass by them, as the children of Israel, and not slay them. Amen.\n", "question": "D&C 89: 18-21"}, {"answer": "20 But now is Christ risen from the dead, and become the firstfruits of them that slept.\r\n21 For since by man came death, by man came also the resurrection of the dead.\r\n22 For as in Adam all die, even so in Christ shall all be made alive.", "question": "1 Corinthians 15: 20-22"}, {"answer": "8 Will a man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me. But ye say, Wherein have we robbed thee? In tithes and offerings.\r\n9 Ye are cursed with a curse: for ye have robbed me, even this whole nation.\r\n10 Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.", "question": "Malachi 3: 8-10"}, {"answer": "12 And I saw the dead, small and great, stand before God; and the books were opened: and another book was opened, which is the book of life: and the dead were judged out of those things which were written in the books, according to their works.\r\n13 And the sea gave up the dead which were in it; and death and hell delivered up the dead which were in them: and they were judged every man according to their works.", "question": "Revelation 20: 12-13"}, {"answer": "  8 My disciples, in days of old, sought occasion against one another and forgave not one another in their hearts; and for this evil they were afflicted and sorely chastened.\n  9 Wherefore, I say unto you, that ye ought to forgive one another; for he that forgiveth not his brother his trespasses standeth condemned before the Lord; for there remaineth in him the greater sin.\n  10 I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men.\n  11 And ye ought to say in your hearts \u2014 let God judge between me and thee, and reward thee according to thy deeds.\n", "question": "D&C 64: 8-11"}, {"answer": "  22 And now, after the many testimonies which have been given of him, this is the testimony, last of all, which we give of him: That he lives!\n  23 For we saw him, even on the right hand of God; and we heard the voice bearing record that he is the Only Begotten of the Father\u2014\n  24 That by him, and through him, and of him, the worlds are and were created, and the inhabitants thereof are begotten sons and daughters unto God.\n", "question": "D&C 76: 22-24"}, {"answer": "15 The word of the Lord came again unto me, saying,\r\n16 Moreover, thou son of man, take thee one stick, and write upon it, For Judah, and for the children of Israel his companions: then take another stick, and write upon it, For Joseph, the stick of Ephraim, and for all the house of Israel his companions:\r\n17 And join them one to another into one stick; and they shall become one in thine hand.", "question": "Ezekiel 37: 15-17"}, {"answer": "  55 But he, being full of the Holy Ghost, looked up stedfastly into heaven, and saw the glory of God, and Jesus standing on the right hand of God,\n  56 And said, Behold, I see the heavens opened, and the Son of man standing on the right hand of God.\n", "question": "Acts 7: 55-56"}, {"answer": "11 And he gave some, apostles; and some, prophets; and some, evangelists; and some, pastors and teachers;\r\n12 For the perfecting of the saints, for the work of the ministry, for the edifying of the body of Christ:\r\n13 Till we all come in the unity of the faith, and of the knowledge of the Son of God, unto a perfect man, unto the measure of the stature of the fulness of Christ:\r\n14 That we henceforth be no more children, tossed to and fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine, by the sleight of men, and cunning craftiness, whereby they lie in wait to deceive;", "question": "Ephesians 4: 11-14"}, {"answer": "  7 Thus came the voice of the Lord unto me, saying: All who have died without a knowledge of this gospel, who would have received it if they had been permitted to tarry, shall be heirs of the celestial kingdom of God;\n  8 Also all that shall die henceforth without a knowledge of it, who would have received it with all their hearts, shall be heirs of that kingdom;\n  9 For I, the Lord, will judge all men according to their works, according to the desire of their hearts.\n  10 And I also beheld that all children who die before they arrive at the years of accountability are saved in the celestial kingdom of heaven.\n", "question": "D&C 137: 7-10"}, {"answer": "  16 For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.\n  17 For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved.\n", "question": "John 3: 16-17"}, {"answer": "1 This know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come.\r\n2 For men shall be lovers of their own selves, covetous, boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unthankful, unholy,\r\n3 Without natural affection, trucebreakers, false accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers of those that are good,\r\n4 Traitors, heady, highminded, lovers of pleasures more than lovers of God;\r\n5 Having a form of godliness, but denying the power thereof: from such turn away.\r\n", "question": "2 Timothy 3: 1-5"}, {"answer": "22 Now the Lord had shown unto me, Abraham, the intelligences that were organized before the world was; and among all these there were many of the noble and great ones;\r\n23 And God saw these souls that they were good, and he stood in the midst of them, and he said: These I will make my rulers; for he stood among those that were spirits, and he saw that they were good; and he said unto me: Abraham, thou art one of them; thou wast chosen before thou wast born.", "question": "Abraham 3: 22-23"}, {"answer": "33  And Christ hath said: If ye will have faith in me ye shall have power to do whatsoever thing is expedient in me.", "question": "Moroni 7: 33"}, {"answer": "3 Neither shalt thou make marriages with them; thy daughter thou shalt not give unto his son, nor his daughter shalt thou take unto thy son.\r\n4 For they will turn away thy son from following me, that they may serve other gods: so will the anger of the Lord be kindled against you, and destroy thee suddenly.", "question": "Deuteronomy 7: 3-4"}, {"answer": "40 There are also celestial bodies, and bodies terrestrial: but the glory of the celestial is one, and the glory of the terrestrial is another.\r\n41 There is one glory of the sun, and another glory of the moon, and another glory of the stars: for one star differeth from another star in glory.\r\n42 So also is the resurrection of the dead. It is sown in corruption; it is raised in incorruption:", "question": "1 Corinthians 15: 40-42"}, {"answer": "1 Now we beseech you, brethren, by the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and by our gathering together unto him,\r\n2 That ye be not soon shaken in mind, or be troubled, neither by spirit, nor by word, nor by letter as from us, as that the day of Christ is at hand.\r\n3 Let no man deceive you by any means: for that day shall not come, except there come a falling away first, and that man of sin be revealed, the son of perdition;", "question": "2 Thessalonians 2: 1-3"}, {"answer": "15 He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?\r\n16 And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.\r\n17 And Jesus answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.\r\n18 And I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.\r\n19 And I will give unto thee the keys of the kingdom of heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt bind on earth shall be bound in heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven.", "question": "Matthew 16: 15-19"}, {"answer": "26 And after that he came men also were saved by faith in his name; and by faith, they become the sons of God. And as surely as Christ liveth he spake these words unto our fathers, saying: Whatsoever thing ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is good, in faith believing that ye shall receive, behold, it shall be done unto you.", "question": "Moroni 7: 26"}, {"answer": "26 And we talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of Christ, and we write according to our prophecies, that our children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins.", "question": "2 Nephi 25: 26"}, {"answer": "  33 These things I have spoken unto you, that in me ye might have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.\n", "question": "John 16: 33"}, {"answer": "  26 But the Comforter, which is the Holy Ghost, whom the Father will send in my name, he shall teach you all things, and bring all things to your remembrance, whatsoever I have said unto you. \n", "question": "John 14: 26"}, {"answer": "  36 Look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear not.\n", "question": "D&C 6: 36"}, {"answer": "  2 But with some I am not well pleased, for they will not open their mouths, but they hide the talent which I have given unto them, because of the fear of man. Wo unto such, for mine anger is kindled against them.\n", "question": "D&C 60: 2"}, {"answer": "  24 Search diligently, pray always, and be believing, and all things shall work together for your good, if ye walk uprightly and remember the covenant wherewith ye have covenanted one with another.\n", "question": "D&C 90: 24"}, {"answer": "  11 And he shall go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind; and this that the word might be fulfilled which saith he will take upon him the pains and the sicknesses of his people.\n  12 And he will take upon him death, that he may loose the bands of death which bind his people; and he will take upon him their infirmities, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the flesh, that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities.\n", "question": "Alma 7: 11-12"}, {"answer": "  7 Behold, you have not understood; you have supposed that I would give it unto you, when you took no thought save it was to ask me.\n  8 But, behold, I say unto you, that you must study it out in your mind; then you must ask me if it be right, and if it is right I will cause that your bosom shall burn within you; therefore, you shall feel that it is right.\n  9 But if it be not right you shall have no such feelings, but you shall have a stupor of thought that shall cause you to forget the thing which is wrong; therefore, you cannot write that which is sacred save it be given you from me.\n", "question": "D&C 9: 7-9"}, {"answer": "  35 I have shewed you all things, how that so labouring ye ought to support the weak, and to remember the words of the Lord Jesus, how he said, It is more blessed to give than to receive.\n", "question": "Acts 20: 35"}, {"answer": "  45 Let thy bowels also be full of charity towards all men, and to the household of faith, and let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.\n  46 The Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion, and thy scepter an unchanging scepter of righteousness and truth; and thy dominion shall be an everlasting dominion, and without compulsory means it shall flow unto thee forever and ever.\n", "question": "D&C 121: 45-46"}, {"answer": "  81 Behold, I sent you out to testify and warn the people, and it becometh every man who hath been warned to warn his neighbor.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 81"}, {"answer": "37 Jesus said unto him, Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.\r\n38 This is the first and great commandment.\r\n39 And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.\r\n40 On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.", "question": "Matthew 22: 37-40"}, {"answer": "6 But this I say, He which soweth sparingly shall reap also sparingly; and he which soweth bountifully shall reap also bountifully.\r\n7 Every man according as he purposeth in his heart, so let him give; not grudgingly, or of necessity: for God loveth a cheerful giver.", "question": "2 Corinthians 9: 6-7"}, {"answer": "  27 Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.\n", "question": "John 14: 27"}, {"answer": "79 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee, in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify this wine to the souls of all those who drink of it, that they may do it in remembrance of the blood of thy Son, which was shed for them; that they may witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they do always remember him, that they may have his Spirit to be with them. Amen.", "question": "D&C 20: 79"}, {"answer": "  4 Wherefore, whoso believeth in God might with surety hope for a better world, yea, even a place at the right hand of God, which hope cometh of faith, maketh an anchor to the souls of men, which would make them sure and steadfast, always abounding in good works, being led to glorify God.\n", "question": "Ether 12: 4"}, {"answer": "6 Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it.", "question": "Proverbs 22: 6"}, {"answer": "  9 And I say unto you, Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.\n  10 For every one that asketh receiveth; and he that seeketh findeth; and to him that knocketh it shall be opened.\n  11 If a son shall ask bread of any of you that is a father, will he give him a stone? or if he ask a fish, will he for a fish give him a serpent?\n  12 Or if he shall ask an egg, will he offer him a scorpion?\n  13 If ye then, being evil, know how to give good gifts unto your children: how much more shall your heavenly Father give [good gifts, through] the Holy Spirit to them that ask him?\n", "question": "Luke 11: 9-13"}, {"answer": "  19 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, let every man be swift to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath:\n  20 For the wrath of man worketh not the righteousness of God.\n", "question": "James 1: 19-20"}, {"answer": "22 But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith,\r\n23 Meekness, temperance: against such there is no law.", "question": "Galatians 5: 22-23"}, {"answer": "  12 Yea, I know that I am nothing; as to my strength I am weak; therefore I will not boast of myself, but I will boast of my God, for in his strength I can do all things; yea, behold, many mighty miracles we have wrought in this land, for which we will praise his name forever.\n", "question": "Alma 26: 12"}, {"answer": "26 And now, for the sake of these things which I have spoken unto you\u2014that is, for the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, that ye may walk guiltless before God\u2014I would that ye should impart of your substance to the poor, every man according to that which he hath, such as feeding the hungry, clothing the naked, visiting the sick and administering to their relief, both spiritually and temporally, according to their wants.\r\n27 And see that all these things are done in wisdom and order; for it is not requisite that a man should run faster than he has strength. And again, it is expedient that he should be diligent, that thereby he might win the prize; therefore, all things must be done in order.", "question": "Mosiah 4: 26-27"}, {"answer": "12 And now, verily, verily, I say unto thee, put your trust in that Spirit which leadeth to do good\u2014yea, to do justly, to walk humbly, to judge righteously; and this is my Spirit.\r\n13 Verily, verily, I say unto you, I will impart unto you of my Spirit, which shall enlighten your mind, which shall fill your soul with joy;\r\n14 And then shall ye know, or by this shall you know, all things whatsoever you desire of me, which are pertaining unto things of righteousness, in faith believing in me that you shall receive.\r\n", "question": "D&C 11: 12-14"}, {"answer": "  22 Verily, verily, I say unto you, if you desire a further witness, cast your mind upon the night that you cried unto me in your heart, that you might know concerning the truth of these things.\n  23 Did I not speak peace to your mind concerning the matter? What greater witness can you have than from God?\n", "question": "D&C 6: 22-23"}, {"answer": "  34 A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you, that ye also love one another.\n  35 By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another.\n", "question": "John 13: 34-35"}, {"answer": "7 So thou, O son of man, I have set thee a watchman unto the house of Israel; therefore thou shalt hear the word at my mouth, and warn them from me.\r\n8 When I say unto the wicked, O wicked man, thou shalt surely die; if thou dost not speak to warn the wicked from his way, that wicked man shall die in his iniquity; but his blood will I require at thine hand.\r\n9 Nevertheless, if thou warn the wicked of his way to turn from it; if he do not turn from his way, he shall die in his iniquity; but thou hast delivered thy soul.", "question": "Ezekiel 33: 7-9"}, {"answer": "  13 Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.\n", "question": "John 15: 13"}, {"answer": "16 The Spirit itself beareth witness with our spirit, that we are the children of God:\r\n17 And if children, then heirs; heirs of God, and joint-heirs with Christ; if so be that we suffer with him, that we may be also glorified together.", "question": "Romans 8: 16-17"}, {"answer": "11 And I said unto him: To know the interpretation thereof \u2014 for I spake unto him as a man speaketh; for I beheld that he was in the form of a man; yet nevertheless, I knew that it was the Spirit of the Lord; and he spake unto me as a man speaketh with another.", "question": "1 Nephi 11: 11"}, {"answer": "  8 And it came to pass that he said unto them: Behold, here are the waters of Mormon (for thus were they called) and now, as ye are desirous to come into the fold of God, and to be called his people, and are willing to bear one another\u2019s burdens, that they may be light;\n  9 Yea, and are willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort, and to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places that ye may be in, even until death, that ye may be redeemed of God, and be numbered with those of the first resurrection, that ye may have eternal life\u2014\n  10 Now I say unto you, if this be the desire of your hearts, what have you against being baptized in the name of the Lord, as a witness before him that ye have entered into a covenant with him, that ye will serve him and keep his commandments, that he may pour out his Spirit more abundantly upon you?\n", "question": "Mosiah 18: 8-10"}, {"answer": "2 And it came to pass that I said unto them that I knew that I had spoken hard things against the wicked, according to the truth; and the righteous have I justified, and testified that they should be lifted up at the last day; wherefore, the guilty taketh the truth to be hard, for it cutteth them to the very center.", "question": "1 Nephi 16: 2"}, {"answer": "77 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify this bread to the souls of all those who partake of it, that they may eat in remembrance of the body of thy Son, and witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they are willing to take upon them the name of thy Son, and always remember him and keep his commandments which he has given them; that they may always have his Spirit to be with them. Amen.", "question": "D&C 20: 77"}, {"answer": "  5 For behold, the time cometh, and is not far distant, that with power, the Lord Omnipotent who reigneth, who was, and is from all eternity to all eternity, shall come down from heaven among the children of men, and shall dwell in a tabernacle of clay, and shall go forth amongst men, working mighty miracles, such as healing the sick, raising the dead, causing the lame to walk, the blind to receive their sight, and the deaf to hear, and curing all manner of diseases.\n  6 And he shall cast out devils, or the evil spirits which dwell in the hearts of the children of men.\n  7 And lo, he shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, hunger, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer, except it be unto death; for behold, blood cometh from every pore, so great shall be his anguish for the wickedness and the abominations of his people.\n  8 And he shall be called Jesus Christ, the Son of God, the Father of heaven and earth, the Creator of all things from the beginning; and his mother shall be called Mary.\n  9 And lo, he cometh unto his own, that salvation might come unto the children of men even through faith on his name; and even after all this they shall consider him a man, and say that he hath a devil, and shall scourge him, and shall crucify him.\n  10 And he shall rise the third day from the dead; and behold, he standeth to judge the world; and behold, all these things are done that a righteous judgment might come upon the children of men.\n", "question": "Mosiah 3: 5-10"}, {"answer": "17 So then faith cometh by hearing, and hearing by the word of God.", "question": "Romans 10: 17"}, {"answer": "9 And the world, because of their iniquity, shall judge him to be a thing of naught; wherefore they scourge him, and he suffereth it; and they smite him, and he suffereth it. Yea, they spit upon him, and he suffereth it, because of his loving kindness and his long-suffering towards the children of men.", "question": "1 Nephi 19: 9"}, {"answer": "16 Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the Spirit of God dwelleth in you?\r\n17 If any man defile the temple of God, him shall God destroy; for the temple of God is holy, which temple ye are.", "question": "1 Corinthians 3: 16-17"}, {"answer": "  31 And when Enoch had heard these words, he bowed himself to the earth, before the Lord, and spake before the Lord, saying: Why is it that I have found favor in thy sight, and am but a lad, and all the people hate me; for I am slow of speech; wherefore am I thy servant?\n  32 And the Lord said unto Enoch: Go forth and do as I have commanded thee, and no man shall pierce thee. Open thy mouth, and it shall be filled, and I will give thee utterance, for all flesh is in my hands, and I will do as seemeth me good.\n", "question": "Moses 6: 31-32"}, {"answer": "  15 And again, verily I say unto you, that whoso forbiddeth to marry is not ordained of God, for marriage is ordained of God unto man.\n  16 Wherefore, it is lawful that he should have one wife, and they twain shall be one flesh, and all this that the earth might answer the end of its creation;\n", "question": "D&C 49: 15-16"}, {"answer": "23 For all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God;", "question": "Romans 3: 23"}, {"answer": "  14 And ye will not suffer your children that they go hungry, or naked; neither will ye suffer that they transgress the laws of God, and fight and quarrel one with another, and serve the devil, who is the master of sin, or who is the evil spirit which hath been spoken of by our fathers, he being an enemy to all righteousness.\n  15 But ye will teach them to walk in the ways of truth and soberness; ye will teach them to love one another, and to serve one another.\n", "question": "Mosiah 4: 14-15"}, {"answer": "24 Therefore shall a man leave his father and his mother, and shall cleave unto his wife: and they shall be one flesh.", "question": "Genesis 2: 24"}, {"answer": "  22 Thou shalt love thy wife with all thy heart, and shalt cleave unto her and none else.\n  23 And he that looketh upon a woman to lust after her shall deny the faith, and shall not have the Spirit; and if he repents not he shall be cast out.\n", "question": "D&C 42: 22-23"}, {"answer": "4 And, ye fathers, provoke not your children to wrath: but bring them up in the nurture and admonition of the Lord.", "question": "Ephesians 6: 4"}, {"answer": "22 Wives, submit yourselves unto your own husbands, as unto the Lord.\r\n23 For the husband is the head of the wife, even as Christ is the head of the church: and he is the saviour of the body.\r\n24 Therefore as the church is subject unto Christ, so let the wives be to their own husbands in every thing.\r\n25 Husbands, love your wives, even as Christ also loved the church, and gave himself for it;", "question": "Ephesians 5: 22-25"}, {"answer": "8 But if any provide not for his own, and specially for those of his own house, he hath denied the faith, and is worse than an infidel.", "question": "1 Timothy 5: 8"}, {"answer": "  99 Wherefore, now let every man learn his duty, and to act in the office in which he is appointed, in all diligence.\n  100 He that is slothful shall not be counted worthy to stand, and he that learns not his duty and shows himself not approved shall not be counted worthy to stand. Even so. Amen.\n", "question": "D&C 107: 99-100"}, {"answer": "21 Pray in your families unto the Father, always in my name, that your wives and your children may be blessed.", "question": "3 Nephi 18: 21"}, {"answer": "  3 Listen to him who is the advocate with the Father, who is pleading your cause before him\u2014\n  4 Saying: Father, behold the sufferings and death of him who did no sin, in whom thou wast well pleased; behold the blood of thy Son which was shed, the blood of him whom thou gavest that thyself might be glorified;\n  5 Wherefore, Father, spare these my brethren that believe on my name, that they may come unto me and have everlasting life.\n", "question": "D&C 45: 3-5"}, {"answer": "  2 And that same sociality which exists among us here will exist among us there, only it will be coupled with eternal glory, which glory we do not now enjoy.\n", "question": "D&C 130: 2"}, {"answer": "  28 For I, the Lord God, delight in the chastity of women. And whoredoms are an abomination before me; thus saith the Lord of Hosts.\n", "question": "Jacob 2: 28"}, {"answer": "9 But as it is written, Eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the things which God hath prepared for them that love him.", "question": "1 Corinthians 2: 9"}, {"answer": "  21 Seek not to declare my word, but first seek to obtain my word, and then shall your tongue be loosed; then, if you desire, you shall have my Spirit and my word, yea, the power of God unto the convincing of men.\n", "question": "D&C 11: 21"}, {"answer": "6 Wherefore, redemption cometh in and through the Holy Messiah; for he is full of grace and truth.\r\n7 Behold, he offereth himself a sacrifice for sin, to answer the ends of the law, unto all those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit; and unto none else can the ends of the law be answered.\r\n8 Wherefore, how great the importance to make these things known unto the inhabitants of the earth, that they may know that there is no flesh that can dwell in the presence of God, save it be through the merits, and mercy, and grace of the Holy Messiah, who layeth down his life according to the flesh, and taketh it again by the power of the Spirit, that he may bring to pass the resurrection of the dead, being the first that should rise.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 6-8"}, {"answer": "7 But if we walk in the light, as he is in the light, we have fellowship one with another, and the blood of Jesus Christ his Son cleanseth us from all sin.", "question": "1 John 1: 7"}, {"answer": "7 For God hath not given us the spirit of fear; but of power, and of love, and of a sound mind.", "question": "2 Timothy 1: 7"}, {"answer": "34 Wo unto the liar, for he shall be thrust down to hell.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 34"}, {"answer": "39 O, my beloved brethren, remember the awfulness in transgressing against that Holy God, and also the awfulness of yielding to the enticings of that cunning one. Remember, to be carnally-minded is death, and to be spiritually-minded is life eternal.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 39"}, {"answer": "  14 And the Spirit shall be given unto you by the prayer of faith; and if ye receive not the Spirit ye shall not teach.\n", "question": "D&C 42: 14"}, {"answer": "  40 And he shall come into the world to redeem his people; and he shall take upon him the transgressions of those who believe on his name; and these are they that shall have eternal life, and salvation cometh to none else.\n", "question": "Alma 11: 40"}, {"answer": "  15 So when they had dined, Jesus saith to Simon Peter, Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these? He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He saith unto him, Feed my lambs.\n  16 He saith to him again the second time, Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me? He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He saith unto him, Feed my sheep.\n  17 He saith unto him the third time, Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me? Peter was grieved because he said unto him the third time, Lovest thou me? And he said unto him, Lord, thou knowest all things; thou knowest that I love thee. Jesus saith unto him, Feed my sheep.\n", "question": "John 21: 15-17"}, {"answer": "14 But the natural man receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God: for they are foolishness unto him: neither can he know them, because they are spiritually discerned.", "question": "1 Corinthians 2: 14"}, {"answer": "11 For it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. If not so, my first-born in the wilderness, righteousness could not be brought to pass, neither wickedness, neither holiness nor misery, neither good nor bad. Wherefore, all things must needs be a compound in one; wherefore, if it should be one body it must needs remain as dead, having no life neither death, nor corruption nor incorruption, happiness nor misery, neither sense nor insensibility.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 11"}, {"answer": "  21 Yea, and they did obey and observe to perform every word of command with exactness; yea, and even according to their faith it was done unto them; and I did remember the words which they said unto me that their mothers had taught them.\n", "question": "Alma 57: 21"}, {"answer": "  12 O be wise; what can I say more?\n", "question": "Jacob 6: 12"}, {"answer": "42 And whoso knocketh, to him will he open; and the wise, and the learned, and they that are rich, who are puffed up because of their learning, and their wisdom, and their riches\u2014yea, they are they whom he despiseth; and save they shall cast these things away, and consider themselves fools before God, and come down in the depths of humility, he will not open unto them.\r\n43 But the things of the wise and the prudent shall be hid from them forever\u2014yea, that happiness which is prepared for the saints.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 42-43"}, {"answer": "  47 Now they never had fought, yet they did not fear death; and they did think more upon the liberty of their fathers than they did upon their lives; yea, they had been taught by their mothers, that if they did not doubt, God would deliver them.\n  48 And they rehearsed unto me the words of their mothers, saying: We do not doubt our mothers knew it.\n", "question": "Alma 56: 47-48"}, {"answer": "3 Then will ye longer deny the Christ, or can ye behold the Lamb of God? Do ye suppose that ye shall dwell with him under a consciousness of your guilt? Do ye suppose that ye could be happy to dwell with that holy Being, when your souls are racked with a consciousness of guilt that ye have ever abused his laws?\r\n4 Behold, I say unto you that ye would be more miserable to dwell with a holy and just God, under a consciousness of your filthiness before him, than ye would to dwell with the damned souls in hell.\r\n5 For behold, when ye shall be brought to see your nakedness before God, and also the glory of God, and the holiness of Jesus Christ, it will kindle a flame of unquenchable fire upon you.", "question": "Mormon 9: 3-5"}, {"answer": "33 But seek ye first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things shall be added unto you.", "question": "3 Nephi 13: 33"}, {"answer": "19 For he that diligently seeketh shall find; and the mysteries of God shall be unfolded unto them, by the power of the Holy Ghost, as well in these times as in times of old, and as well in times of old as in times to come; wherefore, the course of the Lord is one eternal round.", "question": "1 Nephi 10: 19"}, {"answer": "  12 Then spake Jesus again unto them, saying, I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.\n", "question": "John 8: 12"}, {"answer": "  2 Now these sons of Mosiah were with Alma at the time the angel first appeared unto him; therefore Alma did rejoice exceedingly to see his brethren; and what added more to his joy, they were still his brethren in the Lord; yea, and they had waxed strong in the knowledge of the truth; for they were men of a sound understanding and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.\n  3 But this is not all; they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation, and when they taught, they taught with power and authority of God.\n", "question": "Alma 17: 2-3"}, {"answer": "9 Behold, I am the law, and the light. Look unto me, and endure to the end, and ye shall live; for unto him that endureth to the end will I give eternal life.", "question": "3 Nephi 15: 9"}, {"answer": "  5 And now my son, Shiblon, I would that ye should remember, that as much as ye shall put your trust in God even so much ye shall be delivered out of your trials, and your troubles, and your afflictions, and ye shall be lifted up at the last day.\n", "question": "Alma 38: 5"}, {"answer": "23 For we labor diligently to write, to persuade our children, and also our brethren, to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to God; for we know that it is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do.", "question": "2 Nephi 25: 23"}, {"answer": "  37 Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he will direct thee for good; yea, when thou liest down at night lie down unto the Lord, that he may watch over you in your sleep; and when thou risest in the morning let thy heart be full of thanks unto God; and if ye do these things, ye shall be lifted up at the last day.\n", "question": "Alma 37: 37"}, {"answer": "  19 And he who receiveth all things with thankfulness shall be made glorious; and the things of this earth shall be added unto him, even an hundred fold, yea, more.\n", "question": "D&C 78: 19"}, {"answer": "19 Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth, where moth and rust doth corrupt, and where thieves break through and steal:\r\n20 But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven, where neither moth nor rust doth corrupt, and where thieves do not break through nor steal:\r\n21 For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also.", "question": "Matthew 6: 19-21"}, {"answer": "  11 I am the good shepherd: the good shepherd giveth his life for the sheep.\n  12 But he that is an hireling, and not the shepherd, whose own the sheep are not, seeth the wolf coming, and leaveth the sheep, and fleeth: and the wolf catcheth them, and scattereth the sheep.\n  13 The hireling fleeth, because he is an hireling, and careth not for the sheep.\n  14 I am the good shepherd, and know my sheep, and am known of mine.\n  15 As the Father knoweth me, even so know I the Father: and I lay down my life for the sheep.\n", "question": "John 10: 11-15"}, {"answer": "1 Judge not, that ye be not judged.\r\n2 For with what judgment ye judge, ye shall be judged: and with what measure ye mete, it shall be measured to you again.", "question": "Matthew 7: 1-2"}, {"answer": "9 And let us not be weary in well doing: for in due season we shall reap, if we faint not.\r\n10 As we have therefore opportunity, let us do good unto all men, especially unto them who are of the household of faith.\r\n", "question": "Galatians 6: 9-10"}, {"answer": "41 No power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned;\r\n42 By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and without guile\u2014\r\n43 Reproving betimes with sharpness, when moved upon by the Holy Ghost; and then showing forth afterwards an increase of love toward him whom thou hast reproved, lest he esteem thee to be his enemy;\r\n44 That he may know that thy faithfulness is stronger than the cords of death.", "question": "D&C 121: 41-44"}, {"answer": "35 They also that erred in spirit shall come to understanding, and they that murmured shall learn doctrine.", "question": "2 Nephi 27: 35"}, {"answer": "  41 And moreover, I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness. O remember, remember that these things are true; for the Lord God hath spoken it.\n", "question": "Mosiah 2: 41"}, {"answer": "  118 And as all have not faith, seek ye diligently and teach one another words of wisdom; yea, seek ye out of the best books words of wisdom; seek learning, even by study and also by faith.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 118"}, {"answer": "  42 And go ye out from among the wicked. Save yourselves. Be ye clean that bear the vessels of the Lord. Even so. Amen.\n", "question": "D&C 38: 42"}, {"answer": "  25 And again, inasmuch as parents have children in Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized, that teach them not to understand the doctrine of repentance, faith in Christ the Son of the living God, and of baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost by the laying on of the hands, when eight years old, the sin be upon the heads of the parents.\n  26 For this shall be a law unto the inhabitants of Zion, or in any of her stakes which are organized.\n  27 And their children shall be baptized for the remission of their sins when eight years old, and receive the laying on of the hands.\n  28 And they shall also teach their children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord.\n", "question": "D&C 68: 25-28"}, {"answer": "29 Let no corrupt communication proceed out of your mouth, but that which is good to the use of edifying, that it may minister grace unto the hearers.", "question": "Ephesians 4: 29"}, {"answer": "18 There is no fear in love; but perfect love casteth out fear: because fear hath torment. He that feareth is not made perfect in love.", "question": "1 John 4: 18"}, {"answer": "  27 And they were among the people of Nephi, and also numbered among the people who were of the church of God. And they were also distinguished for their zeal towards God, and also towards men; for they were perfectly honest and upright in all things; and they were firm in the faith of Christ, even unto the end.\n", "question": "Alma 27: 27"}, {"answer": "  33 Wherefore, be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. And out of small things proceedeth that which is great.\n", "question": "D&C 64: 33"}, {"answer": "12 Let no man despise thy youth; but be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity.", "question": "1 Timothy 4: 12"}, {"answer": "  19 And we did magnify our office unto the Lord, taking upon us the responsibility, answering the sins of the people upon our own heads if we did not teach them the word of God with all diligence; wherefore, by laboring with our might their blood might not come upon our garments; otherwise their blood would come upon our garments, and we would not be found spotless at the last day.\n", "question": "Jacob 1: 19"}, {"answer": "43 Ye have heard that it hath been said, Thou shalt love thy neighbour, and hate thine enemy.\r\n44 But I say unto you, Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you;\r\n45 That ye may be the children of your Father which is in heaven: for he maketh his sun to rise on the evil and on the good, and sendeth rain on the just and on the unjust.\r\n46 For if ye love them which love you, what reward have ye? do not even the publicans the same?\r\n47 And if ye salute your brethren only, what do ye more than others? do not even the publicans so?\r\n48 Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.", "question": "Matthew 5: 43-48"}, {"answer": "  24 And truth is knowledge of things as they are, and as they were, and as they are to come;\n", "question": "D&C 93: 24"}, {"answer": "  11 And I give unto you a commandment, that ye shall forsake all evil and cleave unto all good, that ye shall live by every word which proceedeth forth out of the mouth of God.\n  12 For he will give unto the faithful line upon line, precept upon precept; and I will try you and prove you herewith.\n", "question": "D&C 98: 11-12"}, {"answer": "22 And Samuel said, Hath the Lord as great delight in burnt offerings and sacrifices, as in obeying the voice of the Lord? Behold, to obey is better than sacrifice, and to hearken than the fat of rams.", "question": "1 Samuel 15: 22"}, {"answer": "  14 But behold, the Jews were a stiffnecked people; and they despised the words of plainness, and killed the prophets, and sought for things that they could not understand. Wherefore, because of their blindness, which blindness came by looking beyond the mark, they must needs fall; for God hath taken away his plainness from them, and delivered unto them many things which they cannot understand, because they desired it. And because they desired it God hath done it, that they may stumble.\n", "question": "Jacob 4: 14"}, {"answer": "  24 That which is of God is light; and he that receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more light; and that light groweth brighter and brighter until the perfect day.\n", "question": "D&C 50: 24"}, {"answer": "  9 Wherefore, a commandment I give unto you, which is the word of God, that ye revile no more against them because of the darkness of their skins; neither shall ye revile against them because of their filthiness; but ye shall remember your own filthiness, and remember that their filthiness came because of their fathers.\n", "question": "Jacob 3: 9"}, {"answer": "6 For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is given: and the government shall be upon his shoulder: and his name shall be called Wonderful, Counsellor, The mighty God, The everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace.", "question": "Isaiah 9: 6"}, {"answer": "7 For the things which some men esteem to be of great worth, both to the body and soul, others set at naught and trample under their feet. Yea, even the very God of Israel do men trample under their feet; I say, trample under their feet but I would speak in other words\u2014they set him at naught, and hearken not to the voice of his counsels.\r\n", "question": "1 Nephi 19: 7"}, {"answer": "20 For behold, at that day shall he rage in the hearts of the children of men, and stir them up to anger against that which is good.\r\n21 And others will he pacify, and lull them away into carnal security, that they will say: All is well in Zion; yea, Zion prospereth, all is well\u2014and thus the devil cheateth their souls, and leadeth them away carefully down to hell.\r\n22 And behold, others he flattereth away, and telleth them there is no hell; and he saith unto them: I am no devil, for there is none\u2014and thus he whispereth in their ears, until he grasps them with his awful chains, from whence there is no deliverance.\r\n", "question": "2 Nephi 28: 20-22"}, {"answer": "  41 And it came to pass that the Lord of the vineyard wept, and said unto the servant: What could I have done more for my vineyard?\n", "question": "Jacob 5: 41"}, {"answer": "  72 And it came to pass that the servants did go and labor with their mights; and the Lord of the vineyard labored also with them; and they did obey the commandments of the Lord of the vineyard in all things.\n", "question": "Jacob 5: 72"}, {"answer": "7 For as he thinketh in his heart, so is he: Eat and drink, saith he to thee; but his heart is not with thee.", "question": "Proverbs 23: 7"}, {"answer": "  5 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, I beseech of you in words of soberness that ye would repent, and come with full purpose of heart, and cleave unto God as he cleaveth unto you. And while his arm of mercy is extended towards you in the light of the day, harden not your hearts.\n  6 Yea, today, if ye will hear his voice, harden not your hearts; for why will ye die?\n", "question": "Jacob 6: 5-6"}, {"answer": "14 Yea, verily I say unto you, if ye will come unto me ye shall have eternal life. Behold, mine arm of mercy is extended towards you, and whosoever will come, him will I receive; and blessed are those who come unto me.", "question": "3 Nephi 9: 14"}, {"answer": "28 Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.\r\n29 Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart: and ye shall find rest unto your souls.\r\n30 For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.\r\n", "question": "Matthew 11: 28-30"}, {"answer": "  46 And the Spirit giveth light to every man that cometh into the world; and the Spirit enlighteneth every man through the world, that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit.\n", "question": "D&C 84: 46"}, {"answer": "1 We believe in God, the Eternal Father, and in His Son, Jesus Christ, and in the Holy Ghost.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 1"}, {"answer": "2 We believe that men will be punished for their own sins, and not for Adam\u2019s transgression.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 2"}, {"answer": "5 For his anger endureth but a moment; in his favour is life: weeping may endure for a night, but joy cometh in the morning.", "question": "Psalms 30: 5"}, {"answer": "3 We believe that through the Atonement of Christ, all mankind may be saved, by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the Gospel.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 3"}, {"answer": "4 We believe that the first principles and ordinances of the Gospel are: first, Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ; second, Repentance; third, Baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; fourth, Laying on of hands for the gift of the Holy Ghost.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 4"}, {"answer": "  63 Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you; seek me diligently and ye shall find me; ask, and ye shall receive; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 63"}, {"answer": "5 We believe that a man must be called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands by those who are in authority, to preach the Gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 5"}, {"answer": "  5 Therefore, verily I say unto you, lift up your voices unto this people; speak the thoughts that I shall put into your hearts, and you shall not be confounded before men;\n  6 For it shall be given you in the very hour, yea, in the very moment, what ye shall say.\n  7 But a commandment I give unto you, that ye shall declare whatsoever thing ye declare in my name, in solemnity of heart, in the spirit of meekness, in all things.\n  8 And I give unto you this promise, that inasmuch as ye do this the Holy Ghost shall be shed forth in bearing record unto all things whatsoever ye shall say.\n", "question": "D&C 100: 5-8"}, {"answer": "31 What shall we then say to these things? If God be for us, who can be against us?", "question": "Romans 8: 31"}, {"answer": "6 We believe in the same organization that existed in the Primitive Church, namely, apostles, prophets, pastors, teachers, evangelists, and so forth.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 6"}, {"answer": "7 We believe in the gift of tongues, prophecy, revelation, visions, healing, interpretation of tongues, and so forth.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 7"}, {"answer": "10 For the love of money is the root of all evil: which while some coveted after, they have erred from the faith, and pierced themselves through with many sorrows.", "question": "1 Timothy 6: 10"}, {"answer": "  6 It is impossible for a man to be saved in ignorance.\n", "question": "D&C 131: 6"}, {"answer": "7 Ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth.", "question": "2 Timothy 3: 7"}, {"answer": "8 We believe the Bible to be the word of God as far as it is translated correctly; we also believe the Book of Mormon to be the word of God.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 8"}, {"answer": "  7 There is no such thing as immaterial matter. All spirit is matter, but it is more fine or pure, and can only be discerned by purer eyes;\n  8 We cannot see it; but when our bodies are purified we shall see that it is all matter.\n", "question": "D&C 131: 7-8"}, {"answer": "  17 Verily I say unto you, he that is ordained of me and sent forth to preach the word of truth by the Comforter, in the Spirit of truth, doth he preach it by the Spirit of truth or some other way?\n  18 And if it be by some other way it is not of God.\n  19 And again, he that receiveth the word of truth, doth he receive it by the Spirit of truth or some other way?\n  20 If it be some other way it is not of God.\n  21 Therefore, why is it that ye cannot understand and know, that he that receiveth the word by the Spirit of truth receiveth it as it is preached by the Spirit of truth?\n  22 Wherefore, he that preacheth and he that receiveth, understand one another, and both are edified and rejoice together.\n", "question": "D&C 50: 17-22"}, {"answer": "9 We believe all that God has revealed, all that He does now reveal, and we believe that He will yet reveal many great and important things pertaining to the Kingdom of God.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 9"}, {"answer": "23 But foolish and unlearned questions avoid, knowing that they do gender strifes.", "question": "2 Timothy 2: 23"}, {"answer": "10 We believe in the literal gathering of Israel and in the restoration of the Ten Tribes; that Zion (the New Jerusalem) will be built upon the American continent; that Christ will reign personally upon the earth; and, that the earth will be renewed and receive its paradisiacal glory.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 10"}, {"answer": "  9 Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.\n", "question": "Mosiah 4: 9"}, {"answer": "11 We claim the privilege of worshiping Almighty God according to the dictates of our own conscience, and allow all men the same privilege, let them worship how, where, or what they may.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 11"}, {"answer": "7 I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith:", "question": "2 Timothy 4: 7"}, {"answer": "12 We believe in being subject to kings, presidents, rulers, and magistrates, in obeying, honoring, and sustaining the law.", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 12"}, {"answer": "  13 For how knoweth a man the master whom he has not served, and who is a stranger unto him, and is far from the thoughts and intents of his heart?\n", "question": "Mosiah 5: 13"}, {"answer": "13 We believe in being honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, and in doing good to all men; indeed, we may say that we follow the admonition of Paul\u2014We believe all things, we hope all things, we have endured many things, and hope to be able to endure all things. If there is anything virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy, we seek after these things.\r\n", "question": "Articles of Faith 1: 13"}, {"answer": "8 For by grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: it is the gift of God:\r\n9 Not of works, lest any man should boast.", "question": "Ephesians 2: 8-9"}, {"answer": "  12 But wo, wo unto him who knoweth that he rebelleth against God! For salvation cometh to none such except it be through repentance and faith on the Lord Jesus Christ.\n", "question": "Mosiah 3: 12"}, {"answer": "20 Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.", "question": "2 Nephi 31: 20"}, {"answer": "13 I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me.", "question": "Philippians 4: 13"}, {"answer": "  7 And now, my sons, I would that ye should remember to search them diligently, that ye may profit thereby; and I would that ye should keep the commandments of God, that ye may prosper in the land according to the promises which the Lord made unto our fathers.\n", "question": "Mosiah 1: 7"}, {"answer": "  28 And moreover, I say unto you, that salvation doth not come by the law alone; and were it not for the atonement, which God himself shall make for the sins and iniquities of his people, that they must unavoidably perish, notwithstanding the law of Moses.\n", "question": "Mosiah 13: 28"}, {"answer": "  17 And moreover, I say unto you, that there shall be no other name given nor any other way nor means whereby salvation can come unto the children of men, only in and through the name of Christ, the Lord Omnipotent.\n", "question": "Mosiah 3: 17"}, {"answer": "9 That if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved.\r\n10 For with the heart man believeth unto righteousness; and with the mouth confession is made unto salvation.", "question": "Romans 10: 9-10"}, {"answer": "  44 But Alma said unto him: Thou hast had signs enough; will ye tempt your God? Will ye say, Show unto me a sign, when ye have the testimony of all these thy brethren, and also all the holy prophets? The scriptures are laid before thee, yea, and all things denote there is a God; yea, even the earth, and all things that are upon the face of it, yea, and its motion, yea, and also all the planets which move in their regular form do witness that there is a Supreme Creator.\n", "question": "Alma 30: 44"}, {"answer": "1 The earth is the Lord\u2018s, and the fulness thereof; the world, and they that dwell therein.", "question": "Psalms 24: 1"}, {"answer": "3 And hereby we do know that we know him, if we keep his commandments.\r\n4 He that saith, I know him, and keepeth not his commandments, is a liar, and the truth is not in him.\r\n5 But whoso keepeth his word, in him verily is the love of God perfected: hereby know we that we are in him.", "question": "1 John 2: 3-5"}, {"answer": "9 Furthermore we have had fathers of our flesh which corrected us, and we gave them reverence: shall we not much rather be in subjection unto the Father of spirits, and live?", "question": "Hebrews 12: 9"}, {"answer": "11 And they overcame him by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their testimony; and they loved not their lives unto the death.", "question": "Revelation 12: 11"}, {"answer": "  46 But behold, I say unto you, that little children are redeemed from the foundation of the world through mine Only Begotten;\n  47 Wherefore, they cannot sin, for power is not given unto Satan to tempt little children, until they begin to become accountable before me;\n", "question": "D&C 29: 46-47"}, {"answer": "  20 I perceive that it has been made known unto you, by the testimony of his word, that he cannot walk in crooked paths; neither doth he vary from that which he hath said; neither hath he a shadow of turning from the right to the left, or from that which is right to that which is wrong; therefore, his course is one eternal round.\n", "question": "Alma 7: 20"}, {"answer": "1 Now faith is the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.", "question": "Hebrews 11: 1"}, {"answer": "18 Forasmuch as ye know that ye were not redeemed with corruptible things, as silver and gold, from your vain conversation received by tradition from your fathers;\r\n19 But with the precious blood of Christ, as of a lamb without blemish and without spot:", "question": "1 Peter 1: 18-19"}, {"answer": "  7 Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.\n", "question": "James 4: 7"}, {"answer": "5 Before I formed thee in the belly I knew thee; and before thou camest forth out of the womb I sanctified thee, and I ordained thee a prophet unto the nations.", "question": "Jeremiah 1: 5"}, {"answer": "  6 Wherefore, we search the prophets, and we have many revelations and the spirit of prophecy; and having all these witnesses we obtain a hope, and our faith becometh unshaken, insomuch that we truly can command in the name of Jesus and the very trees obey us, or the mountains, or the waves of the sea.\n  7 Nevertheless, the Lord God showeth us our weakness that we may know that it is by his grace, and his great condescensions unto the children of men, that we have power to do these things.\n", "question": "Jacob 4: 6-7"}, {"answer": "13 Now the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, that ye may abound in hope, through the power of the Holy Ghost.", "question": "Romans 15: 13"}, {"answer": "20 I say unto you, my brethren, that if you should render all the thanks and praise which your whole soul has power to possess, to that God who has created you, and has kept and preserved you, and has caused that ye should rejoice, and has granted that ye should live in peace one with another\u2014\r\n21 I say unto you that if ye should serve him who has created you from the beginning, and is preserving you from day to day, by lending you breath, that ye may live and move and do according to your own will, and even supporting you from one moment to another\u2014I say, if ye should serve him with all your whole souls yet ye would be unprofitable servants.", "question": "Mosiah 2: 20-21"}, {"answer": "  14 Is any sick among you? let him call for the elders of the church; and let them pray over him, anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord:\n", "question": "James 5: 14"}, {"answer": "20  And Jesus said unto them, Because of your unbelief: for verily I say unto you, If ye have faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye shall say unto this mountain, Remove hence to yonder place; and it shall remove; and nothing shall be impossible unto you.", "question": "Matthew 17: 20"}, {"answer": "  33 Preach unto them repentance, and faith on the Lord Jesus Christ; teach them to humble themselves and to be meek and lowly in heart; teach them to withstand every temptation of the devil, with their faith on the Lord Jesus Christ.\n", "question": "Alma 37: 33"}, {"answer": "  17 Therefore doth my Father love me, because I lay down my life, that I might take it again.\n  18 No man taketh it from me, but I lay it down of myself. I have power to lay it down, and I have power to take it again. This commandment have I received of my Father.\n", "question": "John 10: 17-18"}, {"answer": "  41 That he came into the world, even Jesus, to be crucified for the world, and to bear the sins of the world, and to sanctify the world, and to cleanse it from all unrighteousness;\n  42 That through him all might be saved whom the Father had put into his power and made by him;\n", "question": "D&C 76: 41-42"}, {"answer": "  9 For it is expedient that an atonement should be made; for according to the great plan of the Eternal God there must be an atonement made, or else all mankind must unavoidably perish; yea, all are hardened; yea, all are fallen and are lost, and must perish except it be through the atonement which it is expedient should be made.\n", "question": "Alma 34: 9"}, {"answer": "7 (For we walk by faith, not by sight:)", "question": "2 Corinthians 5: 7"}, {"answer": "  32 But, O my people, beware lest there shall arise contentions among you, and ye list to obey the evil spirit, which was spoken of by my father Mosiah.\n  33 For behold, there is a wo pronounced upon him who listeth to obey that spirit; for if he listeth to obey him, and remaineth and dieth in his sins, the same drinketh damnation to his own soul; for he receiveth for his wages an everlasting punishment, having transgressed the law of God contrary to his own knowledge.\n", "question": "Mosiah 2: 32-33"}, {"answer": "21 Behold, I have come unto the world to bring redemption unto the world, to save the world from sin.\r\n22 Therefore, whoso repenteth and cometh unto me as a little child, him will I receive, for of such is the kingdom of God. Behold, for such I have laid down my life, and have taken it up again; therefore repent, and come unto me ye ends of the earth, and be saved.", "question": "3 Nephi 9: 21-22"}, {"answer": "  10 Be thou humble; and the Lord thy God shall lead thee by the hand, and give thee answer to thy prayers.\n", "question": "D&C 112: 10"}, {"answer": "5 For I remember the word of God which saith by their works ye shall know them; for if their works be good, then they are good also.\r\n6 For behold, God hath said a man being evil cannot do that which is good; for if he offereth a gift, or prayeth unto God, except he shall do it with real intent it profiteth him nothing.\r\n7 For behold, it is not counted unto him for righteousness.\r\n8 For behold, if a man being evil giveth a gift, he doeth it grudgingly; wherefore it is counted unto him the same as if he had retained the gift; wherefore he is counted evil before God.\r\n9 And likewise also is it counted evil unto a man, if he shall pray and not with real intent of heart; yea, and it profiteth him nothing, for God receiveth none such.\r\n10 Wherefore, a man being evil cannot do that which is good; neither will he give a good gift.", "question": "Moroni 7: 5-10"}, {"answer": "18 In every thing give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you.", "question": "1 Thessalonians 5: 18"}, {"answer": "8 He that loveth not knoweth not God; for God is love.", "question": "1 John 4: 8"}, {"answer": "  17 Therefore to him that knoweth to do good, and doeth it not, to him it is sin.\n", "question": "James 4: 17"}, {"answer": "9 In this was manifested the love of God toward us, because that God sent his only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through him.", "question": "1 John 4: 9"}, {"answer": "18 Behold, verily, verily, I say unto you, ye must watch and pray always lest ye enter into temptation; for Satan desireth to have you, that he may sift you as wheat.\r\n19 Therefore ye must always pray unto the Father in my name;", "question": "3 Nephi 18: 18-19"}, {"answer": "  3 And now because of their unbelief they could not understand the word of God; and their hearts were hardened.\n", "question": "Mosiah 26: 3"}, {"answer": "15 I know thy works, that thou art neither cold nor hot: I would thou wert cold or hot.\r\n16 So then because thou art lukewarm, and neither cold nor hot, I will spue thee out of my mouth.\r\n", "question": "Revelation 3: 15-16"}, {"answer": "20 If a man say, I love God, and hateth his brother, he is a liar: for he that loveth not his brother whom he hath seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen?", "question": "1 John 4: 20"}, {"answer": "  4 That they should let no pride nor haughtiness disturb their peace; that every man should esteem his neighbor as himself, laboring with their own hands for their support.\n", "question": "Mosiah 27: 4"}, {"answer": "  39 We have learned by sad experience that it is the nature and disposition of almost all men, as soon as they get a little authority, as they suppose, they will immediately begin to exercise unrighteous dominion.\n  40 Hence many are called, but few are chosen.\n", "question": "D&C 121: 39-40"}, {"answer": "13 Ye are the salt of the earth: but if the salt have lost his savour, wherewith shall it be salted? it is thenceforth good for nothing, but to be cast out, and to be trodden under foot of men.", "question": "Matthew 5: 13"}, {"answer": "12 Therefore all things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them: for this is the law and the prophets.", "question": "Matthew 7: 12"}, {"answer": "21 Not every one that saith unto me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of heaven; but he that doeth the will of my Father which is in heaven.", "question": "Matthew 7: 21"}, {"answer": "24 And there stood one among them that was like unto God, and he said unto those who were with him: We will go down, for there is space there, and we will take of these materials, and we will make an earth whereon these may dwell;\r\n25 And we will prove them herewith, to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them;\r\n26 And they who keep their first estate shall be added upon; and they who keep not their first estate shall not have glory in the same kingdom with those who keep their first estate; and they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever.\r\n", "question": "Abraham 3: 24-26"}, {"answer": "  12 Use boldness, but not overbearance; and also see that ye bridle all your passions, that ye may be filled with love; see that ye refrain from idleness.\n", "question": "Alma 38: 12"}, {"answer": "7 But when ye pray, use not vain repetitions, as the heathen do: for they think that they shall be heard for their much speaking.\r\n8 Be not ye therefore like unto them: for your Father knoweth what things ye have need of, before ye ask him.", "question": "Matthew 6: 7-8"}, {"answer": "3 Blessed are the poor in spirit [who come unto me]: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.", "question": "Matthew 5: 3"}, {"answer": "3 And why beholdest thou the mote that is in thy brother\u2019s eye, but considerest not the beam that is in thine own eye?\r\n4 Or how wilt thou say to thy brother, Let me pull out the mote out of thine eye; and, behold, a beam is in thine own eye?\r\n5 Thou hypocrite, first cast out the beam out of thine own eye; and then shalt thou see clearly to cast out the mote out of thy brother\u2019s eye.", "question": "Matthew 7: 3-5"}, {"answer": "4 Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted.", "question": "Matthew 5: 4"}, {"answer": "6 Give not that which is holy unto the dogs, neither cast ye your pearls before swine, lest they trample them under their feet, and turn again and rend you.", "question": "Matthew 7: 6"}, {"answer": "5 Blessed are the meek: for they shall inherit the earth.", "question": "Matthew 5: 5"}, {"answer": "9 Speak not in the ears of a fool: for he will despise the wisdom of thy words.", "question": "Proverbs 23: 9"}, {"answer": "22 The light of the body is the eye: if therefore thine eye be single [to the glory of God], thy whole body shall be full of light.\r\n23 But if thine eye be evil, thy whole body shall be full of darkness. If therefore the light that is in thee be darkness, how great is that darkness!", "question": "Matthew 6: 22-23"}, {"answer": "6 Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled [with the Holy Ghost].", "question": "Matthew 5: 6"}, {"answer": "7 Blessed are the merciful: for they shall obtain mercy.", "question": "Matthew 5: 7"}, {"answer": "13 Enter ye in at the strait gate: for wide is the gate, and broad is the way, that leadeth to destruction, and many there be which go in thereat:\r\n14 Because strait is the gate, and narrow is the way, which leadeth unto life, and few there be that find it.", "question": "Matthew 7: 13-14"}, {"answer": "8 Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God.", "question": "Matthew 5: 8"}, {"answer": "22 Cast thy burden upon the Lord, and he shall sustain thee: he shall never suffer the righteous to be moved.", "question": "Psalms 55: 22"}, {"answer": "9 Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called the children of God.", "question": "Matthew 5: 9"}, {"answer": "22 Many will say to me in that day, Lord, Lord, have we not prophesied in thy name? and in thy name have cast out devils? and in thy name done many wonderful works?\r\n23 And then will I profess unto them, I never knew you: depart from me, ye that work iniquity.", "question": "Matthew 7: 22-23"}, {"answer": "10 Blessed are they which are persecuted for righteousness\u2019 sake: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.", "question": "Matthew 5: 10"}, {"answer": "11 Blessed are ye, when men shall revile you, and persecute you, and shall say all manner of evil against you falsely, for my sake.\r\n12 Rejoice, and be exceeding glad: for great is your reward in heaven: for so persecuted they the prophets which were before you.", "question": "Matthew 5: 11-12"}, {"answer": "1 Take heed that ye do not your alms before men, to be seen of them: otherwise ye have no reward of your Father which is in heaven.\r\n2 Therefore when thou doest thine alms, do not sound a trumpet before thee, as the hypocrites do in the synagogues and in the streets, that they may have glory of men. Verily I say unto you, They have their reward.\r\n3 But when thou doest alms, let not thy left hand know what thy right hand doeth:\r\n4 That thine alms may be in secret: and thy Father which seeth in secret himself shall reward thee openly.", "question": "Matthew 6: 1-4"}, {"answer": "  88 And whoso receiveth you, there I will be also, for I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up.\n", "question": "D&C 84: 88"}, {"answer": "23 Therefore if thou bring thy gift to the altar, and there rememberest that thy brother hath ought against thee;\r\n24 Leave there thy gift before the altar, and go thy way; first be reconciled to thy brother, and then come and offer thy gift.", "question": "Matthew 5: 23-24"}, {"answer": "5 And when thou prayest, thou shalt not be as the hypocrites are: for they love to pray standing in the synagogues and in the corners of the streets, that they may be seen of men. Verily I say unto you, They have their reward.\r\n6 But thou, when thou prayest, enter into thy closet, and when thou hast shut thy door, pray to thy Father which is in secret; and thy Father which seeth in secret shall reward thee openly.", "question": "Matthew 6: 5-6"}, {"answer": "  31 For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance;\n  32 Nevertheless, he that repents and does the commandments of the Lord shall be forgiven;\n", "question": "D&C 1: 31-32"}, {"answer": "  14 For our words will condemn us, yea, all our works will condemn us; we shall not be found spotless; and our thoughts will also condemn us; and in this awful state we shall not dare to look up to our God; and we would fain be glad if we could command the rocks and the mountains to fall upon us to hide us from his presence.\n", "question": "Alma 12: 14"}, {"answer": "19 Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God;\r\n20 And are built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the chief corner stone;", "question": "Ephesians 2: 19-20"}, {"answer": "  1 Now behold, a marvelous work is about to come forth among the children of men.\n  2 Therefore, O ye that embark in the service of God, see that ye serve him with all your heart, might, mind and strength, that ye may stand blameless before God at the last day.\n  3 Therefore, if ye have desires to serve God ye are called to the work;\n  4 For behold the field is white already to harvest; and lo, he that thrusteth in his sickle with his might, the same layeth up in store that he perisheth not, but bringeth salvation to his soul;\n  5 And faith, hope, charity and love, with an eye single to the glory of God, qualify him for the work.\n  6 Remember faith, virtue, knowledge, temperance, patience, brotherly kindness, godliness, charity, humility, diligence.\n  7 Ask, and ye shall receive; knock, and it shall be opened unto you. Amen.\n", "question": "D&C 4: 1-7"}, {"answer": "16 Moreover when ye fast, be not, as the hypocrites, of a sad countenance: for they disfigure their faces, that they may appear unto men to fast. Verily I say unto you, They have their reward.\r\n17 But thou, when thou fastest, anoint thine head, and wash thy face;\r\n18 That thou appear not unto men to fast, but unto thy Father which is in secret: and thy Father, which seeth in secret, shall reward thee openly.", "question": "Matthew 6: 16-18"}, {"answer": "  10 And therefore, he that will harden his heart, the same receiveth the lesser portion of the word; and he that will not harden his heart, to him is given the greater portion of the word, until it is given unto him to know the mysteries of God until he know them in full.\n  11 And they that will harden their hearts, to them is given the lesser portion of the word until they know nothing concerning his mysteries; and then they are taken captive by the devil, and led by his will down to destruction. Now this is what is meant by the chains of hell.\n", "question": "Alma 12: 10-11"}, {"answer": "  7 Seek not for riches but for wisdom, and behold, the mysteries of God shall be unfolded unto you, and then shall you be made rich. Behold, he that hath eternal life is rich.\n", "question": "D&C 6: 7"}, {"answer": "21 Ye have heard that it was said by them of old time, Thou shalt not kill; and whosoever shall kill shall be in danger of the judgment:\r\n22 But I say unto you, That whosoever is angry with his brother shall be in danger of his judgment: and whosoever shall say to his brother, Raca, shall be in danger of the council: and whosoever shall say, Thou fool, shall be in danger of hell fire.", "question": "Matthew 5: 21-22"}, {"answer": "  65 And these signs shall follow them that believe\u2014\n  66 In my name they shall do many wonderful works;\n  67 In my name they shall cast out devils;\n  68 In my name they shall heal the sick;\n  69 In my name they shall open the eyes of the blind, and unstop the ears of the deaf;\n  70 And the tongue of the dumb shall speak;\n  71 And if any man shall administer poison unto them it shall not hurt them;\n  72 And the poison of a serpent shall not have power to harm them.\n  73 But a commandment I give unto them, that they shall not boast themselves of these things, neither speak them before the world; for these things are given unto you for your profit and for salvation.\n", "question": "D&C 84: 65-73"}, {"answer": "27 Ye have heard that it was said by them of old time, Thou shalt not commit adultery:\r\n28 But I say unto you, That whosoever looketh on a woman to lust after her hath committed adultery with her already in his heart.", "question": "Matthew 5: 27-28"}, {"answer": "  86 Abide ye in the liberty wherewith ye are made free; entangle not yourselves in sin, but let your hands be clean, until the Lord comes.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 86"}, {"answer": "28 And we know that all things work together for good to them that love God, to them who are the called according to his purpose.", "question": "Romans 8: 28"}, {"answer": "  28 Verily, verily, I say unto you, wo be unto him that lieth to deceive because he supposeth that another lieth to deceive, for such are not exempt from the justice of God.\n", "question": "D&C 10: 28"}, {"answer": "3 And thinkest thou this, O man, that judgest them which do such things, and doest the same, that thou shalt escape the judgment of God?", "question": "Romans 2: 3"}, {"answer": "  32 Fear not, little flock; for it is your Father\u2019s good pleasure to give you the kingdom.\n", "question": "Luke 12: 32"}, {"answer": "  15 Therefore, let your hearts be comforted; for all things shall work together for good to them that walk uprightly, and to the sanctification of the church.\n", "question": "D&C 100: 15"}, {"answer": "25 And, again, I say unto you, go ye into the world, and care not for the world; for the world will hate you, and will persecute you, and will turn you out of their synagogues.\r\n26 Nevertheless, ye shall go forth from house to house, teaching the people; and I will go before you.\r\n27 And your heavenly Father will provide for you, whatsoever things ye need for food, what ye shall eat; and for raiment, what ye shall wear or put on.", "question": "JST Matthew 6: 25-27"}, {"answer": "12 And because iniquity shall abound, the love of many shall wax cold.", "question": "Matthew 24: 12"}, {"answer": "5 The earth also is defiled under the inhabitants thereof; because they have transgressed the laws, changed the ordinance, broken the everlasting covenant.", "question": "Isaiah 24: 5"}, {"answer": "  11 Behold, the days come, saith the Lord God, that I will send a famine in the land, not a famine of bread, nor a thirst for water, but of hearing the words of the Lord:\n  12 And they shall wander from sea to sea, and from the north even to the east, they shall run to and fro to seek the word of the Lord, and shall not find it.\n", "question": "Amos 8: 11-12"}, {"answer": "  22  Yea, he that repenteth and exerciseth faith, and bringeth forth good works, and prayeth continually without ceasing - unto such it is given to know the mysteries of God; yea, unto such it shall be given to reveal things which never have been revealed; yea, and it shall be given unto such to bring thousands of souls to repentance, even as it has been given unto us to bring these our brethren to repentance.\n", "question": "Alma 26: 22"}, {"answer": "  12 For there are many yet on the earth among all sects, parties, and denominations, who are blinded by the subtle craftiness of men, whereby they lie in wait to deceive, and who are only kept from the truth because they know not where to find it\u2014\n", "question": "D&C 123: 12"}, {"answer": "6 And I was led by the Spirit, not knowing beforehand the things which I should do.", "question": "1 Nephi 4: 6"}, {"answer": "3 For the time will come when they will not endure sound doctrine; but after their own lusts shall they heap to themselves teachers, having itching ears;\r\n4 And they shall turn away their ears from the truth, and shall be turned unto fables.", "question": "2 Timothy 4: 3-4"}, {"answer": "  16 You know, brethren, that a very large ship is benefited very much by a very small helm in the time of a storm, by being kept workways with the wind and the waves.\n  17 Therefore, dearly beloved brethren, let us cheerfully do all things that lie in our power; and then may we stand still, with the utmost assurance, to see the salvation of God, and for his arm to be revealed.\n", "question": "D&C 123: 16-17"}, {"answer": "6 And blessed is he, whosoever shall not be offended in me.", "question": "Matthew 11: 6"}, {"answer": "9 Then shall they deliver you up to be afflicted, and shall kill you: and ye shall be hated of all nations for my name\u2019s sake.\r\n10 And then shall many be offended, and shall betray one another, and shall hate one another.\r\n11 And many false prophets shall rise, and shall deceive many.", "question": "Matthew 24: 9-11"}, {"answer": "30 For behold, thus saith the Lord God: I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little; and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, and lend an ear unto my counsel, for they shall learn wisdom; for unto him that receiveth I will give more; and from them that shall say, We have enough, from them shall be taken away even that which they have.", "question": "2 Nephi 28: 30"}, {"answer": "20 Therefore remember, O man, for all thy doings thou shalt be brought into judgment.", "question": "1 Nephi 10: 20"}, {"answer": "20 Now this is the commandment: Repent, all ye ends of the earth, and come unto me and be baptized in my name, that ye may be sanctified by the reception of the Holy Ghost, that ye may stand spotless before me at the last day.", "question": "3 Nephi 27: 20"}, {"answer": "13 Let us hear the conclusion of the whole matter: Fear God, and keep his commandments: for this is the whole duty of man.", "question": "Ecclesiastes 12: 13"}, {"answer": "  13 Wherefore, I the Lord ask you this question \u2014 unto what were ye ordained?\n  14 To preach my gospel by the Spirit, even the Comforter which was sent forth to teach the truth.\n", "question": "D&C 50: 13-14"}, {"answer": "  16 And ye are to be taught from on high. Sanctify yourselves and ye shall be endowed with power, that ye may give even as I have spoken.\n", "question": "D&C 43: 16"}, {"answer": "21 Wherefore, if ye have sought to do wickedly in the days of your probation, then ye are found unclean before the judgment-seat of God; and no unclean thing can dwell with God; wherefore, ye must be cast off forever.", "question": "1 Nephi 10: 21"}, {"answer": "8 It is better to trust in the Lord than to put confidence in man.", "question": "Psalms 118: 8"}, {"answer": "  13 Therefore, that we should waste and wear out our lives in bringing to light all the hidden things of darkness, wherein we know them; and they are truly manifest from heaven\u2014\n  14 These should then be attended to with great earnestness.\n  15 Let no man count them as small things; for there is much which lieth in futurity, pertaining to the saints, which depends upon these things.\n", "question": "D&C 123: 13-15"}, {"answer": "10 Who can find a virtuous woman? for her price is far above rubies.", "question": "Proverbs 31: 10"}, {"answer": "22 Abstain from all appearance of evil.", "question": "1 Thessalonians 5: 22"}, {"answer": "5 And now, as the preaching of the word had a great tendency to lead the people to do that which was just\u2014yea, it had had more powerful effect upon the minds of the people than the sword, or anything else, which had happened unto them\u2014therefore Alma thought it was expedient that they should try the virtue of the word of God.", "question": "Alma 31: 5"}, {"answer": "  37 For with God nothing shall be impossible.\n", "question": "Luke 1: 37"}, {"answer": "  10 And verily I say unto thee that thou shalt lay aside the things of this world, and seek for the things of a better.\n", "question": "D&C 25: 10"}, {"answer": "  16 For behold, he said: Thou art angry, O Lord, with this people, because they will not understand thy mercies which thou hast bestowed upon them because of thy Son.\n", "question": "Alma 33: 16"}, {"answer": "30 Favour is deceitful, and beauty is vain: but a woman that feareth the Lord, she shall be praised.", "question": "Proverbs 31: 30"}, {"answer": "20 For where two or three are gathered together in my name, there am I in the midst of them.", "question": "Matthew 18: 20"}, {"answer": "8 Jesus Christ the same yesterday, and to day, and for ever.", "question": "Hebrews 13: 8"}, {"answer": "51 Wherefore, do not spend money for that which is of no worth, nor your labor for that which cannot satisfy. Hearken diligently unto me, and remember the words which I have spoken; and come unto the Holy One of Israel, and feast upon that which perisheth not, neither can be corrupted, and let your soul delight in fatness.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 51"}, {"answer": "  6 Jesus saith unto him, I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.\n", "question": "John 14: 6"}, {"answer": "1 Children, obey your parents in the Lord: for this is right.", "question": "Ephesians 6: 1"}, {"answer": "  5 Know ye not, my son, that these things are an abomination in the sight of the Lord; yea, most abominable above all sins save it be the shedding of innocent blood or denying the Holy Ghost?\n", "question": "Alma 39: 5"}, {"answer": "  2 But your mind has been on the things of the earth more than on the things of me, your Maker, and the ministry whereunto you have been called; and you have not given heed unto my Spirit, and to those who were set over you, but have been persuaded by those whom I have not commanded.\n", "question": "D&C 30: 2"}, {"answer": "8 Be sober, be vigilant; because your adversary the devil, as a roaring lion, walketh about, seeking whom he may devour:", "question": "1 Peter 5: 8"}, {"answer": "  17 For the earth is full, and there is enough and to spare; yea, I prepared all things, and have given unto the children of men to be agents unto themselves.\n", "question": "D&C 104: 17"}, {"answer": "  21 And in nothing doth man offend God, or against none is his wrath kindled, save those who confess not his hand in all things, and obey not his commandments.\n", "question": "D&C 59: 21"}, {"answer": "  21 And said, Naked came I out of my mother\u2019s womb, and naked shall I return thither: the Lord gave, and the Lord hath taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.\n", "question": "Job 1: 21"}, {"answer": "  24 For behold, justice exerciseth all his demands, and also mercy claimeth all which is her own; and thus, none but the truly penitent are saved.\n", "question": "Alma 42: 24"}, {"answer": "7 For we brought nothing into this world, and it is certain we can carry nothing out.", "question": "1 Timothy 6: 7"}, {"answer": "  25 What, do ye suppose that mercy can rob justice? I say unto you, Nay; not one whit. If so, God would cease to be God.\n", "question": "Alma 42: 25"}, {"answer": "  18 Therefore, if any man shall take of the abundance which I have made, and impart not his portion, according to the law of my gospel, unto the poor and the needy, he shall, with the wicked, lift up his eyes in hell, being in torment.\n", "question": "D&C 104: 18"}, {"answer": "5 One Lord, one faith, one baptism,", "question": "Ephesians 4: 5"}, {"answer": "33 For God is not the author of confusion, but of peace, as in all churches of the saints.", "question": "1 Corinthians 14: 33"}, {"answer": "21 He that despiseth his neighbour sinneth: but he that hath mercy on the poor, happy is he.", "question": "Proverbs 14: 21"}, {"answer": "17 But whoso hath this world\u2019s good, and seeth his brother have need, and shutteth up his bowels of compassion from him, how dwelleth the love of God in him?", "question": "1 John 3: 17"}, {"answer": "16 But if any man seem to be contentious, we have no such custom, neither the churches of God.", "question": "1 Corinthians 11: 16"}, {"answer": "  40 And remember in all things the poor and the needy, the sick and the afflicted, for he that doeth not these things, the same is not my disciple.\n", "question": "D&C 52: 40"}, {"answer": "  11 He answereth and saith unto them, He that hath two coats, let him impart to him that hath none; and he that hath meat, let him do likewise.\n", "question": "Luke 3: 11"}, {"answer": "18 My little children, let us not love in word, neither in tongue [only]; but in deed and in truth.", "question": "1 John 3: 18"}, {"answer": "19 And no unclean thing can enter into his kingdom; therefore nothing entereth into his rest save it be those who have washed their garments in my blood, because of their faith, and the repentance of all their sins, and their faithfulness unto the end.", "question": "3 Nephi 27: 19"}, {"answer": "17 Wherefore come out from among them, and be ye separate, saith the Lord, and touch not the unclean thing; and I will receive you.", "question": "2 Corinthians 6: 17"}, {"answer": "  5 For because of faith and great anxiety, it truly had been made manifest unto us concerning our people, what things should happen unto them.\n", "question": "Jacob 1: 5"}, {"answer": "31 The ear that heareth the reproof of life abideth among the wise.", "question": "Proverbs 15: 31"}, {"answer": "8 If we say that we have no sin, we deceive ourselves, and the truth is not in us.\r\n9 If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.", "question": "1 John 1: 8-9"}, {"answer": "11 Depart ye, depart ye, go ye out from thence, touch no unclean thing; go ye out of the midst of her; be ye clean, that bear the vessels of the Lord.", "question": "Isaiah 52: 11"}, {"answer": "27 But wo unto him that has the law given, yea, that has all the commandments of God, like unto us, and that transgresseth them, and that wasteth the days of his probation, for awful is his state!", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 27"}, {"answer": "7 O how great is the nothingness of the children of men; yea, even they are less than the dust of the earth.\r\n8 For behold, the dust of the earth moveth hither and thither, to the dividing asunder, at the command of our great and everlasting God.", "question": "Helaman 12: 7-8"}, {"answer": "  11 And now remember, my son, if it were not for the plan of redemption, (laying it aside) as soon as they were dead their souls were miserable, being cut off from the presence of the Lord.\n", "question": "Alma 42: 11"}, {"answer": "21 If a man therefore purge himself from these, he shall be a vessel unto honour, sanctified, and meet for the master\u2019s use, and prepared unto every good work.", "question": "2 Timothy 2: 21"}, {"answer": "  3 And verily in this thing ye have done wisely, for it is required of the Lord, at the hand of every steward, to render an account of his stewardship, both in time and in eternity.\n", "question": "D&C 72: 3"}, {"answer": "32 He that refuseth instruction despiseth his own soul: but he that heareth reproof getteth understanding.", "question": "Proverbs 15: 32"}, {"answer": "  30 He that asketh in the Spirit asketh according to the will of God; wherefore it is done even as he asketh.\n", "question": "D&C 46: 30"}, {"answer": "18 But those things which proceed out of the mouth come forth from the heart; and they defile the man.\r\n19 For out of the heart proceed evil thoughts, murders, adulteries, fornications, thefts, false witness, blasphemies:", "question": "Matthew 15: 18-19"}, {"answer": "18 Pride goeth before destruction, and an haughty spirit before a fall.", "question": "Proverbs 16: 18"}, {"answer": "  29 And if ye are purified and cleansed from all sin, ye shall ask whatsoever you will in the name of Jesus and it shall be done.\n", "question": "D&C 50: 29"}, {"answer": "14 Wherefore, take heed, my beloved brethren, that ye do not judge that which is evil to be of God, or that which is good and of God to be of the devil.", "question": "Moroni 7: 14"}, {"answer": "21 For all seek their own, not the things which are Jesus Christ\u2019s.", "question": "Philipians 2: 21"}, {"answer": "24 And the servant of the Lord must not strive; but be gentle unto all men, apt to teach, patient,", "question": "2 Timothy 2: 24"}, {"answer": "4 And I heard another voice from heaven, saying, Come out of her, my people, that ye be not partakers of her sins, and that ye receive not of her plagues.", "question": "Revelation 18: 4"}, {"answer": "10 Only by pride cometh contention: but with the well advised is wisdom.", "question": "Proverbs 13: 10"}, {"answer": "2 A bishop then must be blameless, the husband of one wife, vigilant, sober, of good behaviour, given to hospitality, apt to teach;", "question": "1 Timothy 3: 2"}, {"answer": "  3 Ye ask, and receive not, because ye ask amiss, that ye may consume it upon your lusts.\n", "question": "James 4: 3"}, {"answer": "  22 And of some have compassion, making a difference:\n", "question": "Jude 1: 22"}, {"answer": "25 He that is of a proud heart stirreth up strife: but he that putteth his trust in the Lord shall be made fat.", "question": "Proverbs 28: 25"}, {"answer": "20 And they were all young men, and they were exceedingly valiant for courage, and also for strength and activity; but behold, this was not all\u2014they were men who were true at all times in whatsoever thing they were entrusted.", "question": "Alma 53: 20"}, {"answer": "4 Whosoever committeth sin transgresseth also the law: for sin is the transgression of the law.", "question": "1 John 3: 4"}, {"answer": "27 Behold, my son, I will write unto you again if I go not out soon against the Lamanites. Behold, the pride of this nation, or the people of the Nephites, hath proven their destruction except they should repent.", "question": "Moroni 8: 27"}, {"answer": "20 Woe unto them that call evil good, and good evil; that put darkness for light, and light for darkness; that put bitter for sweet, and sweet for bitter!", "question": "Isaiah 5: 20"}, {"answer": "  11 And now, my son, all men that are in a state of nature, or I would say, in a carnal state, are in the gall of bitterness and in the bonds of iniquity; they are without God in the world, and they have gone contrary to the nature of God; therefore, they are in a state contrary to the nature of happiness.\n", "question": "Alma 41: 11"}, {"answer": "41 And Aminadab said unto them: You must repent, and cry unto the voice, even until ye shall have faith in Christ, who was taught unto you by Alma, and Amulek, and Zeezrom; and when ye shall do this, the cloud of darkness shall be removed from overshadowing you.", "question": "Helaman 5: 41"}, {"answer": "49 Behold, this was the iniquity of thy sister Sodom, pride, fulness of bread, and abundance of idleness was in her and in her daughters, neither did she strengthen the hand of the poor and needy.", "question": "Ezekiel 16: 49"}, {"answer": "  23 Cease to contend one with another; cease to speak evil one of another.\n", "question": "D&C 136: 23"}, {"answer": "  3 Nevertheless, ye are blessed, for the testimony which ye have borne is recorded in heaven for the angels to look upon; and they rejoice over you, and your sins are forgiven you.\n", "question": "D&C 62: 3"}, {"answer": "  9 But, behold, faith cometh not by signs, but signs follow those that believe.\n", "question": "D&C 63: 9"}, {"answer": "14 The beginning of strife is as when one letteth out water: therefore leave off contention, before it be meddled with.", "question": "Proverbs 17: 14"}, {"answer": "  8 Also I say unto you, Whosoever shall confess me before men, him shall the Son of man also confess before the angels of God:\n  9 But he that denieth me before men shall be denied before the angels of God.\n", "question": "Luke 12: 8-9"}, {"answer": "26 Likewise the Spirit also helpeth our infirmities: for we know not what we should pray for as we ought: but the Spirit itself maketh intercession for us with groanings which cannot be uttered.", "question": "Romans 8: 26"}, {"answer": "  54 And see that there is no iniquity in the church, neither hardness with each other, neither lying, backbiting, nor evil speaking;\n", "question": "D&C 20: 54"}, {"answer": "12 For the word of God is quick, and powerful, and sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing even to the dividing asunder of body and spirit, and of the joints and marrow, and is a discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart.", "question": "Hebrews 4: 12"}, {"answer": "  16 Yea, I tell thee, that thou mayest know that there is none else save God that knowest thy thoughts and the intents of thy heart.\n", "question": "D&C 6: 16"}, {"answer": "12 And we beseech you, brethren, to know them which labour among you, and are over you in the Lord, and admonish you;\r\n13 And to esteem them very highly in love for their work\u2019s sake. And be at peace among yourselves.", "question": "1 Thessalonians 5: 12-13"}, {"answer": "5 Likewise, ye younger, submit yourselves unto the elder. Yea, all of you be subject one to another, and be clothed with humility: for God resisteth the proud, and giveth grace to the humble.\r\n6 Humble yourselves therefore under the mighty hand of God, that he may exalt you in due time:", "question": "1 Peter 5: 5-6"}, {"answer": "22 Ye do not remember the Lord your God in the things with which he hath blessed you, but ye do always remember your riches, not to thank the Lord your God for them; yea, your hearts are not drawn out unto the Lord, but they do swell with great pride, unto boasting, and unto great swelling, envyings, strifes, malice, persecutions, and murders, and all manner of iniquities.", "question": "Helaman 13: 22"}, {"answer": "26 And the Messiah cometh in the fulness of time, that he may redeem the children of men from the fall. And because that they are redeemed from the fall they have become free forever, knowing good from evil; to act for themselves and not to be acted upon, save it be by the punishment of the law at the great and last day, according to the commandments which God hath given.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 26"}, {"answer": "30 But wo unto the rich, who are rich as to the things of the world. For because they are rich they despise the poor, and they persecute the meek, and their hearts are upon their treasures; wherefore, their treasure is their god. And behold, their treasure shall perish with them also.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 30"}, {"answer": "  9 For verily I say unto you, they are given for the benefit of those who love me and keep all my commandments, and him that seeketh so to do; that all may be benefited that seek or that ask of me, that ask and not for a sign that they may consume it upon their lusts.\r\n", "question": "D&C 46: 9"}, {"answer": "  2 Behold, I, the Lord, who was crucified for the sins of the world, give unto you a commandment that you shall forsake the world.\r\n", "question": "D&C 53: 2"}, {"answer": "19 Therefore repent ye, repent ye, lest by knowing these things and not doing them ye shall suffer yourselves to come under condemnation, and ye are brought down unto this second death.", "question": "Helaman 14: 19"}, {"answer": "19 Wherefore, I beseech of you, brethren, that ye should search diligently in the light of Christ that ye may know good from evil; and if ye will lay hold upon every good thing, and condemn it not, ye certainly will be a child of Christ.", "question": "Moroni 7: 19"}, {"answer": "  7 And he that seeketh signs shall see signs, but not unto salvation.\n", "question": "D&C 63: 7"}, {"answer": "  13 For it is expedient that I, the Lord, should make every man accountable, as a steward over earthly blessings, which I have made and prepared for my creatures.\r\n", "question": "D&C 104: 13"}, {"answer": "30 And now remember, remember, my brethren, that whosoever perisheth, perisheth unto himself; and whosoever doeth iniquity, doeth it unto himself; for behold, ye are free; ye are permitted to act for yourselves; for behold, God hath given unto you a knowledge and he hath made you free.", "question": "Helaman 14: 30"}, {"answer": "41 And also he hath need to repent, for I, the Lord, am not well pleased with him, for he seeketh to excel, and he is not sufficiently meek before me.\r\n", "question": "D&C 58: 41"}, {"answer": "1 But there were false prophets also among the people, even as there shall be false teachers among you, who privily shall bring in damnable heresies, even denying the Lord that bought them, and bring upon themselves swift destruction. \r\n2 And many shall follow their pernicious ways; by reason of whom the way of truth shall be evil spoken of.", "question": "2 Peter 2: 1-2"}, {"answer": "  50 And by this you may know they are under the bondage of sin, because they come not unto me.\r\n", "question": "D&C 84: 50"}, {"answer": "  10 Yea, signs come by faith, not by the will of men, nor as they please, but by the will of God.\r\n", "question": "D&C 63: 10"}, {"answer": "1 And now it came to pass that according to our record, and we know our record to be true, for behold, it was a just man who did keep the record \u2014 for he truly did many miracles in the name of Jesus; and there was not any man who could do a miracle in the name of Jesus save he were cleansed every whit from his iniquity\u2014", "question": "3 Nephi 8: 1"}, {"answer": "20 And the reason why he ceaseth to do miracles among the children of men is because that they dwindle in unbelief, and depart from the right way, and know not the God in whom they should trust.", "question": "Mormon 9: 20"}, {"answer": "20 For ye are bought with a price: therefore glorify God in your body, and in your spirit, which are God\u2019s.", "question": "1 Corinthians 6: 20"}, {"answer": "  7 These are they that are redeemed of the Lord; yea, these are they that are taken out, that are delivered from that endless night of darkness; and thus they stand or fall; for behold, they are their own judges, whether to do good or do evil.\n", "question": "Alma 41: 7"}, {"answer": "  12 For if there be no faith among the children of men God can do no miracle among them; wherefore, he showed not himself until after their faith.\n", "question": "Ether 12: 12"}, {"answer": "58 And he did not many mighty works there because of their unbelief.", "question": "Matthew 13: 58"}, {"answer": "  14 But whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life.\n", "question": "John 4: 14"}, {"answer": "41 Yea, they turned back and tempted God, and limited the Holy One of Israel.", "question": "Psalms 78: 41"}, {"answer": "  22 And if ye judge the man who putteth up his petition to you for your substance that he perish not, and condemn him, how much more just will be your condemnation for withholding your substance, which doth not belong to you but to God, to whom also your life belongeth; and yet ye put up no petition, nor repent of the thing which thou hast done.\n", "question": "Mosiah 4: 22"}, {"answer": "  17 Yea, there are many who do say: If thou wilt show unto us a sign from heaven, then we shall know of a surety; then we shall believe.\n  18 Now I ask, is this faith? Behold, I say unto you, Nay; for if a man knoweth a thing he hath no cause to believe, for he knoweth it.\n", "question": "Alma 32: 17-18"}, {"answer": "  39 And that wicked one cometh and taketh away light and truth, through disobedience, from the children of men, and because of the tradition of their fathers.\n", "question": "D&C 93: 39"}, {"answer": "  29 Wherefore, as ye are agents, ye are on the Lord\u2019s errand; and whatever ye do according to the will of the Lord is the Lord\u2019s business.\n", "question": "D&C 64: 29"}, {"answer": "9 An hypocrite with his mouth destroyeth his neighbour: but through knowledge shall the just be delivered.", "question": "Proverbs 11: 9"}, {"answer": "38 Ye have heard that it hath been said, An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth:\r\n39 But I say unto you, That ye resist not evil: but whosoever shall smite thee on thy right cheek, turn to him the other also.", "question": "Matthew 5: 38-39"}, {"answer": "  27 Therefore, O my son, whosoever will come may come and partake of the waters of life freely; and whosoever will not come the same is not compelled to come; but in the last day it shall be restored unto him according to his deeds.\n", "question": "Alma 42: 27"}, {"answer": "  19 And now, how much more cursed is he that knoweth the will of God and doeth it not, than he that only believeth, or only hath cause to believe, and falleth into transgression?\n", "question": "Alma 32: 19"}, {"answer": "19 When any one heareth the word of the kingdom, and understandeth it not, then cometh the wicked one, and catcheth away that which was sown in his heart. This is he which received seed by the way side.", "question": "Matthew 13: 19"}, {"answer": "  64 Whatsoever ye ask the Father in my name it shall be given unto you, that is expedient for you;\n  65 And if ye ask anything that is not expedient for you, it shall turn unto your condemnation.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 64-65"}, {"answer": "13 Some were lifted up in pride, and others were exceedingly humble; some did return railing for railing, while others would receive railing and persecution and all manner of afflictions, and would not turn and revile again, but were humble and penitent before God.", "question": "3 Nephi 6: 13"}, {"answer": "12 For we wrestle not against flesh and blood, but against principalities, against powers, against the rulers of the darkness of this world, against spiritual wickedness in high places.", "question": "Ephesians 6: 12"}, {"answer": "  6 But wo unto them that are deceivers and hypocrites, for, thus saith the Lord, I will bring them to judgment.\n", "question": "D&C 50: 6"}, {"answer": "  10 Unto the day when the Lord shall come to recompense unto every man according to his work, and measure to every man according to the measure which he has measured to his fellow man.\n", "question": "D&C 1: 10"}, {"answer": "19 And if there were miracles wrought then, why has God ceased to be a God of miracles and yet be an unchangeable Being? And behold, I say unto you he changeth not; if so he would cease to be God; and he ceaseth not to be God, and is a God of miracles.\r\n", "question": "Mormon 9: 19"}, {"answer": "  8 Wherefore, stand ye in holy places, and be not moved, until the day of the Lord come; for behold, it cometh quickly, saith the Lord. Amen.\n", "question": "D&C 87: 8"}, {"answer": "  3 And it is requisite with the justice of God that men should be judged according to their works; and if their works were good in this life, and the desires of their hearts were good, that they should also, at the last day, be restored unto that which is good.\n", "question": "Alma 41: 3"}, {"answer": "  21 And now, if God, who has created you, on whom you are dependent for your lives and for all that ye have and are, doth grant unto you whatsoever ye ask that is right, in faith, believing that ye shall receive, O then, how ye ought to impart of the substance that ye have one to another.\n", "question": "Mosiah 4: 21"}, {"answer": "  9 And I say unto you, Make to yourselves friends of the mammon of unrighteousness; that, when ye fail, they may receive you into everlasting habitations.\n", "question": "Luke 16: 9"}, {"answer": "  29 Man was also in the beginning with God. Intelligence, or the light of truth, was not created or made, neither indeed can be.\n", "question": "D&C 93: 29"}, {"answer": "1 The Lord is my light and my salvation; whom shall I fear? the Lord is the strength of my life; of whom shall I be afraid?", "question": "Psalms 27: 1"}, {"answer": "  21 He that hath my commandments, and keepeth them, he it is that loveth me: and he that loveth me shall be loved of my Father, and I will love him, and will manifest myself to him.\n", "question": "John 14: 21"}, {"answer": "  12 Prepare ye, prepare ye for that which is to come, for the Lord is nigh;\n", "question": "D&C 1: 12"}, {"answer": "1 Now the Spirit speaketh expressly, that in the latter times some shall depart from the faith, giving heed to seducing spirits, and doctrines of devils;\r\n2 Speaking lies in hypocrisy; having their conscience seared with a hot iron;\r\n3 Forbidding to marry, and commanding to abstain from meats, which God hath created to be received with thanksgiving of them which believe and know the truth.", "question": "1 Timothy 4: 1-3"}, {"answer": "  14 Therefore, my son, see that you are merciful unto your brethren; deal justly, judge righteously, and do good continually; and if ye do all these things then shall ye receive your reward; yea, ye shall have mercy restored unto you again; ye shall have justice restored unto you again; ye shall have a righteous judgment restored unto you again; and ye shall have good rewarded unto you again.\n  15 For that which ye do send out shall return unto you again, and be restored; therefore, the word restoration more fully condemneth the sinner, and justifieth him not at all.\n", "question": "Alma 41: 14-15"}, {"answer": "1 Cast thy bread upon the waters: for thou shalt find it after many days.", "question": "Ecclesiastes 11: 1"}, {"answer": "21 Behold, I say unto you that whoso believeth in Christ, doubting nothing, whatsoever he shall ask the Father in the name of Christ it shall be granted him; and this promise is unto all, even unto the ends of the earth.", "question": "Mormon 9: 21"}, {"answer": "17 He that hath pity upon the poor lendeth unto the Lord; and that which he hath given will he pay him again.", "question": "Proverbs 19: 17"}, {"answer": "  28 And again, I command thee that thou shalt pray vocally as well as in thy heart; yea, before the world as well as in secret, in public as well as in private.\n", "question": "D&C 19: 28"}, {"answer": "10 Herein is love, not that we loved God, but that he loved us, and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins.\r\n11 Beloved, if God so loved us, we ought also to love one another.", "question": "1 John 4: 10-11"}, {"answer": "  32 And ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.\n", "question": "John 8: 32"}, {"answer": "19 For I will, saith the Lord, that they shall hide up their treasures unto me; and cursed be they who hide not up their treasures unto me; for none hideth up their treasures unto me save it be the righteous; and he that hideth not up his treasures unto me, cursed is he, and also the treasure, and none shall redeem it because of the curse of the land.", "question": "Helaman 13: 19"}, {"answer": "  4 And whatsoever they shall speak when moved upon by the Holy Ghost shall be scripture, shall be the will of the Lord, shall be the mind of the Lord, shall be the word of the Lord, shall be the voice of the Lord, and the power of God unto salvation.\n", "question": "D&C 68: 4"}, {"answer": "24 He that spareth his rod hateth his son: but he that loveth him chasteneth him betimes.", "question": "Proverbs 13: 24"}, {"answer": "9 Have not I commanded thee? Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid, neither be thou dismayed: for the Lord thy God is with thee whithersoever thou goest.", "question": "Joshua 1: 9"}, {"answer": "  33 Fear not to do good, my sons, for whatsoever ye sow, that shall ye also reap; therefore, if ye sow good ye shall also reap good for your reward.\n", "question": "D&C 6: 33"}, {"answer": "  16 But, exerting all my powers to call upon God to deliver me out of the power of this enemy which had seized upon me, and at the very moment when I was ready to sink into despair and abandon myself to destruction\u2014not to an imaginary ruin, but to the power of some actual being from the unseen world, who had such marvelous power as I had never before felt in any being\u2014just at this moment of great alarm, I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.\r\n  17 It no sooner appeared than I found myself delivered from the enemy which held me bound. When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other\u2014This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!\r\n\r\n", "question": "JS-H 1: 16-17"}, {"answer": "  23 But unto him that keepeth my commandments I will give the mysteries of my kingdom, and the same shall be in him a well of living water, springing up unto everlasting life.\n", "question": "D&C 63: 23"}, {"answer": "11 Wealth gotten by vanity shall be diminished: but he that gathereth by labour shall increase.", "question": "Proverbs 13: 11"}, {"answer": "  17 Be not ashamed, neither confounded; but be admonished in all your high-mindedness and pride, for it bringeth a snare upon your souls.\n", "question": "D&C 90: 17"}, {"answer": "  34 Jesus answered them, Verily, verily, I say unto you, Whosoever committeth sin is the servant of sin.\n", "question": "John 8: 34"}, {"answer": "8 I will therefore that men pray every where, lifting up holy hands, without wrath and doubting.\r\n", "question": "1 Timothy 2: 8"}, {"answer": "1 Verily, thus saith the Lord: It shall come to pass that every soul who forsaketh his sins and cometh unto me, and calleth on my name, and obeyeth my voice, and keepeth my commandments, shall see my face and know that I am;", "question": "D&C 93: 1"}, {"answer": "15 The rod and reproof give wisdom: but a child left to himself bringeth his mother to shame.", "question": "Proverbs 29: 15"}, {"answer": "  16 Confess your faults one to another, and pray one for another, that ye may be healed. The effectual fervent prayer of a righteous man availeth much.\n", "question": "James 5: 16"}, {"answer": "36 Or have angels ceased to appear unto the children of men? Or has he withheld the power of the Holy Ghost from them? Or will he, so long as time shall last, or the earth shall stand, or there shall be one man upon the face thereof to be saved?\r\n37 Behold I say unto you, Nay; for it is by faith that miracles are wrought; and it is by faith that angels appear and minister unto men; wherefore, if these things have ceased wo be unto the children of men, for it is because of unbelief, and all is vain.", "question": "Moroni 7: 36-37"}, {"answer": "  29 But they receive it not; for they perceive not the light, and they turn their hearts from me because of the precepts of men.\n", "question": "D&C 45: 29"}, {"answer": "16 Know ye not, that to whom ye yield yourselves servants to obey, his servants ye are to whom ye obey; whether of sin unto death, or of obedience unto righteousness?", "question": "Romans 6: 16"}, {"answer": "34 Then shall the King say unto them on his right hand, Come, ye blessed of my Father, inherit the kingdom prepared for you from the foundation of the world:\r\n35 For I was an hungred, and ye gave me meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me drink: I was a stranger, and ye took me in:\r\n36 Naked, and ye clothed me: I was sick, and ye visited me: I was in prison, and ye came unto me.\r\n37 Then shall the righteous answer him, saying, Lord, when saw we thee an hungred, and fed thee? or thirsty, and gave thee drink?\r\n38 When saw we thee a stranger, and took thee in? or naked, and clothed thee?\r\n39 Or when saw we thee sick, or in prison, and came unto thee?\r\n40 And the King shall answer and say unto them, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.", "question": "Matthew 25: 34-40"}, {"answer": "  20 Therefore, in the ordinances thereof, the power of godliness is manifest.\n  21 And without the ordinances thereof, and the authority of the priesthood, the power of godliness is not manifest unto men in the flesh;\n", "question": "D&C 84: 20-21"}, {"answer": "13 And ye shall seek me, and find me, when ye shall search for me with all your heart.", "question": "Jeremiah 29: 13"}, {"answer": "15 And it came to pass that there was no contention in the land, because of the love of God which did dwell in the hearts of the people.\r\n", "question": "4 Nephi 1: 15"}, {"answer": "  68 Therefore, sanctify yourselves that your minds become single to God, and the days will come that you shall see him; for he will unveil his face unto you, and it shall be in his own time, and in his own way, and according to his own will.\n", "question": "D&C 88: 68"}, {"answer": "3 Lo, children are an heritage of the Lord: and the fruit of the womb is his reward.", "question": "Psalms 127: 3"}, {"answer": "14 And then cometh the judgment of the Holy One upon them; and then cometh the time that he that is filthy shall be filthy still; and he that is righteous shall be righteous still; he that is happy shall be happy still; and he that is unhappy shall be unhappy still.\r\n", "question": "Mormon 9: 14"}, {"answer": "11 And he said, Go forth, and stand upon the mount before the Lord. And, behold, the Lord passed by, and a great and strong wind rent the mountains, and brake in pieces the rocks before the Lord; but the Lord was not in the wind: and after the wind an earthquake; but the Lord was not in the earthquake:\r\n12 And after the earthquake a fire; but the Lord was not in the fire: and after the fire a still small voice.", "question": "1 Kings 19: 11-12"}, {"answer": "  32 But my disciples shall stand in holy places, and shall not be moved; but among the wicked, men shall lift up their voices and curse God and die.\n", "question": "D&C 45: 32"}, {"answer": "119 Organize yourselves; prepare every needful thing; and establish a house, even a house of prayer, a house of fasting, a house of faith, a house of learning, a house of glory, a house of order, a house of God;", "question": "D&C 88: 119"}, {"answer": "38 But behold, your days of probation are past; ye have procrastinated the day of your salvation until it is everlastingly too late, and your destruction is made sure; yea, for ye have sought all the days of your lives for that which ye could not obtain; and ye have sought for happiness in doing iniquity, which thing is contrary to the nature of that righteousness which is in our great and Eternal Head.", "question": "Helaman 13: 38"}, {"answer": "37 And again, by way of commandment to the church concerning the manner of baptism\u2014All those who humble themselves before God, and desire to be baptized, and come forth with broken hearts and contrite spirits, and witness before the church that they have truly repented of all their sins, and are willing to take upon them the name of Jesus Christ, having a determination to serve him to the end, and truly manifest by their works that they have received of the Spirit of Christ unto the remission of their sins, shall be received by baptism into his church.", "question": "D&C 20: 37"}, {"answer": "  8 But the day soon cometh that ye shall see me, and know that I am; for the veil of darkness shall soon be rent, and he that is not purified shall not abide the day.\n", "question": "D&C 38: 8"}, {"answer": "  22 And now, verily I say unto you, and this is wisdom, make unto yourselves friends with the mammon of unrighteousness, and they will not destroy you.\n", "question": "D&C 82: 22"}, {"answer": "11 When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became a man, I put away childish things.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 11"}, {"answer": "  17 Think of your brethren like unto yourselves, and be familiar with all and free with your substance, that they may be rich like unto you.\n", "question": "Jacob 2: 17"}, {"answer": " 15 And it was this same Melchizedek to whom Abraham paid tithes; yea, even our father Abraham paid tithes of one-tenth part of all he possessed.\n", "question": "Alma 13: 15"}, {"answer": "61 If thou shalt ask, thou shalt receive revelation upon revelation, knowledge upon knowledge, that thou mayest know the mysteries and peaceable things\u2014that which bringeth joy, that which bringeth life eternal.", "question": "D&C 42: 61"}, {"answer": "8 Charity never faileth: but whether there be prophecies, they shall fail; whether there be tongues, they shall cease; whether there be knowledge, it shall vanish away.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 8"}, {"answer": "  19 The weak things of the world shall come forth and break down the mighty and strong ones, that man should not counsel his fellow man, neither trust in the arm of flesh \u2014\n", "question": "D&C 1: 19"}, {"answer": "  27 And no man receiveth a fulness unless he keepeth his commandments.\n  28 He that keepeth his commandments receiveth truth and light, until he is glorified in truth and knoweth all things.\n", "question": "D&C 93: 27-28"}, {"answer": "  6 And my people must needs be chastened until they learn obedience, if it must needs be, by the things which they suffer.\n", "question": "D&C 105: 6"}, {"answer": "7 And the peace of God, which passeth all understanding, shall keep your hearts and minds through Christ Jesus.", "question": "Philippians 4: 7"}, {"answer": "  16 Cursed are all those that shall lift up the heel against mine anointed, saith the Lord, and cry they have sinned when they have not sinned before me, saith the Lord, but have done that which was meet in mine eyes, and which I commanded them.\n", "question": "D&C 121: 16"}, {"answer": "1 Though I speak with the tongues of men and of angels, and have not charity, I am become as sounding brass, or a tinkling cymbal.\r\n2 And though I have the gift of prophecy, and understand all mysteries, and all knowledge; and though I have all faith, so that I could remove mountains, and have not charity, I am nothing.\r\n3 And though I bestow all my goods to feed the poor, and though I give my body to be burned, and have not charity, it profiteth me nothing.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 1-3"}, {"answer": "15 But sanctify the Lord God in your hearts: and be ready always to give an answer to every man that asketh you a reason of the hope that is in you with meekness and fear:", "question": "1 Peter 3: 15"}, {"answer": "  7 And now, verily I say unto you, I, the Lord, will not lay any sin to your charge; go your ways and sin no more; but unto that soul who sinneth shall the former sins return, saith the Lord your God.\n", "question": "D&C 82: 7"}, {"answer": "  1 I waited patiently for the Lord; and he inclined unto me, and heard my cry.\n", "question": "Psalms 40: 1"}, {"answer": "  36 The glory of God is intelligence, or, in other words, light and truth.\n", "question": "D&C 93: 36"}, {"answer": "3 Thou shalt have no other gods before me.", "question": "Exodus 20: 3"}, {"answer": "6 And behold, how oft you have transgressed the commandments and the laws of God, and have gone on in the persuasions of men.\r\n7 For, behold, you should not have feared man more than God. Although men set at naught the counsels of God, and despise his words\u2014\r\n8 Yet you should have been faithful; and he would have extended his arm and supported you against all the fiery darts of the adversary; and he would have been with you in every time of trouble.\r\n", "question": "D&C 3: 6-8"}, {"answer": "27 But God hath chosen the foolish things of the world to confound the wise; and God hath chosen the weak things of the world to confound the things which are mighty;", "question": "1 Corinthians 1: 27"}, {"answer": "  31 Now, I, the Lord, am not well pleased with the inhabitants of Zion, for there are idlers among them; and their children are also growing up in wickedness; they also seek not earnestly the riches of eternity, but their eyes are full of greediness.\n", "question": "D&C 68: 31"}, {"answer": "26 For whosoever shall be ashamed of me and of my words, of him shall the Son of man be ashamed, when he shall come in his own kingdom, clothed in the glory of his Father, with the holy angels.", "question": "Luke 9: 26"}, {"answer": "2 But behold, there are many that harden their hearts against the Holy Spirit, that it hath no place in them; wherefore, they cast many things away which are written and esteem them as things of naught.", "question": "2 Nephi 33: 2"}, {"answer": "4 Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven image, or any likeness of any thing that is in heaven above, or that is in the earth beneath, or that is in the water under the earth:\r\n5 Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them, nor serve them: for I the Lord thy God am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto the third and fourth generation of them that hate me;\r\n6 And shewing mercy unto thousands of them that love me, and keep my commandments.", "question": "Exodus 20: 4-6"}, {"answer": "  7 Behold, verily I say unto you, there are hypocrites among you, who have deceived some, which has given the adversary power; but behold such shall be reclaimed;\n", "question": "D&C 50: 7"}, {"answer": "  14 Seek not after riches nor the vain things of this world; for behold, you cannot carry them with you.\n", "question": "Alma 39: 14"}, {"answer": "  43 For they loved the praise of men more than the praise of God.\n", "question": "John 12: 43"}, {"answer": "  1 Upon you my fellow servants, in the name of Messiah I confer the Priesthood of Aaron, which holds the keys of the ministering of angels, and of the gospel of repentance, and of baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; and this shall never be taken again from the earth, until the sons of Levi do offer again an offering unto the Lord in righteousness.\n", "question": "D&C 13: 1"}, {"answer": "3 And thus we see that except the Lord doth chasten his people with many afflictions, yea, except he doth visit them with death and with terror, and with famine and with all manner of pestilence, they will not remember him.", "question": "Helaman 12: 3"}, {"answer": "7 Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord thy God in vain; for the Lord will not hold him guiltless that taketh his name in vain.", "question": "Exodus 20: 7"}, {"answer": "  16 Wo unto you rich men, that will not give your substance to the poor, for your riches will canker your souls; and this shall be your lamentation in the day of visitation, and of judgment, and of indignation: The harvest is past, the summer is ended, and my soul is not saved!\n", "question": "D&C 56: 16"}, {"answer": "6 And now, my beloved son, notwithstanding their hardness, let us labor diligently; for if we should cease to labor, we should be brought under condemnation; for we have a labor to perform whilst in this tabernacle of clay, that we may conquer the enemy of all righteousness, and rest our souls in the kingdom of God.\r\n", "question": "Moroni 9: 6"}, {"answer": "  23 But learn that he who doeth the works of righteousness shall receive his reward, even peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.\n", "question": "D&C 59: 23"}, {"answer": "13 And now abideth faith, hope, charity, these three; but the greatest of these is charity.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 13"}, {"answer": "  13 Wherefore, I call upon the weak things of the world, those who are unlearned and despised, to thrash the nations by the power of my Spirit;\n", "question": "D&C 35: 13"}, {"answer": "  15 And he said unto them, Take heed, and beware of covetousness: for a man\u2019s life consisteth not in the abundance of the things which he possesseth.\n", "question": "Luke 12: 15"}, {"answer": "  9 Nevertheless, when the wicked rule the people mourn.\n", "question": "D&C 98: 9"}, {"answer": "  17 Therefore, as they were unfaithful they did not prosper nor progress in their journey, but were driven back, and incurred the displeasure of God upon them; and therefore they were smitten with famine and sore afflictions, to stir them up in remembrance of their duty.\n", "question": "Mosiah 1: 17"}, {"answer": "  40 But I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth.\n", "question": "D&C 93: 40"}, {"answer": "14 Ye shall not go after other gods, of the gods of the people which are round about you;", "question": "Deuteronomy 6: 14"}, {"answer": "9 For we know in part, and we prophesy in part.\r\n10 But when that which is perfect is come, then that which is in part shall be done away.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 9-10"}, {"answer": "  45 And this is not all. Do ye not suppose that I know of these things myself? Behold, I testify unto you that I do know that these things whereof I have spoken are true. And how do ye suppose that I know of their surety?\n  46 Behold, I say unto you they are made known unto me by the Holy Spirit of God. Behold, I have fasted and prayed many days that I might know these things of myself. And now I do know of myself that they are true; for the Lord God hath made them manifest unto me by his Holy Spirit; and this is the spirit of revelation which is in me.\n", "question": "Alma 5: 45-46"}, {"answer": "  18 And whoso forbiddeth to abstain from meats, that man should not eat the same, is not ordained of God;\n  19 For, behold, the beasts of the field and the fowls of the air, and that which cometh of the earth, is ordained for the use of man for food and for raiment, and that he might have in abundance.\n", "question": "D&C 49: 18-19"}, {"answer": "10 Trust not in oppression, and become not vain in robbery: if riches increase, set not your heart upon them.", "question": "Psalms 62: 10"}, {"answer": "  26 And the lesser priesthood continued, which priesthood holdeth the key of the ministering of angels and the preparatory gospel;\n", "question": "D&C 84: 26"}, {"answer": "6 Who will render to every man according to his deeds:\r\n7 To them who by patient continuance in well doing seek for glory and honour and immortality, eternal life:\r\n8 But unto them that are contentious, and do not obey the truth, but obey unrighteousness, indignation and wrath,\r\n", "question": "Romans 2: 6-8"}, {"answer": "12 Wherefore lift up the hands which hang down, and the feeble knees;\r\n", "question": "Hebrews 12: 12"}, {"answer": "  7 They were slow to hearken unto the voice of the Lord their God; therefore, the Lord their God is slow to hearken unto their prayers, to answer them in the day of their trouble.\n  8 In the day of their peace they esteemed lightly my counsel; but, in the day of their trouble, of necessity they feel after me.\n", "question": "D&C 101: 7-8"}, {"answer": "27 Thus we may see that the Lord is merciful unto all who will, in the sincerity of their hearts, call upon his holy name.", "question": "Helaman 3: 27"}, {"answer": "  33 For man is spirit. The elements are eternal, and spirit and element, inseparably connected, receive a fulness of joy;\n  34 And when separated, man cannot receive a fulness of joy.\n", "question": "D&C 93: 33-34"}, {"answer": "4 Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up,\r\n5 Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil;\r\n6 Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth;\r\n7 Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 4-7"}, {"answer": "  23 But God ceaseth not to be God, and mercy claimeth the penitent, and mercy cometh because of the atonement; and the atonement bringeth to pass the resurrection of the dead; and the resurrection of the dead bringeth back men into the presence of God; and thus they are restored into his presence, to be judged according to their works, according to the law and justice.\n", "question": "Alma 42: 23"}, {"answer": "8 Remember the sabbath day, to keep it holy.\r\n9 Six days shalt thou labour, and do all thy work:\r\n10 But the seventh day is the sabbath of the Lord thy God: in it thou shalt not do any work, thou, nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is within thy gates:\r\n11 For in six days the Lord made heaven and earth, the sea, and all that in them is, and rested the seventh day: wherefore the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and hallowed it.", "question": "Exodus 20: 8-11"}, {"answer": "  39 And if ye seek the riches which it is the will of the Father to give unto you, ye shall be the richest of all people, for ye shall have the riches of eternity; and it must needs be that the riches of the earth are mine to give; but beware of pride, lest ye become as the Nephites of old.\n\n", "question": "D&C 38: 39"}, {"answer": "12 For now we see through a glass, darkly; but then face to face: now I know in part; but then shall I know even as also I am known.", "question": "1 Corinthians 13: 12"}, {"answer": "22 But be ye doers of the word, and not hearers only, deceiving your own selves.", "question": "James 1: 22"}, {"answer": "21 Let no man break the laws of the land, for he that keepeth the laws of God hath no need to break the laws of the land.\r\n22 Wherefore, be subject to the powers that be, until he reigns whose right it is to reign, and subdues all enemies under his feet.", "question": "D&C 58: 21-22"}, {"answer": "2 When pride cometh, then cometh shame: but with the lowly is wisdom.", "question": "Proverbs 11: 2"}, {"answer": "32 And they who remain shall also be quickened; nevertheless, they shall return again to their own place, to enjoy that which they are willing to receive, because they were not willing to enjoy that which they might have received.", "question": "D&C 88: 32"}, {"answer": "11 For there is no respect of persons with God.", "question": "Romans 2: 11"}, {"answer": "29 He commandeth that there shall be no priestcrafts; for, behold, priestcrafts are that men preach and set themselves up for a light unto the world, that they may get gain and praise of the world; but they seek not the welfare of Zion.", "question": "2 Nephi 26: 29"}, {"answer": "12 Honour thy father and thy mother: that thy days may be long upon the land which the Lord thy God giveth thee.", "question": "Exodus 20: 12"}, {"answer": "  29 And if thy right eye offend thee, pluck it out, and cast it from thee: for it is profitable for thee that one of thy members should perish, and not that thy whole body should be cast into hell.\r\n  30 And if thy right hand offend thee, cut it off, and cast it from thee: for it is profitable for thee that one of thy members should perish, and not that thy whole body should be cast into hell.", "question": "Matthew 5: 29-30"}, {"answer": "  21 Nevertheless the Lord seeth fit to chasten his people; yea, he trieth their patience and their faith.\r\n  22 Nevertheless\u2014whosoever putteth his trust in him the same shall be lifted up at the last day. Yea, and thus it was with this people.", "question": "Mosiah 23: 21-22"}, {"answer": "8 Verily I say unto you, all among them who know their hearts are honest, and are broken, and their spirits contrite, and are willing to observe their covenants by sacrifice\u2014yea, every sacrifice which I, the Lord, shall command\u2014they are accepted of me.", "question": "D&C 97: 8"}, {"answer": "13 Thou shalt not kill.", "question": "Exodus 20: 13"}, {"answer": "14 For if ye forgive men their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you:\r\n15 But if ye forgive not men their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses.", "question": "Matthew 6: 14-15"}, {"answer": "16 And I desire that ye should remember to observe the statutes and the judgments of the Lord; behold, this hath been the anxiety of my soul from the beginning.", "question": "2 Nephi 1: 16"}, {"answer": "  21 Therefore, verily, thus saith the Lord, let Zion rejoice, for this is Zion \u2014 the pure in heart; therefore, let Zion rejoice, while all the wicked shall mourn.", "question": "D&C 97: 21"}, {"answer": "19 Every tree that bringeth not forth good fruit is hewn down, and cast into the fire.\r\n20 Wherefore by their fruits ye shall know them.", "question": "Matthew 7: 19-20"}, {"answer": "14 Thou shalt not commit adultery.", "question": "Exodus 20: 14"}, {"answer": "121 Therefore, cease from all your light speeches, from all laughter, from all your lustful desires, from all your pride and light-mindedness, and from all your wicked doings.", "question": "D&C 88: 121"}, {"answer": "40 And if any man will sue thee at the law, and take away thy coat, let him have thy cloke also.\r\n41 And whosoever shall compel thee to go a mile, go with him twain.", "question": "Matthew 5: 40-41"}, {"answer": "  10 In this the children of God are manifest, and the children of the devil: whosoever doeth not righteousness is not of God, neither he that loveth not his brother.", "question": "1 John 3: 10"}, {"answer": "38 For I am persuaded, that neither death, nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, nor things to come,\r\n39 Nor height, nor depth, nor any other creature, shall be able to separate us from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus our Lord.", "question": "Romans 8: 38-39"}, {"answer": "  18 O that thou hadst hearkened to my commandments! then had thy peace been as a river, and thy righteousness as the waves of the sea:", "question": "Isaiah 48: 18"}, {"answer": "15 Thou shalt not steal.", "question": "Exodus 20: 15"}, {"answer": "15 But behold, the Lord hath redeemed my soul from hell; I have beheld his glory, and I am encircled about eternally in the arms of his love.", "question": "2 Nephi 1: 15"}, {"answer": "  34 Hearken ye to these words. Behold, I am Jesus Christ, the Savior of the world. Treasure these things up in your hearts, and let the solemnities of eternity rest upon your minds.", "question": "D&C 43: 34"}, {"answer": "28 And it came to pass, when Jesus had ended these sayings, the people were astonished at his doctrine:\r\n29 For he taught them as one having authority, and not as the scribes.", "question": "Matthew 7: 28-29"}, {"answer": "26 If any man among you seem to be religious, and bridleth not his tongue, but deceiveth his own heart, this man\u2019s religion is vain.", "question": "James 1: 26"}, {"answer": "16 Thou shalt not bear false witness against thy neighbour.", "question": "Exodus 20: 16"}, {"answer": "19 Whosoever therefore shall break one of these least commandments, and shall teach men so, he shall be called the least in the kingdom of heaven: but whosoever shall do and teach them, the same shall be called great in the kingdom of heaven.", "question": "Matthew 5: 19"}, {"answer": "39 And let him repent of his sins, for he seeketh the praise of the world.", "question": "D&C 58: 39"}, {"answer": "34 Take therefore no thought for the morrow: for the morrow shall take thought for the things of itself. Sufficient unto the day is the evil thereof.", "question": "Matthew 6: 34"}, {"answer": "6 Behold, I say unto you, that ye must visit the poor and the needy and administer to their relief, that they may be kept until all things may be done according to my law which ye have received. Amen.", "question": "D&C 44: 6"}, {"answer": "17 Thou shalt not covet thy neighbour\u2019s house, thou shalt not covet thy neighbour\u2019s wife, nor his manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his ox, nor his ass, nor any thing that is thy neighbour\u2019s.", "question": "Exodus 20: 17"}, {"answer": "36 For behold, the time is at hand that whosoever bringeth forth not good fruit, or whosoever doeth not the works of righteousness, the same have cause to wail and mourn.", "question": "Alma 5: 36"}, {"answer": "42 Give to him that asketh thee, and from him that would borrow of thee turn not thou away.", "question": "Matthew 5: 42"}, {"answer": "33 For what doth it profit a man if a gift is bestowed upon him, and he receive not the gift? Behold, he rejoices not in that which is given unto him, neither rejoices in him who is the giver of the gift.", "question": "D&C 88: 33"}, {"answer": "25 For whosoever will save his life shall lose it: and whosoever will lose his life for my sake shall find it.", "question": "Matthew 16: 25"}, {"answer": "2 But your iniquities have separated between you and your God, and your sins have hid his face from you, that he will not hear.", "question": "Isaiah 59: 2"}, {"answer": "17 Think not that I am come to destroy the law, or the prophets: I am not come to destroy, but to fulfil.\r\n18 For verily I say unto you, Till heaven and earth pass, one jot or one tittle shall in no wise pass from the law, till all be fulfilled.", "question": "Matthew 5: 17-18"}, {"answer": "28 And now, my sons, I would that ye should look to the great Mediator, and hearken unto his great commandments; and be faithful unto his words, and choose eternal life, according to the will of his Holy Spirit;\r\n29 And not choose eternal death, according to the will of the flesh and the evil which is therein, which giveth the spirit of the devil power to captivate, to bring you down to hell, that he may reign over you in his own kingdom.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 28-29"}, {"answer": "34 Behold, the Lord requireth the heart and a willing mind; and the willing and obedient shall eat the good of the land of Zion in these last days.", "question": "D&C 64: 34"}, {"answer": "27 Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this, To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction, and to keep himself unspotted from the world.", "question": "James 1: 27"}, {"answer": "24 Therefore whosoever heareth these sayings of mine, and doeth them, I will liken him unto a wise man, which built his house upon a rock:\r\n25 And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell not: for it was founded upon a rock.", "question": "Matthew 7: 24-25"}, {"answer": "7 Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you:\r\n8 For every one that asketh receiveth; and he that seeketh findeth; and to him that knocketh it shall be opened.", "question": "Matthew 7: 7-8"}, {"answer": "11 Behold, all ye that kindle a fire, that compass yourselves about with sparks: walk in the light of your fire, and in the sparks that ye have kindled. This shall ye have of mine hand; ye shall lie down in sorrow.", "question": "Isaiah 50: 11"}, {"answer": "57 For they that are wise and have received the truth, and have taken the Holy Spirit for their guide, and have not been deceived\u2014verily I say unto you, they shall not be hewn down and cast into the fire, but shall abide the day.", "question": "D&C 45: 57"}, {"answer": "24 Judge not according to the appearance, but judge righteous judgment.", "question": "John 7: 24"}, {"answer": "28 Yea, thus we see that the gate of heaven is open unto all, even to those who will believe on the name of Jesus Christ, who is the Son of God.", "question": "Helaman 3: 28"}, {"answer": "1 For, behold, the day cometh, that shall burn as an oven; and all the proud, yea, and all that do wickedly, shall be stubble: and the day that cometh shall burn them up, saith the Lord of hosts, that it shall leave them neither root nor branch.", "question": "Malachi 4: 1"}, {"answer": "24 Then said Jesus unto his disciples, If any man will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow me.", "question": "Matthew 16: 24"}, {"answer": "35 That which breaketh a law, and abideth not by law, but seeketh to become a law unto itself, and willeth to abide in sin, and altogether abideth in sin, cannot be sanctified by law, neither by mercy, justice, nor judgment. Therefore, they must remain filthy still.", "question": "D&C 88: 35"}, {"answer": "3 And shall make him of quick understanding in the fear of the Lord: and he shall not judge after the sight of his eyes, neither reprove after the hearing of his ears:", "question": "Isaiah 11: 3"}, {"answer": "25 Agree with thine adversary quickly, whiles thou art in the way with him; lest at any time the adversary deliver thee to the judge, and the judge deliver thee to the officer, and thou be cast into prison.\r\n26 Verily I say unto thee, Thou shalt by no means come out thence, till thou hast paid the uttermost farthing.", "question": "Matthew 5: 25-26"}, {"answer": "24 Therefore, wo be unto him that is at ease in Zion!", "question": "2 Nephi 28: 24"}, {"answer": "4 Therefore, they must needs be chastened and tried, even as Abraham, who was commanded to offer up his only son.\r\n5 For all those who will not endure chastening, but deny me, cannot be sanctified.", "question": "D&C 101: 4-5"}, {"answer": "11 But he that is greatest among you shall be your servant.", "question": "Matthew 23: 11"}, {"answer": "16 O that he would rid you from this iniquity and abomination. And, O that ye would listen unto the word of his commands, and let not this pride of your hearts destroy your souls!", "question": "Jacob 2: 16"}, {"answer": "13 But as for me, when they were sick, my clothing was sackcloth: I humbled my soul with fasting; and my prayer returned into mine own bosom.", "question": "Psalms 35: 13"}, {"answer": "3 And said, Verily I say unto you, Except ye be converted, and become as little children, ye shall not enter into the kingdom of heaven.", "question": "Matthew 18: 3"}, {"answer": "49 Behold, my soul abhorreth sin, and my heart delighteth in righteousness; and I will praise the holy name of my God.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 49"}, {"answer": "69 Remember the great and last promise which I have made unto you; cast away your idle thoughts and your excess of laughter far from you.", "question": "D&C 88: 69"}, {"answer": "20 Brethren, be not children in understanding: howbeit in malice be ye children, but in understanding be men.", "question": "1 Corinthians 14: 20"}, {"answer": "4 Wherefore, now after I have spoken these words, if ye cannot understand them it will be because ye ask not, neither do ye knock; wherefore, ye are not brought into the light, but must perish in the dark.", "question": "2 Nephi 32: 4"}, {"answer": "22 Lay hands suddenly on no man, neither be partaker of other men\u2019s sins: keep thyself pure.", "question": "1 Timothy 5: 22"}, {"answer": "1 And as Jesus passed by, he saw a man which was blind from his birth.\r\n2 And his disciples asked him, saying, Master, who did sin, this man, or his parents, that he was born blind?\r\n3 Jesus answered, Neither hath this man sinned, nor his parents: but that the works of God should be made manifest in him.", "question": "John 9: 1-3"}, {"answer": "32 Let him that is ignorant learn wisdom by humbling himself and calling upon the Lord his God, that his eyes may be opened that he may see, and his ears opened that he may hear;", "question": "D&C 136: 32"}, {"answer": "9 After this manner therefore pray ye: Our Father which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy name.\r\n10 Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done in earth, as it is in heaven.\r\n11 Give us this day our daily bread.\r\n12 And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors.\r\n13 And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil: For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever. Amen.", "question": "Matthew 6: 9-13"}, {"answer": "10 And again, believe that ye must repent of your sins and forsake them, and humble yourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive you; and now, if you believe all these things see that ye do them.", "question": "Mosiah 4: 10"}, {"answer": "28 Behold, are ye stripped of pride? I say unto you, if ye are not ye are not prepared to meet God. Behold ye must prepare quickly; for the kingdom of heaven is soon at hand, and such an one hath not eternal life.", "question": "Alma 5: 28"}, {"answer": "34 Therefore, fear not, little flock; do good; let earth and hell combine against you, for if ye are built upon my rock, they cannot prevail.", "question": "D&C 6: 34"}, {"answer": "13 The fear of the Lord is to hate evil: pride, and arrogancy, and the evil way, and the froward mouth, do I hate.", "question": "Proverbs 8: 13"}, {"answer": "2 And I will send upon him the Comforter, which shall teach him the truth and the way whither he shall go;\r\n3 And inasmuch as he is faithful, I will crown him again with sheaves.", "question": "D&C 79: 2-3"}, {"answer": "36 But I say unto you, That every idle word that men shall speak, they shall give account thereof in the day of judgment.\r\n37 For by thy words thou shalt be justified, and by thy words thou shalt be condemned.", "question": "Matthew 12: 36-37"}, {"answer": "15 Beware of false prophets, which come to you in sheep\u2019s clothing, but inwardly they are ravening wolves.", "question": "Matthew 7: 15"}, {"answer": "1 We then that are strong ought to bear the infirmities of the weak, and not to please ourselves.", "question": "Romans 15: 1"}, {"answer": "14 Seeing then that we have a great high priest, that is passed into the heavens, Jesus the Son of God, let us hold fast our profession.\r\n15 For we have not an high priest which cannot be touched with the feeling of our infirmities; but was in all points tempted like as we are, yet without sin.", "question": "Hebrews 4: 14-15"}, {"answer": "9 And being made perfect, he became the author of eternal salvation unto all them that obey him;", "question": "Hebrews 5: 9"}, {"answer": "4 O how foolish, and how vain, and how evil, and devilish, and how quick to do iniquity, and how slow to do good, are the children of men; yea, how quick to hearken unto the words of the evil one, and to set their hearts upon the vain things of the world!\r\n5 Yea, how quick to be lifted up in pride; yea, how quick to boast, and do all manner of that which is iniquity; and how slow are they to remember the Lord their God, and to give ear unto his counsels, yea, how slow to walk in wisdom\u2019s paths!", "question": "Helaman 12: 4-5"}, {"answer": "4 Behold, my soul delighteth in proving unto my people the truth of the coming of Christ; for, for this end hath the law of Moses been given; and all things which have been given of God from the beginning of the world, unto man, are the typifying of him.", "question": "2 Nephi 11: 4"}, {"answer": "29 Let every man be diligent in all things. And the idler shall not have place in the church, except he repent and mend his ways.", "question": "D&C 75: 29"}, {"answer": "2 Be not rash with thy mouth, and let not thine heart be hasty to utter any thing before God: for God is in heaven, and thou upon earth: therefore let thy words be few.", "question": "Ecclesiastes 5: 2"}, {"answer": "34 When he slew them, then they sought him: and they returned and enquired early after God.", "question": "Psalms 78: 34"}, {"answer": "26 For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul?", "question": "Matthew 16: 26"}, {"answer": "34 O give thanks unto the Lord; for he is good; for his mercy endureth for ever.", "question": "1 Chronicles 16: 34"}, {"answer": "24 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, reconcile yourselves to the will of God, and not to the will of the devil and the flesh; and remember, after ye are reconciled unto God, that it is only in and through the grace of God that ye are saved.", "question": "2 Nephi 10: 24"}, {"answer": "5 Therefore, thrust in your sickle with all your soul, and your sins are forgiven you, and you shall be laden with sheaves upon your back, for the laborer is worthy of his hire. Wherefore, your family shall live.", "question": "D&C 31: 5"}, {"answer": "20 For I say unto you, That except your righteousness shall exceed the righteousness of the scribes and Pharisees, ye shall in no case enter into the kingdom of heaven.", "question": "Matthew 5: 20"}, {"answer": "40 And thus, if ye will not nourish the word, looking forward with an eye of faith to the fruit thereof, ye can never pluck of the fruit of the tree of life.", "question": "Alma 32: 40"}, {"answer": "36 Be ye therefore merciful, as your Father also is merciful.", "question": "Luke 6: 36"}, {"answer": "18 But, behold, the righteous, the saints of the Holy One of Israel, they who have believed in the Holy One of Israel, they who have endured the crosses of the world, and despised the shame of it, they shall inherit the kingdom of God, which was prepared for them from the foundation of the world, and their joy shall be full forever.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 18"}, {"answer": "5 Wherefore, be faithful; stand in the office which I have appointed unto you; succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.", "question": "D&C 81: 5"}, {"answer": "26 And every one that heareth these sayings of mine, and doeth them not, shall be likened unto a foolish man, which built his house upon the sand:\r\n27 And the rain descended, and the floods came, and the winds blew, and beat upon that house; and it fell: and great was the fall of it.", "question": "Matthew 7: 26-27"}, {"answer": "25 And whosoever shall believe in my name, doubting nothing, unto him will I confirm all my words, even unto the ends of the earth.", "question": "Mormon 9: 25"}, {"answer": "5 And God saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every imagination of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually.", "question": "Genesis 6: 5"}, {"answer": "12 Yea, and how is it that ye have forgotten that the Lord is able to do all things according to his will, for the children of men, if it so be that they exercise faith in him? Wherefore, let us be faithful to him.", "question": "1 Nephi 7: 12"}, {"answer": "34 Behold, there are many called, but few are chosen. And why are they not chosen?\r\n35 Because their hearts are set so much upon the things of this world, and aspire to the honors of men, that they do not learn this one lesson\u2014\r\n36 That the rights of the priesthood are inseparably connected with the powers of heaven, and that the powers of heaven cannot be controlled nor handled only upon the principles of righteousness.\r\n37 That they may be conferred upon us, it is true; but when we undertake to cover our sins, or to gratify our pride, our vain ambition, or to exercise control or dominion or compulsion upon the souls of the children of men, in any degree of unrighteousness, behold, the heavens withdraw themselves; the Spirit of the Lord is grieved; and when it is withdrawn, Amen to the priesthood or the authority of that man.\r\n38 Behold, ere he is aware, he is left unto himself, to kick against the pricks, to persecute the saints, and to fight against God.", "question": "D&C 121: 34-38"}, {"answer": "12 And whosoever shall exalt himself shall be abased; and he that shall humble himself shall be exalted.", "question": "Matthew 23: 12"}, {"answer": "14 Wherefore, we shall have a perfect knowledge of all our guilt, and our uncleanness, and our nakedness; and the righteous shall have a perfect knowledge of their enjoyment, and their righteousness, being clothed with purity, yea, even with the robe of righteousness.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 14"}, {"answer": "33 For my Spirit is sent forth into the world to enlighten the humble and contrite, and to the condemnation of the ungodly.", "question": "D&C 136: 33"}, {"answer": "3 Again, ye have heard that it hath been said by them of old time, Thou shalt not forswear thyself, but shalt perform unto the Lord thine oaths:\r\n34 But I say unto you, Swear not at all; neither by heaven; for it is God\u2019s throne:\r\n35 Nor by the earth; for it is his footstool: neither by Jerusalem; for it is the city of the great King.\r\n36 Neither shalt thou swear by thy head, because thou canst not make one hair white or black.\r\n37 But let your communication be, Yea, yea; Nay, nay: for whatsoever is more than these cometh of evil.", "question": "Matthew 5: 33-37"}, {"answer": "24 Cease drunkenness; and let your words tend to edifying one another.", "question": "D&C 136: 24"}, {"answer": "11 Nevertheless neither is the man without the woman, neither the woman without the man, in the Lord.", "question": "1 Corinthians 11: 11"}, {"answer": "6 Nevertheless the children of God were commanded that they should gather themselves together oft, and join in fasting and mighty prayer in behalf of the welfare of the souls of those who knew not God.", "question": "Alma 6: 6"}, {"answer": "2 By whom also we have access by faith into this grace wherein we stand, and rejoice in hope of the glory of God.", "question": "Romans 5: 2"}, {"answer": "35 And a portion of that Spirit dwelleth in me, which giveth me knowledge, and also power according to my faith and desires which are in God.", "question": "Alma 18: 35"}, {"answer": "25 Therefore I say unto you, Take no thought for your life, what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink; nor yet for your body, what ye shall put on. Is not the life more than meat, and the body than raiment?", "question": "Matthew 6: 25"}, {"answer": "16 Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen you, and ordained you, that ye should go and bring forth fruit, and that your fruit should remain: that whatsoever ye shall ask of the Father in my name, he may give it you.", "question": "John 15: 16"}, {"answer": "7 Therefore, strengthen your brethren in all your conversation, in all your prayers, in all your exhortations, and in all your doings.", "question": "D&C 108: 7"}, {"answer": "20 Behold, I stand at the door, and knock: if any man hear my voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup with him, and he with me.", "question": "Revelation 3: 20"}, {"answer": "7 There is that maketh himself rich, yet hath nothing: there is that maketh himself poor, yet hath great riches.", "question": "Proverbs 13: 7"}, {"answer": "22 And now, behold, I say unto you, and I would that ye should remember, that God is merciful unto all who believe on his name; therefore he desireth, in the first place, that ye should believe, yea, even on his word.", "question": "Alma 32: 22"}, {"answer": "42 Thou shalt not be idle; for he that is idle shall not eat the bread nor wear the garments of the laborer.", "question": "D&C 42: 42"}, {"answer": "4 Whosoever therefore shall humble himself as this little child, the same is greatest in the kingdom of heaven.", "question": "Matthew 18: 4"}, {"answer": "13 To some it is given by the Holy Ghost to know that Jesus Christ is the Son of God, and that he was crucified for the sins of the world.", "question": "D&C 46: 13"}, {"answer": "5 Not by works of righteousness which we have done, but according to his mercy he saved us, by the washing of regeneration, and renewing of the Holy Ghost;\r\n6 Which he shed on us abundantly through Jesus Christ our Saviour;", "question": "Titus 3: 5-6"}, {"answer": "27 Behold, this I have given unto you as a parable, and it is even as I am. I say unto you, be one; and if ye are not one ye are not mine.", "question": "D&C 38: 27"}, {"answer": "31 It hath been said, Whosoever shall put away his wife, let him give her a writing of divorcement:\r\n32 But I say unto you, That whosoever shall put away his wife, saving for the cause of fornication, causeth her to commit adultery: and whosoever shall marry her that is divorced committeth adultery.", "question": "Matthew 5: 31-32"}, {"answer": "6 But blessed are they who have kept the covenant and observed the commandment, for they shall obtain mercy.", "question": "D&C 54: 6"}, {"answer": "23 For behold, I am God; and I am a God of miracles; and I will show unto the world that I am the same yesterday, today, and forever; and I work not among the children of men save it be according to their faith.", "question": "2 Nephi 27: 23"}, {"answer": "20 And to others it is given to have faith to heal.", "question": "D&C 46: 20"}, {"answer": "16 For where envying and strife is, there is confusion and every evil work.", "question": "James 3: 16"}, {"answer": "32 But I have prayed for thee, that thy faith fail not: and when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.", "question": "Luke 22: 32"}, {"answer": "31 But the laborer in Zion shall labor for Zion; for if they labor for money they shall perish.", "question": "2 Nephi 26: 31"}, {"answer": "27 And whosoever doth not bear his cross, and come after me, cannot be my disciple.", "question": "Luke 14: 27"}, {"answer": "12 For thou, Lord, wilt bless the righteous; with favour wilt thou compass him as with a shield.", "question": "Psalms 5: 12"}, {"answer": "26 Behold the fowls of the air: for they sow not, neither do they reap, nor gather into barns; yet your heavenly Father feedeth them. Are ye not much better than they?\r\n27 Which of you by taking thought can add one cubit unto his stature?", "question": "Matthew 6: 26-27"}, {"answer": "10 And again, verily I say unto you that it is your privilege, and a promise I give unto you that have been ordained unto this ministry, that inasmuch as you strip yourselves from jealousies and fears, and humble yourselves before me, for ye are not sufficiently humble, the veil shall be rent and you shall see me and know that I am\u2014not with the carnal neither natural mind, but with the spiritual.", "question": "D&C 67: 10"}, {"answer": "25 Jesus said unto her, I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:", "question": "John 11: 25"}, {"answer": "8 And no one can assist in this work except he shall be humble and full of love, having faith, hope, and charity, being temperate in all things, whatsoever shall be entrusted to his care.", "question": "D&C 12: 8"}, {"answer": "16 Let us therefore come boldly unto the throne of grace, that we may obtain mercy, and find grace to help in time of need.", "question": "Hebrews 4: 16"}, {"answer": "19 Little children cannot repent; wherefore, it is awful wickedness to deny the pure mercies of God unto them, for they are all alive in him because of his mercy.\r\n20 And he that saith that little children need baptism denieth the mercies of Christ, and setteth at naught the atonement of him and the power of his redemption.", "question": "Moroni 8: 19-20"}, {"answer": "18 And the fruit of righteousness is sown in peace of them that make peace.", "question": "James 3: 18"}, {"answer": "11 But we believe that through the grace of the Lord Jesus Christ we shall be saved, even as they.", "question": "Acts 15: 11"}, {"answer": "14 To others it is given to believe on their words, that they also might have eternal life if they continue faithful.", "question": "D&C 46: 14"}, {"answer": "18 For Christ also hath once suffered for sins, the just for the unjust, that he might bring us to God, being put to death in the flesh, but quickened by the Spirit:", "question": "1 Peter 3: 18"}, {"answer": "11 Do ye not remember the things which the Lord hath said?\u2014If ye will not harden your hearts, and ask me in faith, believing that ye shall receive, with diligence in keeping my commandments, surely these things shall be made known unto you.", "question": "1 Nephi 15: 11"}, {"answer": "29 And he that sent me is with me: the Father hath not left me alone; for I do always those things that please him.", "question": "John 8: 29"}, {"answer": "12 Having gone according to their own carnal wills and desires; having never called upon the Lord while the arms of mercy were extended towards them; for the arms of mercy were extended towards them, and they would not; they being warned of their iniquities and yet they would not depart from them; and they were commanded to repent and yet they would not repent.", "question": "Mosiah 16: 12"}, {"answer": "13 He that covereth his sins shall not prosper: but whoso confesseth and forsaketh them shall have mercy.", "question": "Proverbs 28: 13"}, {"answer": "10 If thou faint in the day of adversity, thy strength is small.", "question": "Proverbs 24: 10"}, {"answer": "23 Woe unto you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! for ye pay tithe of mint and anise and cummin, and have omitted the weightier matters of the law, judgment, mercy, and faith: these ought ye to have done, and not to leave the other undone.", "question": "Matthew 23: 23"}, {"answer": "19 And again, to some it is given to have faith to be healed;", "question": "D&C 46: 19"}, {"answer": "23 Jesus answered and said unto him, If a man love me, he will keep my words: and my Father will love him, and we will come unto him, and make our abode with him.", "question": "John 14: 23"}, {"answer": "21 And again, to some is given the working of miracles;", "question": "D&C 46: 21"}, {"answer": "15 For thus saith the high and lofty One that inhabiteth eternity, whose name is Holy; I dwell in the high and holy place, with him also that is of a contrite and humble spirit, to revive the spirit of the humble, and to revive the heart of the contrite ones.", "question": "Isaiah 57: 15"}, {"answer": "13 And that he manifesteth himself unto all those who believe in him, by the power of the Holy Ghost; yea, unto every nation, kindred, tongue, and people, working mighty miracles, signs, and wonders, among the children of men according to their faith.", "question": "2 Nephi 26: 13"}, {"answer": "22 And to others it is given to prophesy;", "question": "D&C 46: 22"}, {"answer": "27 And they did impart of their substance, every man according to that which he had, to the poor, and the needy, and the sick, and the afflicted; and they did not wear costly apparel, yet they were neat and comely.", "question": "Alma 1: 27"}, {"answer": "16 Ye shall know them by their fruits. Do men gather grapes of thorns, or figs of thistles?\r\n17 Even so every good tree bringeth forth good fruit; but a corrupt tree bringeth forth evil fruit.\r\n18 A good tree cannot bring forth evil fruit, neither can a corrupt tree bring forth good fruit.", "question": "Matthew 7: 16-18"}, {"answer": "16 But Jesus called them unto him, and said, Suffer little children to come unto me, and forbid them not: for of such is the kingdom of God.", "question": "Luke 18: 16"}, {"answer": "48 And again, it shall come to pass that he that hath faith in me to be healed, and is not appointed unto death, shall be healed.", "question": "D&C 42: 48"}, {"answer": "24 There is that scattereth, and yet increaseth; and there is that withholdeth more than is meet, but it tendeth to poverty.", "question": "Proverbs 11: 24"}, {"answer": "43 When the unclean spirit is gone out of a man, he walketh through dry places, seeking rest, and findeth none.\r\n44 Then he saith, I will return into my house from whence I came out; and when he is come, he findeth it empty, swept, and garnished.\r\n45 Then goeth he, and taketh with himself seven other spirits more wicked than himself, and they enter in and dwell there: and the last state of that man is worse than the first. Even so shall it be also unto this wicked generation.", "question": "Matthew 12: 43-45"}, {"answer": "1 The Spirit of the Lord God is upon me; because the Lord hath anointed me to preach good tidings unto the meek; he hath sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to them that are bound;", "question": "Isaiah 61: 1"}, {"answer": "25 And if they be evil they are consigned to an awful view of their own guilt and abominations, which doth cause them to shrink from the presence of the Lord into a state of misery and endless torment, from whence they can no more return; therefore they have drunk damnation to their own souls.", "question": "Mosiah 3: 25"}, {"answer": "17 And again, verily I say unto you, to some is given, by the Spirit of God, the word of wisdom.", "question": "D&C 46: 17"}, {"answer": "18 Poverty and shame shall be to him that refuseth instruction: but he that regardeth reproof shall be honoured.", "question": "Proverbs 13: 18"}, {"answer": "17 But the wisdom that is from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, and easy to be intreated, full of mercy and good fruits, without partiality, and without hypocrisy.", "question": "James 3: 17"}, {"answer": "31 My people must be tried in all things, that they may be prepared to receive the glory that I have for them, even the glory of Zion; and he that will not bear chastisement is not worthy of my kingdom.", "question": "D&C 136: 31"}, {"answer": "1 Verily, thus saith the Lord unto you whom I love, and whom I love I also chasten that their sins may be forgiven, for with the chastisement I prepare a way for their deliverance in all things out of temptation, and I have loved you\u2014", "question": "D&C 95: 1"}, {"answer": "23 That the fulness of my gospel might be proclaimed by the weak and the simple unto the ends of the world, and before kings and rulers.", "question": "D&C 1: 23"}, {"answer": "3 Every moving thing that liveth shall be meat for you; even as the green herb have I given you all things.", "question": "Genesis 9: 6"}, {"answer": "41 Therefore, if a man bringeth forth good works he hearkeneth unto the voice of the good shepherd, and he doth follow him; but whosoever bringeth forth evil works, the same becometh a child of the devil, for he hearkeneth unto his voice, and doth follow him.", "question": "Alma 5: 41"}, {"answer": "19 By which also he went and preached unto the spirits in prison;\r\n20 Which sometime were disobedient, when once the longsuffering of God waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was a preparing, wherein few, that is, eight souls were saved by water.", "question": "1 Peter 3: 19-20"}, {"answer": "4 Their idols are silver and gold, the work of men's hands.", "question": "Psalms 115: 4"}, {"answer": "18 To another is given the word of knowledge, that all may be taught to be wise and to have knowledge.", "question": "D&C 46: 18"}, {"answer": "51 I am the living bread which came down from heaven: if any man eat of this bread, he shall live for ever: and the bread that I will give is my flesh, which I will give for the life of the world.", "question": "John 6: 51"}, {"answer": "26 And ye have murmured because he hath been plain unto you. Ye say that he hath used sharpness; ye say that he hath been angry with you; but behold, his sharpness was the sharpness of the power of the word of God, which was in him; and that which ye call anger was the truth, according to that which is in God, which he could not restrain, manifesting boldly concerning your iniquities.", "question": "2 Nephi 1: 26"}, {"answer": "7 And thou shalt teach them diligently unto thy children, and shalt talk of them when thou sittest in thine house, and when thou walkest by the way, and when thou liest down, and when thou risest up.", "question": "Deuteronomy 6: 7"}, {"answer": "9 Nevertheless, thou hast seen great sorrow, for thou hast rejected me many times because of pride and the cares of the world.", "question": "D&C 39: 9"}, {"answer": "9 Now my son, I would that ye should repent and forsake your sins, and go no more after the lusts of your eyes, but cross yourself in all these things; for except ye do this ye can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God. Oh, remember, and take it upon you, and cross yourself in these things.", "question": "Alma 39: 9"}, {"answer": "11 For all have not every gift given unto them; for there are many gifts, and to every man is given a gift by the Spirit of God.\r\n12 To some is given one, and to some is given another, that all may be profited thereby.", "question": "D&C 46: 11-12"}, {"answer": "21 Beloved, if our heart condemn us not, then have we confidence toward God.", "question": "1 John 3: 21"}, {"answer": "6 Nevertheless, I did harden my heart, for I was called many times and I would not hear; therefore I knew concerning these things, yet I would not know; therefore I went on rebelling against God, in the wickedness of my heart, even until the fourth day of this seventh month, which is in the tenth year of the reign of the judges.", "question": "Alma 10: 6"}, {"answer": "16 They seek not the Lord to establish his righteousness, but every man walketh in his own way, and after the image of his own god, whose image is in the likeness of the world, and whose substance is that of an idol, which waxeth old and shall perish in Babylon, even Babylon the great, which shall fall.", "question": "D&C 1: 16"}, {"answer": "8 Thus we see how quick the children of men do forget the Lord their God, yea, how quick to do iniquity, and to be led away by the evil one.", "question": "Alma 46: 8"}, {"answer": "28 And why take ye thought for raiment? Consider the lilies of the field, how they grow; they toil not, neither do they spin:\r\n29 And yet I say unto you, That even Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these.\r\n30 Wherefore, if God so clothe the grass of the field, which to day is, and to morrow is cast into the oven, shall he not much more clothe you, O ye of little faith?", "question": "Matthew 6: 28-30"}, {"answer": "16 And thus mercy can satisfy the demands of justice, and encircles them in the arms of safety, while he that exercises no faith unto repentance is exposed to the whole law of the demands of justice; therefore only unto him that has faith unto repentance is brought about the great and eternal plan of redemption.", "question": "Alma 34: 16"}, {"answer": "14 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, beheld the power of the Lamb of God, that it descended upon the saints of the church of the Lamb, and upon the covenant people of the Lord, who were scattered upon all the face of the earth; and they were armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory.", "question": "1 Nephi 14: 14"}, {"answer": "16 I say unto you, can you imagine to yourselves that ye hear the voice of the Lord, saying unto you, in that day: Come unto me ye blessed, for behold, your works have been the works of righteousness upon the face of the earth?\r\n17 Or do ye imagine to yourselves that ye can lie unto the Lord in that day, and say\u2014Lord, our works have been righteous works upon the face of the earth\u2014and that he will save you?", "question": "Alma 5: 16-17"}, {"answer": "27 Have ye walked, keeping yourselves blameless before God? Could ye say, if ye were called to die at this time, within yourselves, that ye have been sufficiently humble? That your garments have been cleansed and made white through the blood of Christ, who will come to redeem his people from their sins?", "question": "Alma 5: 27"}, {"answer": "38 And he that taketh not his cross, and followeth after me, is not worthy of me.", "question": "Matthew 10: 38"}, {"answer": "9 Or what man is there of you, whom if his son ask bread, will he give him a stone?\r\n10 Or if he ask a fish, will he give him a serpent?\r\n11 If ye then, being evil, know how to give good gifts unto your children, how much more shall your Father which is in heaven give good things to them that ask him?", "question": "Matthew 7: 9-11"}, {"answer": "20 The power and authority of the lesser, or Aaronic Priesthood, is to hold the keys of the ministering of angels, and to administer in outward ordinances, the letter of the gospel, the baptism of repentance for the remission of sins, agreeable to the covenants and commandments.", "question": "D&C 107: 20"}, {"answer": "8 Wherefore, beware lest ye are deceived; and that ye may not be deceived seek ye earnestly the best gifts, always remembering for what they are given;", "question": "D&C 46: 8"}, {"answer": "18 For I reckon that the sufferings of this present time are not worthy to be compared with the glory which shall be revealed in us.", "question": "Romans 8: 18"}, {"answer": "10 And again, verily I say unto you, I would that ye should always remember, and always retain in your minds what those gifts are, that are given unto the church.", "question": "D&C 46: 10"}, {"answer": "24 And again, it is given to some to speak with tongues;", "question": "D&C 46: 24"}, {"answer": "5 A fool despiseth his father\u2019s instruction: but he that regardeth reproof is prudent.", "question": "Proverbs 15: 5"}, {"answer": "10 Correction is grievous unto him that forsaketh the way: and he that hateth reproof shall die.", "question": "Proverbs 15: 10"}, {"answer": "46 Prepare your souls for that glorious day when justice shall be administered unto the righteous, even the day of judgment, that ye may not shrink with awful fear; that ye may not remember your awful guilt in perfectness, and be constrained to exclaim: Holy, holy are thy judgments, O Lord God Almighty\u2014but I know my guilt; I transgressed thy law, and my transgressions are mine; and the devil hath obtained me, that I am a prey to his awful misery.", "question": "2 Nephi 9: 46"}, {"answer": "10 Fear thou not; for I am with thee: be not dismayed; for I am thy God: I will strengthen thee; yea, I will help thee; yea, I will uphold thee with the right hand of my righteousness.", "question": "Isaiah 41: 10"}, {"answer": "4 For after much tribulation come the blessings. Wherefore the day cometh that ye shall be crowned with much glory; the hour is not yet, but is nigh at hand.", "question": "D&C 58: 4"}, {"answer": "25 And to another is given the interpretation of tongues.", "question": "D&C 46: 25"}, {"answer": "31 Therefore take no thought, saying, What shall we eat? or, What shall we drink? or, Wherewithal shall we be clothed?\r\n32 (For after all these things do the Gentiles seek:) for your heavenly Father knoweth that ye have need of all these things.", "question": "Matthew 6: 31-32"}, {"answer": "31 And the Lord said, Simon, Simon, behold, Satan hath desired to have you, that he may sift you as wheat:", "question": "Luke 22: 31"}, {"answer": "28 And it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out my spirit upon all flesh; and your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, your old men shall dream dreams, your young men shall see visions:", "question": "Joel 2: 28"}, {"answer": "22 And now, behold, if Adam had not transgressed he would not have fallen, but he would have remained in the garden of Eden. And all things which were created must have remained in the same state in which they were after they were created; and they must have remained forever, and had no end.\r\n23 And they would have had no children; wherefore they would have remained in a state of innocence, having no joy, for they knew no misery; doing no good, for they knew no sin.", "question": "2 Nephi 2: 22-23"}, {"answer": "38 O ye pollutions, ye hypocrites, ye teachers, who sell yourselves for that which will canker, why have ye polluted the holy church of God? Why are ye ashamed to take upon you the name of Christ? Why do ye not think that greater is the value of an endless happiness than that misery which never dies\u2014because of the praise of the world?", "question": "Mormon 8: 38"}, {"answer": "23 And to others the discerning of spirits.", "question": "D&C 46: 23"}, {"answer": "27 And again Alma commanded that the people of the church should impart of their substance, every one according to that which he had; if he have more abundantly he should impart more abundantly; and of him that had but little, but little should be required; and to him that had not should be given.", "question": "Mosiah 18: 27"}, {"answer": "29 For behold, the Lord hath said: I will not succor my people in the day of their transgression; but I will hedge up their ways that they prosper not; and their doings shall be as a stumbling block before them.", "question": "Mosiah 7: 29"}, {"answer": "15 And again, to some it is given by the Holy Ghost to know the differences of administration, as it will be pleasing unto the same Lord, according as the Lord will, suiting his mercies according to the conditions of the children of men.", "question": "D&C 46: 15"}, {"answer": "16 And again, it is given by the Holy Ghost to some to know the diversities of operations, whether they be of God, that the manifestations of the Spirit may be given to every man to profit withal.", "question": "D&C 46: 16"}, {"answer": "56 Even before they were born, they, with many others, received their first lessons in the world of spirits and were prepared to come forth in the due time of the Lord to labor in his vineyard for the salvation of the souls of men.", "question": "D&C 138: 56"}, {"answer": "9 Verily I say unto you, notwithstanding their sins, my bowels are filled with compassion towards them. I will not utterly cast them off; and in the day of wrath I will remember mercy.", "question": "D&C 101: 9"}, {"answer": "33 But seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.", "question": "Matthew 6: 33"}, {"answer": "66 These things remain to overcome through patience, that such may receive a more exceeding and eternal weight of glory, otherwise, a greater condemnation. Amen.", "question": "D&C 63: 66"}, {"answer": "15 And inasmuch as my people build a house unto me in the name of the Lord, and do not suffer any unclean thing to come into it, that it be not defiled, my glory shall rest upon it;\r\n16 Yea, and my presence shall be there, for I will come into it, and all the pure in heart that shall come into it shall see God.", "question": "D&C 97: 15-16"}, {"answer": "2 Set your affection on things above, not on things on the earth.", "question": "Colossians 3: 2"}, {"answer": "17 For our light affliction, which is but for a moment, worketh for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory;", "question": "2 Corinthians 4: 17"}, {"answer": "26 And all these gifts come from God, for the benefit of the children of God.", "question": "D&C 46: 26"}, {"answer": "22 And again I say unto you, if ye observe to do whatsoever I command you, I, the Lord, will turn away all wrath and indignation from you, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against you.", "question": "D&C 98: 22"}, {"answer": "3 And not only so, but we glory in tribulations also: knowing that tribulation worketh patience;", "question": "Romans 5: 3"}, {"answer": "12 Then said he also to him that bade him, When thou makest a dinner or a supper, call not thy friends, nor thy brethren, neither thy kinsmen, nor thy rich neighbours; lest they also bid thee again, and a recompence be made thee.\r\n13 But when thou makest a feast, call the poor, the maimed, the lame, the blind:\r\n14 And thou shalt be blessed; for they cannot recompense thee: for thou shalt be recompensed at the resurrection of the just.", "question": "Luke 14: 12-14"}, {"answer": "32 Nevertheless, ye shall not cast him out of your synagogues, or your places of worship, for unto such shall ye continue to minister; for ye know not but what they will return and repent, and come unto me with full purpose of heart, and I shall heal them; and ye shall be the means of bringing salvation unto them.", "question": "3 Nephi 18: 32"}, {"answer": "3 And Aminadi was a descendant of Nephi, who was the son of Lehi, who came out of the land of Jerusalem, who was a descendant of Manasseh, who was the son of Joseph who was sold into Egypt by the hands of his brethren.", "question": "Alma 10: 3"}, {"answer": "27 And unto the bishop of the church, and unto such as God shall appoint and ordain to watch over the church and to be elders unto the church, are to have it given unto them to discern all those gifts lest there shall be any among you professing and yet be not of God.", "question": "D&C 46: 27"}, {"answer": "3 Strengthen ye the weak hands, and confirm the feeble knees.", "question": "Isaiah 35: 3"}, {"answer": "22 For he who is not able to abide the law of a celestial kingdom cannot abide a celestial glory.", "question": "D&C 88: 22"}, {"answer": "21 Verily I say unto you, that I, the Lord, will chasten them and will do whatsoever I list, if they do not repent and observe all things whatsoever I have said unto them.", "question": "D&C 98: 21"}, {"answer": "20 And the Gentiles are lifted up in the pride of their eyes, and have stumbled, because of the greatness of their stumbling block, that they have built up many churches; nevertheless, they put down the power and miracles of God, and preach up unto themselves their own wisdom and their own learning, that they may get gain and grind upon the face of the poor.\r\n21 And there are many churches built up which cause envyings, and strifes, and malice.", "question": "2 Nephi 26: 20-21"}, {"answer": "8 The silver is mine, and the gold is mine, saith the Lord of hosts.", "question": "Haggai 2: 8"}, {"answer": "17 Now I beseech you, brethren, mark them which cause divisions and offences contrary to the doctrine which ye have learned; and avoid them.\r\n18 For they that are such serve not our Lord Jesus Christ, but their own belly; and by good words and fair speeches deceive the hearts of the simple.", "question": "Romans 16: 17-18"}, {"answer": "10 And he said unto me: Behold there are save two churches only; the one is the church of the Lamb of God, and the other is the church of the devil; wherefore, whoso belongeth not to the church of the Lamb of God belongeth to that great church, which is the mother of abominations; and she is the whore of all the earth.", "question": "1 Nephi 14: 10"}, {"answer": "16 Wherefore, he that fighteth against Zion, both Jew and Gentile, both bond and free, both male and female, shall perish; for they are they who are the whore of all the earth; for they who are not for me are against me, saith our God.", "question": "2 Nephi 10: 16"}, {"answer": "1 For this Melchisedec, king of Salem, priest of the most high God, who met Abraham returning from the slaughter of the kings, and blessed him;\r\n2 To whom also Abraham gave a tenth part of all; first being by interpretation King of righteousness, and after that also King of Salem, which is, King of peace;", "question": "Hebrews 7: 1-2"}, {"answer": "33 For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods of which I have spoken, and the magnifying their calling, are sanctified by the Spirit unto the renewing of their bodies.\r\n34 They become the sons of Moses and of Aaron and the seed of Abraham, and the church and kingdom, and the elect of God.\r\n35 And also all they who receive this priesthood receive me, saith the Lord;\r\n36 For he that receiveth my servants receiveth me;\r\n37 And he that receiveth me receiveth my Father;\r\n38 And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my Father\u2019s kingdom; therefore all that my Father hath shall be given unto him.\r\n39 And this is according to the oath and covenant which belongeth to the priesthood.", "question": "D&C 84: 33-39"}, {"answer": "32 He that spared not his own Son, but delivered him up for us all, how shall he not with him also freely give us all things?", "question": "Romans 8: 32"}, {"answer": "7 And ye are called to bring to pass the gathering of mine elect; for mine elect hear my voice and harden not their hearts;", "question": "D&C 29: 7"}, {"answer": "5 That you may be equal in the bonds of heavenly things, yea, and earthly things also, for the obtaining of heavenly things.\r\n6 For if ye are not equal in earthly things ye cannot be equal in obtaining heavenly things;", "question": "D&C 78: 5-6"}, {"answer": "12 And he answered: Yea, Lord, I know that thou speakest the truth, for thou art a God of truth, and canst not lie.", "question": "Ether 3: 12"}, {"answer": "7 But ye are commanded in all things to ask of God, who giveth liberally; and that which the Spirit testifies unto you even so I would that ye should do in all holiness of heart, walking uprightly before me, considering the end of your salvation, doing all things with prayer and thanksgiving, that ye may not be seduced by evil spirits, or doctrines of devils, or the commandments of men; for some are of men, and others of devils.", "question": "D&C 46: 7"}, {"answer": "30 And it came to pass when they heard this voice, and beheld that it was not a voice of thunder, neither was it a voice of a great tumultuous noise, but behold, it was a still voice of perfect mildness, as if it had been a whisper, and it did pierce even to the very soul\u2014", "question": "Helaman 5: 30"}, {"answer": "21 And wo be unto man that sheddeth blood or that wasteth flesh and hath no need.", "question": "D&C 49: 21"}, {"answer": "14 Nevertheless, in your temporal things you shall be equal, and this not grudgingly, otherwise the abundance of the manifestations of the Spirit shall be withheld.", "question": "D&C 70: 14"}, {"answer": "20 Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that receiveth whomsoever I send receiveth me; and he that receiveth me receiveth him that sent me.", "question": "John 13: 20"}, {"answer": "11 And if thou wilt inquire, thou shalt know mysteries which are great and marvelous; therefore thou shalt exercise thy gift, that thou mayest find out mysteries, that thou mayest bring many to the knowledge of the truth, yea, convince them of the error of their ways.", "question": "D&C 6: 11"}, {"answer": "30 He that is not with me is against me; and he that gathereth not with me scattereth abroad.", "question": "Matthew 12: 30"}, {"answer": "20 But it is not given that one man should possess that which is above another, wherefore the world lieth in sin.", "question": "D&C 49: 20"}, {"answer": "30 And thus we can plainly discern, that after a people have been once enlightened by the Spirit of God, and have had great knowledge of things pertaining to righteousness, and then have fallen away into sin and transgression, they become more hardened, and thus their state becomes worse than though they had never known these things.", "question": "Alma 24: 30"}, {"answer": "15 Meditate upon these things; give thyself wholly to them; that thy profiting may appear to all.", "question": "1 Timothy 4: 15"}, {"answer": "9 Jesus saith unto him, Have I been so long time with you, and yet hast thou not known me, Philip? he that hath seen me hath seen the Father; and how sayest thou then, Shew us the Father?", "question": "John 14: 9"}, {"answer": "29 And if ye be Christ\u2019s, then are ye Abraham\u2019s seed, and heirs according to the promise.", "question": "Galatians 3: 29"}, {"answer": "2 And he that will not take up his cross and follow me, and keep my commandments, the same shall not be saved.", "question": "D&C 56: 2"}, {"answer": "12 Yea, flesh also of beasts and of the fowls of the air, I, the Lord, have ordained for the use of man with thanksgiving; nevertheless they are to be used sparingly;\r\n13 And it is pleasing unto me that they should not be used, only in times of winter, or of cold, or famine.", "question": "D&C 89: 12-13"}, {"answer": "7 And if thou shouldst be cast into the pit, or into the hands of murderers, and the sentence of death passed upon thee; if thou be cast into the deep; if the billowing surge conspire against thee; if fierce winds become thine enemy; if the heavens gather blackness, and all the elements combine to hedge up the way; and above all, if the very jaws of hell shall gape open the mouth wide after thee, know thou, my son, that all these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good.\r\n8 The Son of Man hath descended below them all. Art thou greater than he?", "question": "D&C 122: 7-8"}, {"answer": "10 And I will bless them through thy name; for as many as receive this Gospel shall be called after thy name, and shall be accounted thy seed, and shall rise up and bless thee, as their father;", "question": "Abraham 2: 10"}, {"answer": "20 Let him know, that he which converteth the sinner from the error of his way shall save a soul from death, and shall hide a multitude of sins.", "question": "James 5: 20"}, {"answer": "20 And it pleaseth God that he hath given all these things unto man; for unto this end were they made to be used, with judgment, not to excess, neither by extortion.", "question": "D&C 59: 20"}, {"answer": "9  Therefore, hold on thy way, and the priesthood shall remain with thee; for their bounds are set, they cannot pass. Thy days are known, and thy years shall not be numbered less; therefore, fear not what man can do, for God shall be with you forever and ever.", "question": "D&C 122: 9"}, {"answer": "10  But he said unto her, Thou speakest as one of the foolish women speaketh. What? shall we receive good at the hand of God, and shall we not receive evil? In all this did not Job sin with his lips.", "question": "Job 2: 10"}, {"answer": "10  For they verily for a few days chastened us after their own pleasure; but he for our profit, that we might be partakers of his holiness.", "question": "Hebrews 12: 10"}, {"answer": "16  Take heed unto thyself, and unto the doctrine; continue in them: for in doing this thou shalt both save thyself, and them that hear thee.", "question": "1 Timothy 4: 16"}, {"answer": "11 Now no chastening for the present seemeth to be joyous, but grievous: nevertheless afterward it yieldeth the peaceable fruit of righteousness unto them which are exercised thereby.", "question": "Hebrews 12: 11"}, {"answer": "9 And now Alma began to expound these things unto him, saying: It is given unto many to know the mysteries of God; nevertheless they are laid under a strict command that they shall not impart only according to the portion of his word which he doth grant unto the children of men, according to the heed and diligence which they give unto him.", "question": "Alma 12: 9"}, {"answer": "10 Behold, I have refined thee, but not with silver; I have chosen thee in the furnace of affliction.", "question": "Isaiah 48: 10"}, {"answer": "7  And in that day that they shall exercise faith in me, saith the Lord, even as the brother of Jared did, that they may become sanctified in me, then will I manifest unto them the things which the brother of Jared saw, even to the unfolding unto them all my revelations, saith Jesus Christ, the Son of God, the Father of the heavens and of the earth, and all things that in them are.", "question": "Ether 4: 7"}, {"answer": "13 And if ye believe on his name ye will repent of all your sins, that thereby ye may have a remission of them through his merits.", "question": "Helaman 14: 13"}, {"answer": "25 For there is a time appointed for every man, according as his works shall be.", "question": "D&C 121: 25"}, {"answer": "2 For behold, I say unto you that as many of the Gentiles as will repent are the covenant people of the Lord; and as many of the Jews as will not repent shall be cast off; for the Lord covenanteth with none save it be with them that repent and believe in his Son, who is the Holy One of Israel.", "question": "2 Nephi 30: 2"}, {"answer": "6 For whom the Lord loveth he chasteneth, and scourgeth every son whom he receiveth.", "question": "Hebrews 12: 6"}, {"answer": "10 And if it so be that they will not believe these things, then shall the greater things be withheld from them, unto their condemnation.", "question": "3 Nephi 26: 10"}, {"answer": "40 For he that is not against us is on our part.", "question": "Mark 9: 40"}, {"answer": "5 Verily I say unto you all: Arise and shine forth, that thy light may be a standard for the nations;", "question": "D&C 115: 5"}, {"answer": "10 Now I beseech you, brethren, by the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, that ye all speak the same thing, and that there be no divisions among you; but that ye be perfectly joined together in the same mind and in the same judgment.", "question": "1 Corinthians 1: 10"}, {"answer": "6 Knowing this, that our old man is crucified with him, that the body of sin might be destroyed, that henceforth we should not serve sin.", "question": "Romans 6: 6"}, {"answer": "8 Finally, brethren, whatsoever things are true, whatsoever things are honest, whatsoever things are just, whatsoever things are pure, whatsoever things are lovely, whatsoever things are of good report; if there be any virtue, and if there be any praise, think on these things.", "question": "Philippians 4: 8"}, {"answer": "19 For this is thankworthy, if a man for conscience toward God endure grief, suffering wrongfully.\r\n20 For what glory is it, if, when ye be buffeted for your faults, ye shall take it patiently? but if, when ye do well, and suffer for it, ye take it patiently, this is acceptable with God.", "question": "1 Peter 2: 19-20"}, {"answer": "27 And inasmuch as they sinned they might be chastened, that they might repent;", "question": "D&C 1: 27"}, {"answer": "15 Therefore I command you to repent\u2014repent, lest I smite you by the rod of my mouth, and by my wrath, and by my anger, and your sufferings be sore\u2014how sore you know not, how exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.", "question": "D&C 19: 15"}, {"answer": "14 Therefore, be not afraid of your enemies, for I have decreed in my heart, saith the Lord, that I will prove you in all things, whether you will abide in my covenant, even unto death, that you may be found worthy.\r\n15 For if ye will not abide in my covenant ye are not worthy of me.", "question": "D&C 98: 14-15"}, {"answer": "8 And how be it my church save it be called in my name? For if a church be called in Moses\u2019 name then it be Moses\u2019 church; or if it be called in the name of a man then it be the church of a man; but if it be called in my name then it is my church, if it so be that they are built upon my gospel.", "question": "3 Nephi 27: 8"}, {"answer": "6 Yea, I say unto you, that the more part of them are doing this, and they are striving with unwearied diligence that they may bring the remainder of their brethren to the knowledge of the truth; therefore there are many who do add to their numbers daily.", "question": "Helaman 15: 6"}, {"answer": "19 As many as I love, I rebuke and chasten: be zealous therefore, and repent.", "question": "Revelation 3: 19"}, {"answer": "18 Yea, all things which come of the earth, in the season thereof, are made for the benefit and the use of man, both to please the eye and to gladden the heart;\r\n19 Yea, for food and for raiment, for taste and for smell, to strengthen the body and to enliven the soul.", "question": "D&C 59: 18-19"}, {"answer": "42 You have not taught your children light and truth, according to the commandments; and that wicked one hath power, as yet, over you, and this is the cause of your affliction.", "question": "D&C 93: 42"}, {"answer": "43 And now a commandment I give unto you\u2014if you will be delivered you shall set in order your own house, for there are many things that are not right in your house.", "question": "D&C 93: 43"}, {"answer": "4 For thus shall my church be called in the last days, even The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.", "question": "D&C 115: 4"}, {"answer": "29 Jesus saith unto him, Thomas, because thou hast seen me, thou hast believed: blessed are they that have not seen, and yet have believed.", "question": "John 20: 29"}, {"answer": "8 For behold, the Lord doth grant unto all nations, of their own nation and tongue, to teach his word, yea, in wisdom, all that he seeth fit that they should have; therefore we see that the Lord doth counsel in wisdom, according to that which is just and true.", "question": "Alma 29: 8"}, {"answer": "5 (For if a man know not how to rule his own house, how shall he take care of the church of God?)", "question": "1 Timothy 3: 5"}, {"answer": "32 Yea, come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and deny yourselves of all ungodliness; and if ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness, and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ; and if by the grace of God ye are perfect in Christ, ye can in nowise deny the power of God.", "question": "Moroni 10: 32"}, {"answer": "13 For I have told him that I will judge his house for ever for the iniquity which he knoweth; because his sons made themselves vile, and he restrained them not.", "question": "1 Samuel 3: 13"}, {"answer": "26 And now, my beloved brethren, I would that ye should come unto Christ, who is the Holy One of Israel, and partake of his salvation, and the power of his redemption. Yea, come unto him, and offer your whole souls as an offering unto him, and continue in fasting and praying, and endure to the end; and as the Lord liveth ye will be saved.", "question": "Omni 1: 26"}, {"answer": "12 And thus Laman and Lemuel, being the eldest, did murmur against their father. And they did murmur because they knew not the dealings of that God who had created them.", "question": "1 Nephi 2: 12"}, {"answer": "4 Therefore we are buried with him by baptism into death: that like as Christ was raised up from the dead by the glory of the Father, even so we also should walk in newness of life.", "question": "Romans 6: 4"}, {"answer": "1. Lead, kindly Light, amid th\u2019encircling gloom;\r\nLead thou me on!\r\nThe night is dark, and I am far from home;\r\nLead thou me on!\r\nKeep thou my feet; I do not ask to see\r\nThe distant scene\u2014one step enough for me.", "question": "Hymns 97: 1"}, {"answer": "1 I beseech you therefore, brethren, by the mercies of God, that ye present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy, acceptable unto God, which is your reasonable service.", "question": "Romans 12: 1"}, {"answer": "8 And again, I exhort you, my brethren, that ye deny not the gifts of God, for they are many; and they come from the same God. And there are different ways that these gifts are administered; but it is the same God who worketh all in all; and they are given by the manifestations of the Spirit of God unto men, to profit them.", "question": "Moroni 10: 8"}, {"answer": "2. I was not ever thus, nor pray\u2019d that thou\r\nShouldst lead me on.\r\nI loved to choose and see my path; but now,\r\nLead thou me on!\r\nI loved the garish day, and, spite of fears,\r\nPride ruled my will. Remember not past years.", "question": "Hymns 97: 2"}, {"answer": "3. So long thy pow\u2019r hath blest me, sure it still\r\nWill lead me on\r\nO\u2019er moor and fen, o\u2019er crag and torrent, till\r\nThe night is gone.\r\nAnd with the morn those angel faces smile,\r\nWhich I have loved long since, and lost awhile!", "question": "Hymns 97: 3"}, {"answer": "1. A poor, wayfaring Man of grief\r\nHath often crossed me on my way,\r\nWho sued so humbly for relief\r\nThat I could never answer nay.\r\nI had not pow\u2019r to ask his name,\r\nWhereto he went, or whence he came;\r\nYet there was something in his eye\r\nThat won my love; I knew not why.", "question": "Hymns 29: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Once, when my scanty meal was spread,\r\nHe entered; not a word he spake,\r\nJust perishing for want of bread.\r\nI gave him all; he blessed it, brake,\r\nAnd ate, but gave me part again.\r\nMine was an angel\u2019s portion then,\r\nFor while I fed with eager haste,\r\nThe crust was manna to my taste.", "question": "Hymns 29: 2"}, {"answer": "3. I spied him where a fountain burst\r\nClear from the rock; his strength was gone.\r\nThe heedless water mocked his thirst;\r\nHe heard it, saw it hurrying on.\r\nI ran and raised the suff\u2019rer up;\r\nThrice from the stream he drained my cup,\r\nDipped and returned it running o\u2019er;\r\nI drank and never thirsted more.", "question": "Hymns 29: 3"}, {"answer": "4. \u2019Twas night; the floods were out; it blew\r\nA winter hurricane aloof.\r\nI heard his voice abroad and flew\r\nTo bid him welcome to my roof.\r\nI warmed and clothed and cheered my guest\r\nAnd laid him on my couch to rest,\r\nThen made the earth my bed and seemed\r\nIn Eden\u2019s garden while I dreamed.", "question": "Hymns 29: 4"}, {"answer": "5. Stript, wounded, beaten nigh to death,\r\nI found him by the highway side.\r\nI roused his pulse, brought back his breath,\r\nRevived his spirit, and supplied\r\nWine, oil, refreshment\u2014he was healed.\r\nI had myself a wound concealed,\r\nBut from that hour forgot the smart,\r\nAnd peace bound up my broken heart.", "question": "Hymns 29: 5"}, {"answer": "6. In pris\u2019n I saw him next, condemned\r\nTo meet a traitor\u2019s doom at morn.\r\nThe tide of lying tongues I stemmed,\r\nAnd honored him \u2019mid shame and scorn.\r\nMy friendship\u2019s utmost zeal to try,\r\nHe asked if I for him would die.\r\nThe flesh was weak; my blood ran chill,\r\nBut my free spirit cried, \u201cI will!\u201d", "question": "Hymns 29: 6"}, {"answer": "7. Then in a moment to my view\r\nThe stranger started from disguise.\r\nThe tokens in his hands I knew;\r\nThe Savior stood before mine eyes.\r\nHe spake, and my poor name he named,\r\n\u201cOf me thou hast not been ashamed.\r\nThese deeds shall thy memorial be;\r\nFear not, thou didst them unto me.\u201d", "question": "Hymns 29: 7"}, {"answer": "1. Come, come, ye Saints, no toil nor labor fear;\r\nBut with joy wend your way.\r\nThough hard to you this journey may appear,\r\nGrace shall be as your day.\r\n\u2019Tis better far for us to strive\r\nOur useless cares from us to drive;\r\nDo this, and joy your hearts will swell\u2014\r\nAll is well! All is well!", "question": "Hymns 30: 1"}, {"answer": "3. We\u2019ll find the place which God for us prepared,\r\nFar away in the West,\r\nWhere none shall come to hurt or make afraid;\r\nThere the Saints will be blessed.\r\nWe\u2019ll make the air with music ring,\r\nShout praises to our God and King;\r\nAbove the rest these words we\u2019ll tell\u2014\r\nAll is well! All is well!", "question": "Hymns 30: 3"}, {"answer": "2. Why should we mourn or think our lot is hard?\r\n\u2019Tis not so; all is right.\r\nWhy should we think to earn a great reward\r\nIf we now shun the fight?\r\nGird up your loins; fresh courage take.\r\nOur God will never us forsake;\r\nAnd soon we\u2019ll have this tale to tell\u2014\r\nAll is well! All is well!", "question": "Hymns 30: 2"}, {"answer": "4. And should we die before our journey\u2019s through,\r\nHappy day! All is well!\r\nWe then are free from toil and sorrow, too;\r\nWith the just we shall dwell!\r\nBut if our lives are spared again\r\nTo see the Saints their rest obtain,\r\nOh, how we\u2019ll make this chorus swell\u2014\r\nAll is well! All is well!", "question": "Hymns 30: 4"}, {"answer": "39 Pray always that you enter not into temptation, that you may abide the day of his coming, whether in life or in death. Even so. Amen.", "question": "D&C 61: 39"}, {"answer": "20 And ye shall offer for a sacrifice unto me a broken heart and a contrite spirit. And whoso cometh unto me with a broken heart and a contrite spirit, him will I baptize with fire and with the Holy Ghost, even as the Lamanites, because of their faith in me at the time of their conversion, were baptized with fire and with the Holy Ghost, and they knew it not.", "question": "3 Nephi 9: 20"}, {"answer": "1. Ere you left your room this morning,\r\nDid you think to pray?\r\nIn the name of Christ, our Savior,\r\nDid you sue for loving favor\r\nAs a shield today?\r\nOh, how praying rests the weary!\r\nPrayer will change the night to day.\r\nSo, when life gets dark and dreary,\r\nDon\u2019t forget to pray.", "question": "Hymns 140: 1"}, {"answer": "2. When your heart was filled with anger,\r\nDid you think to pray?\r\nDid you plead for grace, my brother,\r\nThat you might forgive another\r\nWho had crossed your way?\r\nOh, how praying rests the weary!\r\nPrayer will change the night to day.\r\nSo, when life gets dark and dreary,\r\nDon\u2019t forget to pray.", "question": "Hymns 140: 2"}, {"answer": "3. When sore trials came upon you,\r\nDid you think to pray?\r\nWhen your soul was full of sorrow,\r\nBalm of Gilead did you borrow\r\nAt the gates of day?\r\nOh, how praying rests the weary!\r\nPrayer will change the night to day.\r\nSo, when life gets dark and dreary,\r\nDon\u2019t forget to pray.", "question": "Hymns 140: 3"}, {"answer": "1. We thank thee, O God, for a prophet\r\nTo guide us in these latter days.\r\nWe thank thee for sending the gospel\r\nTo lighten our minds with its rays.\r\nWe thank thee for every blessing\r\nBestowed by thy bounteous hand.\r\nWe feel it a pleasure to serve thee\r\nAnd love to obey thy command.", "question": "Hymns 19: 1"}, {"answer": "38 Gird up your loins and be watchful and be sober, looking forth for the coming of the Son of Man, for he cometh in an hour you think not.", "question": "D&C 61: 38"}, {"answer": "2. When dark clouds of trouble hang o\u2019er us\r\nAnd threaten our peace to destroy,\r\nThere is hope smiling brightly before us,\r\nAnd we know that deliv\u2019rance is nigh.\r\nWe doubt not the Lord nor his goodness.\r\nWe\u2019ve proved him in days that are past.\r\nThe wicked who fight against Zion\r\nWill surely be smitten at last.", "question": "Hymns 19: 2"}, {"answer": "3. We\u2019ll sing of his goodness and mercy.\r\nWe\u2019ll praise him by day and by night,\r\nRejoice in his glorious gospel,\r\nAnd bask in its life-giving light.\r\nThus on to eternal perfection\r\nThe honest and faithful will go,\r\nWhile they who reject this glad message\r\nShall never such happiness know.", "question": "Hymns 19: 3"}, {"answer": "37 And inasmuch as you have humbled yourselves before me, the blessings of the kingdom are yours.", "question": "D&C 61: 37"}, {"answer": "1. Have I done any good in the world today?\r\nHave I helped anyone in need?\r\nHave I cheered up the sad and made someone feel glad?\r\nIf not, I have failed indeed.\r\nHas anyone's burden been lighter today\r\nBecause I was willing to share?\r\nHave the sick and the weary been helped on their way?\r\nWhen they needed my help was I there?\r\nThen wake up and do something more\r\nThan dream of your mansion above.\r\nDoing good is a pleasure, a joy beyond measure,\r\nA blessing of duty and love.", "question": "Hymns 223: 1"}, {"answer": "2. There are chances for work all around just now,\r\nOpportunities right in our way.\r\nDo not let them pass by, saying, \"Sometime I'll try,\"\r\nBut go and do something today.\r\n'Tis noble of man to work and to give;\r\nLove's labor has merit alone.\r\nOnly he who does something helps others to live.\r\nTo God each good work will be known.\r\nThen wake up and do something more\r\nThan dream of your mansion above.\r\nDoing good is a pleasure, a joy beyond measure,\r\nA blessing of duty and love.", "question": "Hymns 223: 2"}, {"answer": "2. I marvel that he would descend from his throne divine\r\nTo rescue a soul so rebellious and proud as mine,\r\nThat he should extend his great love unto such as I,\r\nSufficient to own, to redeem, and to justify.\r\nOh, it is wonderful that he should care for me\r\nEnough to die for me!\r\nOh, it is wonderful, wonderful to me!", "question": "Hymns 193: 2"}, {"answer": "1. I stand all amazed at the love Jesus offers me,\r\nConfused at the grace that so fully he proffers me.\r\nI tremble to know that for me he was crucified,\r\nThat for me, a sinner, he suffered, he bled and died.\r\nOh, it is wonderful that he should care for me\r\nEnough to die for me!\r\nOh, it is wonderful, wonderful to me!", "question": "Hymns 193: 1"}, {"answer": "3. I think of his hands pierced and bleeding to pay the debt!\r\nSuch mercy, such love and devotion can I forget?\r\nNo, no, I will praise and adore at the mercy seat,\r\nUntil at the glorified throne I kneel at his feet.\r\nOh, it is wonderful that he should care for me\r\nEnough to die for me!\r\nOh, it is wonderful, wonderful to me!", "question": "Hymns 193: 3"}, {"answer": "3 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify this bread to the souls of all those who partake of it; that they may eat in remembrance of the body of thy Son, and witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they are willing to take upon them the name of thy Son, and always remember him, and keep his commandments which he hath given them, that they may always have his Spirit to be with them. Amen.", "question": "Moroni 4: 3"}, {"answer": "2 O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee, in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and sanctify this wine to the souls of all those who drink of it, that they may do it in remembrance of the blood of thy Son, which was shed for them; that they may witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they do always remember him, that they may have his Spirit to be with them. Amen.", "question": "Moroni 5: 2"}, {"answer": "36 And now, verily I say unto you, and what I say unto one I say unto all, be of good cheer, little children; for I am in your midst, and I have not forsaken you;", "question": "D&C 61: 36"}, {"answer": "1. As I have loved you,\r\nLove one another.\r\nThis new commandment:\r\nLove one another.\r\nBy this shall men know\r\nYe are my disciples,\r\nIf ye have love\r\nOne to another.", "question": "Hymns 308: 1"}, {"answer": "1. Be thou humble in thy weakness, and the Lord thy God shall lead thee,\r\nShall lead thee by the hand and give thee answer to thy prayers.\r\nBe thou humble in thy pleading, and the Lord thy God shall bless thee,\r\nShall bless thee with a sweet and calm assurance that he cares.", "question": "Hymns 130: 1"}, {"answer": "1. There is a green hill far away,\r\nWithout a city wall,\r\nWhere the dear Lord was crucified,\r\nWho died to save us all.", "question": "Hymns 194: 1"}, {"answer": "2. We may not know, we cannot tell,\r\nWhat pains he had to bear,\r\nBut we believe it was for us\r\nHe hung and suffered there.", "question": "Hymns 194: 2"}, {"answer": "4. Oh, dearly, dearly has he loved!\r\nAnd we must love him too,\r\nAnd trust in his redeeming blood,\r\nAnd try his works to do.", "question": "Hymns 194: 4"}, {"answer": "2. Called to know the richness of his blessing\u2014\r\nSons and daughters, children of a King\u2014\r\nGlad of heart, his holy name confessing,\r\nPraises unto him we bring.\r\nOnward, ever onward, as we glory in his name;\r\nOnward, ever onward, as we glory in his name;\r\nForward, pressing forward, as a triumph song we sing.\r\nGod our strength will be; press forward ever,\r\nCalled to serve our King.", "question": "Hymns 249: 2"}, {"answer": "3. There was no other good enough\r\nTo pay the price of sin.\r\nHe only could unlock the gate\r\nOf heav\u2019n and let us in.", "question": "Hymns 194: 3"}, {"answer": "2. Are you ever burdened with a load of care?\r\nDoes the cross seem heavy you are called to bear?\r\nCount your many blessings; ev\u2019ry doubt will fly,\r\nAnd you will be singing as the days go by.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your many blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.", "question": "Hymns 241: 2"}, {"answer": "2. Be thou humble in thy calling, and the Lord thy God shall teach thee\r\nTo serve his children gladly with a pure and gentle love.\r\nBe thou humble in thy longing, and the Lord thy God shall take thee,\r\nShall take thee home at last to ever dwell with him above.", "question": "Hymns 130: 2"}, {"answer": "1. Called to serve Him, heav\u2019nly King of glory,\r\nChosen e\u2019er to witness for his name,\r\nFar and wide we tell the Father\u2019s story,\r\nFar and wide his love proclaim.\r\nOnward, ever onward, as we glory in his name;\r\nOnward, ever onward, as we glory in his name;\r\nForward, pressing forward, as a triumph song we sing.\r\nGod our strength will be; press forward ever,\r\nCalled to serve our King.", "question": "Hymns 249: 1"}, {"answer": "1. Choose the right when a choice is placed before you.\r\nIn the right the Holy Spirit guides;\r\nAnd its light is forever shining o\u2019er you,\r\nWhen in the right your heart confides.\r\nChoose the right! Choose the right!\r\nLet wisdom mark the way before.\r\nIn its light, choose the right!\r\nAnd God will bless you evermore.", "question": "Hymns 239: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Choose the right! Let no spirit of digression\r\nOvercome you in the evil hour.\r\nThere\u2019s the right and the wrong to ev\u2019ry question;\r\nBe safe thru inspiration\u2019s pow\u2019r.\r\nChoose the right! Choose the right!\r\nLet wisdom mark the way before.\r\nIn its light, choose the right!\r\nAnd God will bless you evermore.", "question": "Hymns 239: 2"}, {"answer": "1. When upon life\u2019s billows you are tempest-tossed,\r\nWhen you are discouraged, thinking all is lost,\r\nCount your many blessings; name them one by one,\r\nAnd it will surprise you what the Lord has done.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your many blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.", "question": "Hymns 241: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Choose the right! There is peace in righteous doing.\r\nChoose the right! There\u2019s safety for the soul.\r\nChoose the right in all labors you\u2019re pursuing;\r\nLet God and heaven be your goal.\r\nChoose the right! Choose the right!\r\nLet wisdom mark the way before.\r\nIn its light, choose the right!\r\nAnd God will bless you evermore.", "question": "Hymns 239: 3"}, {"answer": "3. When you look at others with their lands and gold,\r\nThink that Christ has promised you his wealth untold.\r\nCount your many blessings; money cannot buy\r\nYour reward in heaven nor your home on high.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your many blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.", "question": "Hymns 241: 3"}, {"answer": "4. So amid the conflict, whether great or small,\r\nDo not be discouraged; God is over all.\r\nCount your many blessings; angels will attend,\r\nHelp and comfort give you to your journey\u2019s end.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.\r\nCount your blessings;\r\nName them one by one.\r\nCount your many blessings;\r\nSee what God hath done.", "question": "Hymns 241: 4"}, {"answer": "2. The straight and narrow way to heav\u2019n,\r\nWhere angels bright and fair\r\nAre singing to God\u2019s praise, is found\r\nThru constant secret prayer.\r\nMay my heart be turned to pray,\r\nPray in secret day by day,\r\nThat this boon to mortals giv\u2019n\r\nMay unite my soul with heav\u2019n.", "question": "Hymns 144: 2"}, {"answer": "1. The Spirit of God like a fire is burning!\r\nThe latter-day glory begins to come forth;\r\nThe visions and blessings of old are returning,\r\nAnd angels are coming to visit the earth.\r\nWe\u2019ll sing and we\u2019ll shout with the armies of heaven,\r\nHosanna, hosanna to God and the Lamb!\r\nLet glory to them in the highest be given,\r\nHenceforth and forever, Amen and amen!", "question": "Hymns 2: 1"}, {"answer": "2. The Lord is extending the Saints\u2019 understanding,\r\nRestoring their judges and all as at first.\r\nThe knowledge and power of God are expanding;\r\nThe veil o\u2019er the earth is beginning to burst.\r\nWe\u2019ll sing and we\u2019ll shout with the armies of heaven,\r\nHosanna, hosanna to God and the Lamb!\r\nLet glory to them in the highest be given,\r\nHenceforth and forever, Amen and amen!", "question": "Hymns 2: 2"}, {"answer": "1. Teach me to walk in the light of his love;\r\nTeach me to pray to my Father above;\r\nTeach me to know of the things that are right;\r\nTeach me, teach me to walk in the light.\r\n", "question": "Hymns 304: 1"}, {"answer": "1. Nearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer to thee!\r\nE\u2019en though it be a cross\r\nThat raiseth me.\r\nStill all my song shall be\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer to thee!", "question": "Hymns 100: 1"}, {"answer": "4. How blessed the day when the lamb and the lion\r\nShall lie down together without any ire,\r\nAnd Ephraim be crowned with his blessing in Zion,\r\nAs Jesus descends with his chariot of fire!\r\nWe\u2019ll sing and we\u2019ll shout with the armies of heaven,\r\nHosanna, hosanna to God and the Lamb!\r\nLet glory to them in the highest be given,\r\nHenceforth and forever, Amen and amen!", "question": "Hymns 2: 4"}, {"answer": "2. Come, little child, and together we\u2019ll learn\r\nOf his commandments, that we may return\r\nHome to his presence, to live in his sight\u2014\r\nAlways, always to walk in the light.", "question": "Hymns 304: 2"}, {"answer": "1. I have a fam\u2019ly here on earth.\r\nThey are so good to me.\r\nI want to share my life with them through all eternity.\r\nFam\u2019lies can be together forever\r\nThrough Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s plan.\r\nI always want to be with my own family,\r\nAnd the Lord has shown me how I can.\r\nThe Lord has shown me how I can.", "question": "Hymns 300: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Father in Heaven, we thank thee this day\r\nFor loving guidance to show us the way.\r\nGrateful, we praise thee with songs of delight!\r\nGladly, gladly we\u2019ll walk in the light.", "question": "Hyms 304: 3"}, {"answer": "1. There is an hour of peace and rest,\r\nUnmarred by earthly care;\r\n\u2019Tis when before the Lord I go\r\nAnd kneel in secret prayer.\r\nMay my heart be turned to pray,\r\nPray in secret day by day,\r\nThat this boon to mortals giv\u2019n\r\nMay unite my soul with heav\u2019n.", "question": "Hymns 144: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Though like the wanderer,\r\nThe sun gone down,\r\nDarkness be over me,\r\nMy rest a stone,\r\nYet in my dreams I\u2019d be\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer to thee!", "question": "Hymns 100: 2"}, {"answer": "3. There let the way appear,\r\nSteps unto heav\u2019n;\r\nAll that thou sendest me,\r\nIn mercy giv\u2019n;\r\nAngels to beckon me\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer to thee!", "question": "Hymns 100: 3"}, {"answer": "5. Or if, on joyful wing\r\nCleaving the sky,\r\nSun, moon, and stars forgot,\r\nUpward I fly,\r\nStill all my song shall be\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer to thee!", "question": "Hyms 100: 5"}, {"answer": "4. Then with my waking thoughts\r\nBright with thy praise,\r\nOut of my stony griefs\r\nBethel I\u2019ll raise;\r\nSo by my woes to be\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer, my God, to thee,\r\nNearer to thee!", "question": "Hymns 100: 4"}, {"answer": "3. When sailing on life\u2019s stormy sea,\r\n\u2019Mid billows of despair,\r\n\u2019Tis solace to my soul to know\r\nGod hears my secret prayer.\r\nMay my heart be turned to pray,\r\nPray in secret day by day,\r\nThat this boon to mortals giv\u2019n\r\nMay unite my soul with heav\u2019n.", "question": "Hymns 144: 3"}, {"answer": "4. When thorns are strewn along my path,\r\nAnd foes my feet ensnare,\r\nMy Savior to my aid will come,\r\nIf sought in secret prayer.\r\nMay my heart be turned to pray,\r\nPray in secret day by day,\r\nThat this boon to mortals giv\u2019n\r\nMay unite my soul with heav\u2019n.", "question": "Hyms 144: 4"}, {"answer": "2. While I am in my early years,\r\nI\u2019ll prepare most carefully,\r\nSo I can marry in God\u2019s temple for eternity.\r\nFam\u2019lies can be together forever\r\nThrough Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s plan.\r\nI always want to be with my own family,\r\nAnd the Lord has shown me how I can.\r\nThe Lord has shown me how I can.", "question": "Hymns 300: 2"}, {"answer": "3. We\u2019ll call in our solemn assemblies in spirit,\r\nTo spread forth the kingdom of heaven abroad,\r\nThat we through our faith may begin to inherit\r\nThe visions and blessings and glories of God.\r\nWe\u2019ll sing and we\u2019ll shout with the armies of heaven,\r\nHosanna, hosanna to God and the Lamb!\r\nLet glory to them in the highest be given,\r\nHenceforth and forever, Amen and amen!", "question": "Hymns 2: 3"}, {"answer": "11 My son, despise not the chastening of the Lord; neither be weary of his correction:\r\n12 For whom the Lord loveth he correcteth; even as a father the son in whom he delighteth.", "question": "Proverbs 3: 11-12"}, {"answer": "1. Oh, how lovely was the morning!\r\nRadiant beamed the sun above.\r\nBees were humming, sweet birds singing,\r\nMusic ringing thru the grove,\r\nWhen within the shady woodland\r\nJoseph sought the God of love,\r\nWhen within the shady woodland\r\nJoseph sought the God of love.", "question": "Hymns 26: 1"}, {"answer": "1. Joy to the world, the Lord is come;\r\nLet earth receive her King!\r\nLet ev\u2019ry heart prepare him room,\r\nAnd Saints and angels sing,\r\nAnd Saints and angels sing,\r\nAnd Saints, and Saints and angels sing.", "question": "Hymns 201: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Humbly kneeling, sweet appealing\u2014\r\n\u2019Twas the boy\u2019s first uttered prayer\u2014\r\nWhen the pow\u2019rs of sin assailing\r\nFilled his soul with deep despair;\r\nBut undaunted, still he trusted\r\nIn his Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s care;\r\nBut undaunted, still he trusted\r\nIn his Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s care.", "question": "Hymns 26: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Suddenly a light descended,\r\nBrighter far than noonday sun,\r\nAnd a shining, glorious pillar\r\nO\u2019er him fell, around him shone,\r\nWhile appeared two heav\u2019nly beings,\r\nGod the Father and the Son,\r\nWhile appeared two heav\u2019nly beings,\r\nGod the Father and the Son.", "question": "Hymns 26: 3"}, {"answer": "4. \u201cJoseph, this is my Beloved;\r\nHear him!\u201d Oh, how sweet the word!\r\nJoseph\u2019s humble prayer was answered,\r\nAnd he listened to the Lord.\r\nOh, what rapture filled his bosom,\r\nFor he saw the living God;\r\nOh, what rapture filled his bosom,\r\nFor he saw the living God.", "question": "Hymns 26: 4"}, {"answer": "2. Rejoice! Rejoice when Jesus reigns,\r\nAnd Saints their songs employ,\r\nWhile fields and floods, rocks, hills, and plains\r\nRepeat the sounding joy,\r\nRepeat the sounding joy,\r\nRepeat, repeat the sounding joy.", "question": "Hymns 201: 2"}, {"answer": "3. No more will sin and sorrow grow,\r\nNor thorns infest the ground;\r\nHe\u2019ll come and make the blessings flow\r\nFar as the curse was found,\r\nFar as the curse was found,\r\nFar as, far as the curse was found.", "question": "Hymns 201: 3"}, {"answer": "4. Rejoice! Rejoice in the Most High,\r\nWhile Israel spreads abroad\r\nLike stars that glitter in the sky,\r\nAnd ever worship God,\r\nAnd ever worship God,\r\nAnd ever, and ever worship God.", "question": "Hymns 201: 4"}, {"answer": "1. Angels we have heard on high\r\nSweetly singing o\u2019er the plains,\r\nAnd the mountains in reply\r\nEchoing their joyous strains.\r\nGloria in excelsis Deo.\r\nGloria in excelsis Deo.", "question": "Hymns 203: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Shepherds, why this jubilee?\r\nWhy your joyous strains prolong?\r\nWhat the gladsome tidings be\r\nWhich inspire your heav\u2019nly song?\r\nGloria in excelsis Deo.\r\nGloria in excelsis Deo.", "question": "Hymns 203: 2"}, {"answer": "1. Silent night! Holy night!\r\nAll is calm, all is bright\r\nRound yon virgin mother and Child.\r\nHoly Infant, so tender and mild,\r\nSleep in heavenly peace;\r\nSleep in heavenly peace.", "question": "Hymns 204: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Come to Bethlehem and see\r\nHim whose birth the angels sing;\r\nCome, adore on bended knee\r\nChrist the Lord, the newborn King.\r\nGloria in excelsis Deo.\r\nGloria in excelsis Deo.", "question": "Hymns 203: 3"}, {"answer": "2. Silent night! Holy night!\r\nShepherds quake at the sight!\r\nGlories stream from heaven afar;\r\nHeav\u2019nly hosts sing Alleluia!\r\nChrist, the Savior, is born!\r\nChrist, the Savior, is born!", "question": "Hymns 204: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Silent night! Holy night!\r\nSon of God, love\u2019s pure light\r\nRadiant beams from thy holy face,\r\nWith the dawn of redeeming grace,\r\nJesus, Lord, at thy birth;\r\nJesus, Lord, at thy birth.", "question": "Hymns 204: 3"}, {"answer": "1. Away in a manger, no crib for his bed,\r\nThe little Lord Jesus laid down his sweet head;\r\nThe stars in the heavens looked down where he lay,\r\nThe little Lord Jesus, asleep on the hay.", "question": "Hymns 206: 1"}, {"answer": "2. The cattle are lowing; the poor baby wakes,\r\nBut little Lord Jesus, no crying he makes.\r\nI love thee, Lord Jesus; look down from the sky\r\nAnd stay by my cradle till morning is nigh.", "question": "Hymns 206: 2"}, {"answer": "1. The first Noel the angel did say\r\nWas to certain poor shepherds in fields as they lay,\r\nIn fields where they lay keeping their sheep\r\nOn a cold winter\u2019s night that was so deep.\r\nNoel, Noel, Noel, Noel!\r\nBorn is the King of Israel!", "question": "Hymns 213: 1"}, {"answer": "2. They looked up and saw a star\r\nShining in the East beyond them far,\r\nAnd to the earth it gave great light,\r\nAnd so it continued both day and night.\r\nNoel, Noel, Noel, Noel!\r\nBorn is the King of Israel!", "question": "Hymns 213: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Be near me, Lord Jesus; I ask thee to stay\r\nClose by me forever, and love me, I pray.\r\nBless all the dear children in thy tender care,\r\nAnd fit us for heaven to live with thee there.", "question": "Hymns 206: 3"}, {"answer": "1. Hark! the herald angels sing\r\nGlory to the newborn King!\r\nPeace on earth and mercy mild,\r\nGod and sinners reconciled!\r\nJoyful, all ye nations, rise;\r\nJoin the triumph of the skies;\r\nWith th\u2019angelic host proclaim\r\nChrist is born in Bethlehem!\r\nHark! the herald angels sing\r\nGlory to the newborn King!", "question": "Hymns 209: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Hail the heav\u2019n-born Prince of Peace!\r\nHail the Son of Righteousness!\r\nLight and life to all he brings,\r\nRis\u2019n with healing in his wings.\r\nMild he lays his glory by,\r\nBorn that man no more may die;\r\nBorn to raise the sons of earth,\r\nBorn to give them second birth.\r\nHark! the herald angels sing\r\nGlory to the newborn King!", "question": "Hymns 209: 2"}, {"answer": "1. I heard the bells on Christmas day\r\nTheir old familiar carols play,\r\nAnd wild and sweet the words repeat\r\nOf peace on earth, good will to men.", "question": "Hymns 214: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Sing, choirs of angels,\r\nSing in exultation;\r\nSing, all ye citizens of heav\u2019n above!\r\nGlory to God,\r\nGlory in the highest;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him,\r\nChrist, the Lord.", "question": "Hymns 202: 2"}, {"answer": "2. I thought how, as the day had come,\r\nThe belfries of all Christendom\r\nHad rolled along th\u2019unbroken song\r\nOf peace on earth, good will to men.", "question": "Hymns 214: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Yea, Lord, we greet thee,\r\nBorn this happy morning;\r\nJesus, to thee be all glory giv\u2019n.\r\nSon of the Father,\r\nNow in flesh appearing;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him,\r\nChrist, the Lord.", "question": "Hymns 202: 3"}, {"answer": "2. For Christ is born of Mary,\r\nAnd, gathered all above\r\nWhile mortals sleep, the angels keep\r\nTheir watch of wond\u2019ring love.\r\nO morning stars, together\r\nProclaim the holy birth,\r\nAnd praises sing to God the King,\r\nAnd peace to men on earth.", "question": "Hymns 208: 2"}, {"answer": "1. \u201cCome, follow me,\u201d the Savior said.\r\nThen let us in his footsteps tread,\r\nFor thus alone can we be one\r\nWith God\u2019s own loved, begotten Son.", "question": "Hymns 116: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Is it enough alone to know\r\nThat we must follow him below,\r\nWhile trav\u2019ling thru this vale of tears?\r\nNo, this extends to holier spheres.", "question": "Hymns 116: 3"}, {"answer": "5. We must the onward path pursue\r\nAs wider fields expand to view,\r\nAnd follow him unceasingly,\r\nWhate\u2019er our lot or sphere may be.", "question": "Hymns 116: 5"}, {"answer": "3. And in despair I bowed my head:\r\n\u201cThere is no peace on earth,\u201d I said,\r\n\u201cFor hate is strong and mocks the song\r\nOf peace on earth, good will to men.\u201d", "question": "Hymns 214: 3"}, {"answer": "1. Oh, come, all ye faithful,\r\nJoyful and triumphant!\r\nOh, come ye, oh come ye to Bethlehem.\r\nCome and behold him,\r\nBorn the King of angels;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him;\r\nOh, come, let us adore him,\r\nChrist, the Lord.", "question": "Hymns 202: 1"}, {"answer": "4. Then pealed the bells more loud and deep:\r\n\u201cGod is not dead, nor doth he sleep;\r\nThe wrong shall fail, the right prevail,\r\nWith peace on earth, good will to men.\u201d", "question": "Hymns 214: 4"}, {"answer": "5. Till, ringing, singing, on its way,\r\nThe world revolved from night to day,\r\nA voice, a chime, a chant sublime,\r\nOf peace on earth, good will to men!", "question": "Hymns 214: 5"}, {"answer": "3. How silently, how silently\r\nThe wondrous gift is giv\u2019n!\r\nSo God imparts to human hearts\r\nThe blessings of his heav\u2019n.\r\nNo ear may hear his coming;\r\nBut in this world of sin,\r\nWhere meek souls will receive him, still\r\nThe dear Christ enters in.", "question": "Hymns 208: 3"}, {"answer": "4. The heav\u2019nly star its rays afar\r\nOn ev\u2019ry land is throwing,\r\nAnd shall not cease till holy peace\r\nIn all the earth is growing.\r\nHosanna, hosanna, hosanna to his name!", "question": "Hymns 210: 4"}, {"answer": "4. Not only shall we emulate\r\nHis course while in this earthly state,\r\nBut when we\u2019re freed from present cares,\r\nIf with our Lord we would be heirs.", "question": "Hymns 116: 4"}, {"answer": "1. O little town of Bethlehem,\r\nHow still we see thee lie.\r\nAbove thy deep and dreamless sleep\r\nThe silent stars go by;\r\nYet in thy dark streets shineth\r\nThe everlasting Light.\r\nThe hopes and fears of all the years\r\nAre met in thee tonight.", "question": "Hymns 208: 1"}, {"answer": "1. With wond\u2019ring awe the wise men saw\r\nThe star in heaven springing,\r\nAnd with delight, in peaceful night,\r\nThey heard the angels singing:\r\nHosanna, hosanna, hosanna to his name!", "question": "Hymns 210: 1"}, {"answer": "2. By light of star they traveled far\r\nTo seek the lowly manger,\r\nA humble bed wherein was laid\r\nThe wondrous little Stranger.\r\nHosanna, hosanna, hosanna to his name!", "question": "Hymns 210: 2"}, {"answer": "20 Behold what the scripture says\u2014man shall not smite, neither shall he judge; for judgment is mine, saith the Lord, and vengeance is mine also, and I will repay.", "question": "Mormon 8: 20"}, {"answer": "2. \u201cCome, follow me,\u201d a simple phrase,\r\nYet truth\u2019s sublime, effulgent rays\r\nAre in these simple words combined\r\nTo urge, inspire the human mind.", "question": "Hymns 116: 2"}, {"answer": "3. And still is found, the world around,\r\nThe old and hallowed story,\r\nAnd still is sung in ev\u2019ry tongue\r\nThe angels\u2019 song of glory:\r\nHosanna, hosanna, hosanna to his name!", "question": "Hymns 210: 3"}, {"answer": "6. For thrones, dominions, kingdoms, pow\u2019rs,\r\nAnd glory great and bliss are ours,\r\nIf we, throughout eternity,\r\nObey his words, \u201cCome, follow me.\u201d", "question": "Hymns 116: 6"}, {"answer": "42 Saying, What think ye of Christ? whose son is he? They say unto him, The Son of David.", "question": "Matthew 22: 42"}, {"answer": "3. I would be my brother\u2019s keeper;\r\nI would learn the healer\u2019s art.\r\nTo the wounded and the weary\r\nI would show a gentle heart.\r\nI would be my brother\u2019s keeper\u2014\r\nLord, I would follow thee.", "question": "Hymns 220: 3"}, {"answer": "4. In word and deed he doth require\r\nMy will to his, like son to sire,\r\nBe made to bend, and I, as son,\r\nLearn conduct from the Holy One.", "question": "Hymns 187: 4"}, {"answer": "13 Happy is the man that findeth wisdom, and the man that getteth understanding.", "question": "Proverbs 3: 13"}, {"answer": "1. God be with you till we meet again;\r\nBy his counsels guide, uphold you;\r\nWith his sheep securely fold you.\r\nGod be with you till we meet again.\r\nTill we meet, till we meet,\r\nTill we meet at Jesus\u2019 feet,\r\nTill we meet, till we meet,\r\nGod be with you till we meet again.", "question": "Hymns 152: 1"}, {"answer": "3. God be with you till we meet again;\r\nKeep love\u2019s banner floating o\u2019er you;\r\nSmite death\u2019s threat\u2019ning wave before you.\r\nGod be with you till we meet again.\r\nTill we meet, till we meet,\r\nTill we meet at Jesus\u2019 feet,\r\nTill we meet, till we meet,\r\nGod be with you till we meet again.", "question": "Hymns 152: 3"}, {"answer": "4. When through the deep waters I call thee to go,\r\nThe rivers of sorrow shall not thee o\u2019erflow,\r\nFor I will be with thee, thy troubles to bless,\r\nAnd sanctify to thee, and sanctify to thee,\r\nAnd sanctify to thee thy deepest distress.", "question": "Hymns 85: 4"}, {"answer": "1. Savior, may I learn to love thee,\r\nWalk the path that thou hast shown,\r\nPause to help and lift another,\r\nFinding strength beyond my own.\r\nSavior, may I learn to love thee\u2014\r\nLord, I would follow thee.", "question": "Hymns 220: 1"}, {"answer": "2. He came as man, though Son of God,\r\nAnd bowed himself beneath the rod.\r\nHe died in holy innocence,\r\nA broken law to recompense.", "question": "Hymns 187: 2"}, {"answer": "2. Who am I to judge another\r\nWhen I walk imperfectly?\r\nIn the quiet heart is hidden\r\nSorrow that the eye can\u2019t see.\r\nWho am I to judge another?\r\nLord, I would follow thee.", "question": "Hymns 220: 2"}, {"answer": "1. God loved us, so he sent his Son,\r\nChrist Jesus, the atoning One,\r\nTo show us by the path he trod\r\nThe one and only way to God.", "question": "Hymns 187: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Come unto Jesus; He\u2019ll surely hear you,\r\nIf you in meekness plead for his love.\r\nOh, know you not that angels are near you\r\nFrom brightest mansions above?", "question": "Hymns 117: 3"}, {"answer": "4. Savior, may I love my brother\r\nAs I know thou lovest me,\r\nFind in thee my strength, my beacon,\r\nFor thy servant I would be.\r\nSavior, may I love my brother\u2014\r\nLord, I would follow thee.", "question": "Hymns 220: 4"}, {"answer": "3. Oh, love effulgent, love divine!\r\nWhat debt of gratitude is mine,\r\nThat in his off\u2019ring I have part\r\nAnd hold a place within his heart.", "question": "Hymns 187: 3"}, {"answer": "5. This sacrament doth represent\r\nHis blood and body for me spent.\r\nPartaking now is deed for word\r\nThat I remember him, my Lord.", "question": "Hymns 187: 5"}, {"answer": "1 This is the third time I am coming to you. In the mouth of two or three witnesses shall every word be established.", "question": "2 Corinthians 13: 1"}, {"answer": "2. God be with you till we meet again;\r\nWhen life\u2019s perils thick confound you,\r\nPut his arms unfailing round you.\r\nGod be with you till we meet again.\r\nTill we meet, till we meet,\r\nTill we meet at Jesus\u2019 feet,\r\nTill we meet, till we meet,\r\nGod be with you till we meet again.", "question": "Hymns 152: 2"}, {"answer": "1. How firm a foundation, ye Saints of the Lord,\r\nIs laid for your faith in his excellent word!\r\nWhat more can he say than to you he hath said,\r\nWho unto the Savior, who unto the Savior,\r\nWho unto the Savior for refuge have fled?", "question": "Hymns 85: 1"}, {"answer": "5. When through fiery trials thy pathway shall lie,\r\nMy grace, all sufficient, shall be thy supply.\r\nThe flame shall not hurt thee; I only design\r\nThy dross to consume, thy dross to consume,\r\nThy dross to consume and thy gold to refine.", "question": "Hymns 85: 5"}, {"answer": "6. E\u2019en down to old age, all my people shall prove\r\nMy sov\u2019reign, eternal, unchangeable love;\r\nAnd then, when gray hair shall their temples adorn,\r\nLike lambs shall they still, like lambs shall they still,\r\nLike lambs shall they still in my bosom be borne.", "question": "Hymns 85: 6"}, {"answer": "1. Come unto Jesus, ye heavy laden,\r\nCareworn and fainting, by sin oppressed.\r\nHe\u2019ll safely guide you unto that haven\r\nWhere all who trust him may rest.", "question": "Hymns 117: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Come unto Jesus; He\u2019ll ever heed you,\r\nThough in the darkness you\u2019ve gone astray.\r\nHis love will find you and gently lead you\r\nFrom darkest night into day.", "question": "Hymns 117: 2"}, {"answer": "4. Come unto Jesus from ev\u2019ry nation,\r\nFrom ev\u2019ry land and isle of the sea.\r\nUnto the high and lowly in station,\r\nEver he calls, \u201cCome to me.\u201d", "question": "Hymns 117: 4"}, {"answer": "2. In ev\u2019ry condition\u2014in sickness, in health,\r\nIn poverty\u2019s vale or abounding in wealth,\r\nAt home or abroad, on the land or the sea\u2014\r\nAs thy days may demand, as thy days may demand,\r\nAs thy days may demand, so thy succor shall be.", "question": "Hymns 85: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Fear not, I am with thee; oh, be not dismayed,\r\nFor I am thy God and will still give thee aid.\r\nI\u2019ll strengthen thee, help thee, and cause thee to stand,\r\nUpheld by my righteous, upheld by my righteous,\r\nUpheld by my righteous, omnipotent hand.", "question": "Hymns 85: 3"}, {"answer": "7. The soul that on Jesus hath leaned for repose\r\nI will not, I cannot, desert to his foes;\r\nThat soul, though all hell should endeavor to shake,\r\nI\u2019ll never, no never, I\u2019ll never, no never,\r\nI\u2019ll never, no never, no never forsake!", "question": "Hymns 85: 7"}, {"answer": "5 For all who will have a blessing at my hands shall abide the law which was appointed for that blessing, and the conditions thereof, as were instituted from before the foundation of the world.", "question": "D&C 132: 5"}, {"answer": "1. Keep the commandments; keep the commandments!\r\nIn this there is safety; in this there is peace.\r\nHe will send blessings; He will send blessings.\r\nWords of a prophet: Keep the commandments.\r\nIn this there is safety and peace.", "question": "Hymns 303: 1"}, {"answer": "1. Heavenly Father, are you really there?\r\nAnd do you hear and answer ev\u2019ry child\u2019s prayer?\r\nSome say that heaven is far away,\r\nBut I feel it close around me as I pray.\r\nHeavenly Father, I remember now\r\nSomething that Jesus told disciples long ago:\r\n\u201cSuffer the children to come to me.\u201d\r\nFather, in prayer I\u2019m coming now to thee.", "question": "Children's Songbook 12: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Pray, he is there;\r\nSpeak, he is list\u2019ning.\r\nYou are his child;\r\nHis love now surrounds you.\r\nHe hears your prayer;\r\nHe loves the children.\r\nOf such is the kingdom, the kingdom of heav\u2019n.", "question": "Children's Songbook 12: 2"}, {"answer": "1. I\u2019m trying to be like Jesus;\r\nI\u2019m following in his ways.\r\nI\u2019m trying to love as he did, in all that I do and say.\r\nAt times I am tempted to make a wrong choice,\r\nBut I try to listen as the still small voice whispers,\r\n\u201cLove one another as Jesus loves you.\r\nTry to show kindness in all that you do.\r\nBe gentle and loving in deed and in thought,\r\nFor these are the things Jesus taught.\u201d", "question": "Children's Songbook 78: 1"}, {"answer": "2. I\u2019m trying to love my neighbor;\r\nI\u2019m learning to serve my friends.\r\nI watch for the day of gladness when Jesus will come again.\r\nI try to remember the lessons he taught.\r\nThen the Holy Spirit enters into my thoughts, saying:\r\n\u201cLove one another as Jesus loves you.\r\nTry to show kindness in all that you do.\r\nBe gentle and loving in deed and in thought,\r\nFor these are the things Jesus taught.\u201d", "question": "Children's Songbook 78: 2"}, {"answer": "1. \u201cGive,\u201d said the little stream,\r\n\u201cGive, oh! give, give, oh! give.\u201d\r\n\u201cGive,\u201d said the little stream,\r\nAs it hurried down the hill;\r\n\u201cI\u2019m small, I know, but wherever I go\r\nThe fields grow greener still.\u201d\r\nSinging, singing all the day,\r\n\u201cGive away, oh! give away.\u201d\r\nSinging, singing all the day,\r\n\u201cGive, oh! give away.\u201d", "question": "Children's Songbook 236: 1"}, {"answer": "1. I know my Father lives and loves me too.\r\nThe Spirit whispers this to me and tells me it is true,\r\nAnd tells me it is true.", "question": "Children's Songbook 5: 1"}, {"answer": "2. He sent me here to earth, by faith to live his plan.\r\nThe Spirit whispers this to me and tells me that I can,\r\nAnd tells me that I can.", "question": "Children's Songbook 5: 2"}, {"answer": "24 And see that ye have faith, hope, and charity, and then ye will always abound in good works.", "question": "Alma 7: 24"}, {"answer": "2. Father said he needed someone who had enough love\r\nTo give his life so we all could return there above.\r\nThere was another who sought for the honor divine.\r\nJesus said, \u201cFather, send me, and the glory be thine.\u201d", "question": "Children's Songbook 4: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Jesus was chosen, and as the Messiah he came,\r\nConquering evil and death through his glorious name,\r\nGiving us hope of a wonderful life yet to be\u2014\r\nHome in that heaven where Father is waiting for me.", "question": "Children's Songbook 4: 3"}, {"answer": "2. \u201cGive,\u201d said the little rain,\r\n\u201cGive, oh! give, give, oh! give.\u201d\r\n\u201cGive,\u201d said the little rain,\r\nAs it fell upon the flow\u2019rs;\r\n\u201cI\u2019ll raise their drooping heads again,\u201d\r\nAs it fell upon the flow\u2019rs.\r\nSinging, singing all the day,\r\n\u201cGive away, oh! give away.\u201d\r\nSinging, singing all the day,\r\n\u201cGive, oh! give away.\u201d", "question": "Children's Songbook 236: 2"}, {"answer": "2. (Boys) Mine is a home where ev\u2019ry hour\r\nis blessed by the strength of priesthood pow\u2019r,\r\nWith father and mother leading the way,\r\nTeaching me how to trust and obey;\r\nAnd the things they teach are crystal clear,\r\nFor love is spoken here.\r\n\r\n[3rd ending] I can often feel the Savior near\r\nWhen love is spoken here.", "question": "Children's Songbook 190: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Give, then, as Jesus gives,\r\nGive, oh! give, give, oh! give.\r\nGive, then, as Jesus gives;\r\nThere is something all can give.\r\nDo as the streams and blossoms do:\r\nFor God and others live.\r\nSinging, singing all the day,\r\n\u201cGive away, oh! give away.\u201d\r\nSinging, singing all the day,\r\n\u201cGive, oh! give away.\u201d", "question": "Children's Songbook 236: 3"}, {"answer": "1. I lived in heaven a long time ago, it is true;\r\nLived there and loved there with people I know. So did you.\r\nThen Heav\u2019nly Father presented a beautiful plan,\r\nAll about earth and eternal salvation for man.", "question": "Children's Songbook 4: 1"}, {"answer": "1. (Girls) I see my mother kneeling with our family each day.\r\nI hear the words she whispers as she bows her head to pray.\r\nHer plea to the Father quiets all my fears,\r\nAnd I am thankful love is spoken here.", "question": "Children's Songbook 190: 1"}, {"answer": "1. I am a child of God,\r\nAnd he has sent me here,\r\nHas given me an earthly home\r\nWith parents kind and dear.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Children's Songbook 2: 1"}, {"answer": "2. I am a child of God,\r\nAnd so my needs are great;\r\nHelp me to understand his words\r\nBefore it grows too late.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Children's Songbook 2: 2"}, {"answer": "3. I am a child of God.\r\nRich blessings are in store;\r\nIf I but learn to do his will,\r\nI\u2019ll live with him once more.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Children's Songbook 2: 3"}, {"answer": "4. I am a child of God.\r\nHis promises are sure;\r\nCelestial glory shall be mine\r\nIf I can but endure.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Children's Songbook 2: 4"}, {"answer": "1. All things bright and beautiful,\r\nAll creatures great and small,\r\nAll things wise and wonderful,\r\nThe Lord God made them all.\r\nEach little flow\u2019r that opens,\r\nEach little bird that sings,\r\nHe made their glowing colors,\r\nHe made their tiny wings:", "question": "Children's Songbook 231: 1"}, {"answer": "2. All things bright and beautiful,\r\nAll creatures great and small,\r\nAll things wise and wonderful,\r\nThe Lord God made them all.\r\nThe purple-headed mountain,\r\nThe river running by,\r\nThe sunset and the morning\r\nThat brighten up the sky:", "question": "Children's Songbook 231: 2"}, {"answer": "3. All things bright and beautiful,\r\nAll creatures great and small,\r\nAll things wise and wonderful,\r\nThe Lord God made them all.\r\nThe cold wind in the winter,\r\nThe pleasant summer sun,\r\nThe ripe fruits in the garden,\r\nHe made them ev\u2019ry one:", "question": "Children's Songbook 231: 3"}, {"answer": "4. All things bright and beautiful,\r\nAll creatures great and small,\r\nAll things wise and wonderful,\r\nThe Lord God made them all.\r\nThe tall trees in the greenwood,\r\nThe meadows where we play,\r\nThe rushes by the water\r\nWe gather ev\u2019ry day:", "question": "Children's Songbook 231: 4"}, {"answer": "1. I am like a star shining brightly,\r\nSmiling for the whole world to see.\r\nI can do and say happy things each day,\r\nFor I know Heav\u2019nly Father loves me.", "question": "Children's Songbook 163: 1"}, {"answer": "1. Jesus said love ev\u2019ryone;\r\nTreat them kindly, too.\r\nWhen your heart is filled with love,\r\nOthers will love you.", "question": "Children's Songbook 61: 1"}, {"answer": "1. I feel my Savior\u2019s love\r\nIn all the world around me.\r\nHis Spirit warms my soul\r\nThrough ev\u2019rything I see.\r\nHe knows I will follow him,\r\nGive all my life to him.\r\nI feel my Savior\u2019s love,\r\nThe love he freely gives me.", "question": "Children's Songbook 74: 1"}, {"answer": "2. I feel my Savior\u2019s love;\r\nIts gentleness enfolds me,\r\nAnd when I kneel to pray,\r\nMy heart is filled with peace.\r\nHe knows I will follow him,\r\nGive all my life to him.\r\nI feel my Savior\u2019s love,\r\nThe love he freely gives me.", "question": "Children's Songbook 74: 2"}, {"answer": "3. I feel my Savior\u2019s love\r\nAnd know that he will bless me.\r\nI offer him my heart;\r\nMy shepherd he will be.\r\nHe knows I will follow him,\r\nGive all my life to him.\r\nI feel my Savior\u2019s love,\r\nThe love he freely gives me.", "question": "Children's Songbook 74: 3"}, {"answer": "4. I\u2019ll share my Savior\u2019s love\r\nBy serving others freely.\r\nIn serving I am blessed.\r\nIn giving I receive.\r\nHe knows I will follow him,\r\nGive all my life to him.\r\nI feel my Savior\u2019s love,\r\nThe love he freely gives me.", "question": "Children's Songbook 74: 4"}, {"answer": "1. We have been born, as Nephi of old,\r\nTo goodly parents who love the Lord.\r\nWe have been taught, and we understand,\r\nThat we must do as the Lord commands.\r\nWe are as the army of Helaman.\r\nWe have been taught in our youth.\r\nAnd we will be the Lord\u2019s missionaries\r\nTo bring the world his truth.", "question": "Children's Songbook 172: 1"}, {"answer": "1. How gentle God\u2019s commands!\r\nHow kind his precepts are!\r\nCome, cast your burdens on the Lord\r\nAnd trust his constant care.", "question": "Hymns 125: 1"}, {"answer": "2. We have been saved for these latter days\r\nTo build the kingdom in righteous ways.\r\nWe hear the words our prophet declares:\r\n\u201cLet each who\u2019s worthy go forth and share.\u201d\r\nWe are as the army of Helaman.\r\nWe have been taught in our youth.\r\nAnd we will be the Lord\u2019s missionaries\r\nTo bring the world his truth.", "question": "Children's Songbook 172: 2"}, {"answer": "3. We know his plan, and we will prepare,\r\nIncrease our knowledge through study and prayer.\r\nDaily we\u2019ll learn until we are called\r\nTo take the gospel to all the world.\r\nWe are as the army of Helaman.\r\nWe have been taught in our youth.\r\nAnd we will be the Lord\u2019s missionaries\r\nTo bring the world his truth.", "question": "Children's Songbook 172: 3"}, {"answer": "2. Beneath his watchful eye,\r\nHis Saints securely dwell;\r\nThat hand which bears all nature up\r\nShall guard his children well.", "question": "Hymns 125: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Why should this anxious load\r\nPress down your weary mind?\r\nHaste to your Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s throne\r\nAnd sweet refreshment find.", "question": "Hymns 125: 3"}, {"answer": "4. His goodness stands approved,\r\nUnchanged from day to day;\r\nI\u2019ll drop my burden at his feet\r\nAnd bear a song away.", "question": "Hymns 125: 4"}, {"answer": "1. Praise to the man who communed with Jehovah!\r\nJesus anointed that Prophet and Seer.\r\nBlessed to open the last dispensation,\r\nKings shall extol him, and nations revere.\r\nHail to the Prophet, ascended to heaven!\r\nTraitors and tyrants now fight him in vain.\r\nMingling with Gods, he can plan for his brethren;\r\nDeath cannot conquer the hero again.", "question": "Hymns 27: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Praise to his mem\u2019ry, he died as a martyr;\r\nHonored and blest be his ever great name!\r\nLong shall his blood, which was shed by assassins,\r\nPlead unto heav\u2019n while the earth lauds his fame.\r\nHail to the Prophet, ascended to heaven!\r\nTraitors and tyrants now fight him in vain.\r\nMingling with Gods, he can plan for his brethren;\r\nDeath cannot conquer the hero again.", "question": "Hymns 27: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Great is his glory and endless his priesthood.\r\nEver and ever the keys he will hold.\r\nFaithful and true, he will enter his kingdom,\r\nCrowned in the midst of the prophets of old.\r\nHail to the Prophet, ascended to heaven!\r\nTraitors and tyrants now fight him in vain.\r\nMingling with Gods, he can plan for his brethren;\r\nDeath cannot conquer the hero again.", "question": "Hymns 27: 3"}, {"answer": "4. Sacrifice brings forth the blessings of heaven;\r\nEarth must atone for the blood of that man.\r\nWake up the world for the conflict of justice.\r\nMillions shall know \u201cBrother Joseph\u201d again.\r\nHail to the Prophet, ascended to heaven!\r\nTraitors and tyrants now fight him in vain.\r\nMingling with Gods, he can plan for his brethren;\r\nDeath cannot conquer the hero again.", "question": "Hymns 27: 4"}, {"answer": "1. I love to see the temple.\r\nI\u2019m going there someday\r\nTo feel the Holy Spirit,\r\nTo listen and to pray.\r\nFor the temple is a house of God,\r\nA place of love and beauty.\r\nI\u2019ll prepare myself while I am young;\r\nThis is my sacred duty.", "question": "Children's Songbook 95: 1"}, {"answer": "2. I love to see the temple.\r\nI\u2019ll go inside someday.\r\nI\u2019ll cov\u2019nant with my Father;\r\nI\u2019ll promise to obey.\r\nFor the temple is a holy place\r\nWhere we are sealed together.\r\nAs a child of God, I\u2019ve learned this truth:\r\nA fam\u2019ly is forever.", "question": "Children's Songbook 95: 2"}, {"answer": "2. The Spirit, voice\r\nOf goodness, whispers to our hearts\r\nA better choice\r\nThan evil\u2019s anguished cries.\r\nLoud may the sound\r\nOf hope ring till all doubt departs,\r\nAnd we are bound\r\nTo him by loving ties.", "question": "Hymns 113: 2"}, {"answer": "1. Our Savior\u2019s love\r\nShines like the sun with perfect light,\r\nAs from above\r\nIt breaks thru clouds of strife.\r\nLighting our way,\r\nIt leads us back into his sight,\r\nWhere we may stay\r\nTo share eternal life.", "question": "Hymns 113: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Our Father, God\r\nOf all creation, hear us pray\r\nIn rev\u2019rence, awed\r\nBy thy Son\u2019s sacrifice.\r\nPraises we sing.\r\nWe love thy law; we will obey.\r\nOur heav\u2019nly King,\r\nIn thee our hearts rejoice.", "question": "Hymns 113: 3"}, {"answer": "2. The harvest is great, and the lab\u2019rers are few;\r\nBut if we\u2019re united, we all things can do.\r\nWe\u2019ll gather the wheat from the midst of the tares\r\nAnd bring them from bondage, from sorrows and snares.\r\nO Babylon, O Babylon, we bid thee farewell;\r\nWe\u2019re going to the mountains of Ephraim to dwell.", "question": "Hymns 319: 2"}, {"answer": "46 And why call ye me, Lord, Lord, and do not the things which I say?", "question": "Luke 6: 46"}, {"answer": "1. Ye elders of Israel, come join now with me\r\nAnd seek out the righteous, where\u2019er they may be\u2014\r\nIn desert, on mountain, on land, or on sea\u2014\r\nAnd bring them to Zion, the pure and the free.\r\nO Babylon, O Babylon, we bid thee farewell;\r\nWe\u2019re going to the mountains of Ephraim to dwell.", "question": "Hymns 319: 1"}, {"answer": "3. We\u2019ll go to the poor, like our Captain of old,\r\nAnd visit the weary, the hungry, and cold;\r\nWe\u2019ll cheer up their hearts with the news that he bore\r\nAnd point them to Zion and life evermore.\r\nO Babylon, O Babylon, we bid thee farewell;\r\nWe\u2019re going to the mountains of Ephraim to dwell.", "question": "Hymns 319: 3"}, {"answer": "1. Fair is the sunshine,\r\nFairer the moonlight\r\nAnd all the stars in heav\u2019n above;\r\nJesus shines brighter,\r\nJesus shines purer\r\nAnd brings to all the world his love.", "question": "Children's Songbook 62: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Fair are the meadows,\r\nFairer the woodlands,\r\nRobed in the flowers of blooming spring;\r\nJesus is fairer,\r\nJesus is purer.\r\nHe makes the sorrowing spirit sing.", "question": "Children's Songbook 62: 2"}, {"answer": "3. Beautiful Savior!\r\nLord of the nations!\r\nSon of God and Son of Man!\r\nThee will I honor, praise, and give glory,\r\nGive praise and glory evermore!\r\nEvermore!", "question": "Children's Songbook 62: 3"}, {"answer": "4 I have no greater joy than to hear that my children walk in truth.", "question": "3 John 1: 4"}, {"answer": "2. The Church has need of helping hands,\r\nAnd hearts that know and feel.\r\nThe work to do is here for you;\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel; push along,\r\nDo your duty with a heart full of song,\r\nWe all have work; let no one shirk.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.", "question": "Hymns 252: 2"}, {"answer": "1. The world has need of willing men\r\nWho wear the worker\u2019s seal.\r\nCome, help the good work move along;\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel; push along,\r\nDo your duty with a heart full of song,\r\nWe all have work; let no one shirk.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.", "question": "Hymns 252: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Then don\u2019t stand idly looking on;\r\nThe fight with sin is real.\r\nIt will be long but must go on;\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel; push along,\r\nDo your duty with a heart full of song,\r\nWe all have work; let no one shirk.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.", "question": "Hymns 252: 3"}, {"answer": "4. Then work and watch and fight and pray\r\nWith all your might and zeal.\r\nPush ev\u2019ry worthy work along;\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel; push along,\r\nDo your duty with a heart full of song,\r\nWe all have work; let no one shirk.\r\nPut your shoulder to the wheel.", "question": "Hymns 252: 4"}, {"answer": "3. Do what is right; be faithful and fearless.\r\nOnward, press onward, the goal is in sight.\r\nEyes that are wet now, ere long will be tearless.\r\nBlessings await you in doing what\u2019s right!\r\nDo what is right; let the consequence follow.\r\nBattle for freedom in spirit and might;\r\nAnd with stout hearts look ye forth till tomorrow.\r\nGod will protect you; then do what is right!", "question": "Hymns 237: 3"}, {"answer": "1. I am a child of God,\r\nAnd he has sent me here,\r\nHas given me an earthly home\r\nWith parents kind and dear.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Hymns 301: 1"}, {"answer": "2. I am a child of God,\r\nAnd so my needs are great;\r\nHelp me to understand his words\r\nBefore it grows too late.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Hymns 301: 2"}, {"answer": "3. I am a child of God.\r\nRich blessings are in store;\r\nIf I but learn to do his will\r\nI\u2019ll live with him once more.\r\nLead me, guide me, walk beside me,\r\nHelp me find the way.\r\nTeach me all that I must do\r\nTo live with him someday.", "question": "Hymns 301: 3"}, {"answer": "29 Do not anger again because of mine enemies. Do not slacken my strength because of mine afflictions.", "question": "2 Nephi 4: 29"}, {"answer": "1. Do what is right; the day-dawn is breaking,\r\nHailing a future of freedom and light.\r\nAngels above us are silent notes taking\r\nOf ev\u2019ry action; then do what is right!\r\nDo what is right; let the consequence follow.\r\nBattle for freedom in spirit and might;\r\nAnd with stout hearts look ye forth till tomorrow.\r\nGod will protect you; then do what is right!", "question": "Hymns 237: 1"}, {"answer": "2. Once a meek and lowly Lamb,\r\nNow the Lord, the great I Am.\r\nOnce upon the cross he bowed;\r\nNow his chariot is the cloud.\r\nNow his chariot is the cloud.", "question": "Hymns 196: 2"}, {"answer": "2. Do what is right; the shackles are falling.\r\nChains of the bondsmen no longer are bright;\r\nLightened by hope, soon they\u2019ll cease to be galling.\r\nTruth goeth onward; then do what is right!\r\nDo what is right; let the consequence follow.\r\nBattle for freedom in spirit and might;\r\nAnd with stout hearts look ye forth till tomorrow.\r\nGod will protect you; then do what is right!", "question": "Hymns 237: 2"}, {"answer": "21 Shall not God search this out? for he knoweth the secrets of the heart.", "question": "Psalms 44: 21"}, {"answer": "1. Jesus, once of humble birth,\r\nNow in glory comes to earth.\r\nOnce he suffered grief and pain;\r\nNow he comes on earth to reign.\r\nNow he comes on earth to reign.", "question": "Hymns 196: 1"}, {"answer": "3. Once he groaned in blood and tears;\r\nNow in glory he appears.\r\nOnce rejected by his own,\r\nNow their King he shall be known.\r\nNow their King he shall be known.", "question": "Hymns 196: 3"}, {"answer": "4. Once forsaken, left alone,\r\nNow exalted to a throne.\r\nOnce all things he meekly bore,\r\nBut he now will bear no more.\r\nBut he now will bear no more.", "question": "Hymns 196: 4"}, {"answer": "1. (Child) Teach me to walk in the light of his love;\r\nTeach me to pray to my Father above;\r\nTeach me to know of the things that are right;\r\nTeach me, teach me to walk in the light.", "question": "Children's Songbook 177: 1"}, {"answer": "2. (Parent) Come, little child, and together we\u2019ll learn\r\nOf his commandments, that we may return\r\nHome to his presence, to live in his sight\r\nAlways, always to walk in the light.", "question": "Children's Songbook 177: 2"}, {"answer": "3. (Both) Father in Heaven, we thank thee this day\r\nFor loving guidance to show us the way.\r\nGrateful, we praise thee with songs of delight!\r\nGladly, gladly we\u2019ll walk in the light.", "question": "Children's Songbook 177: 3"}, {"answer": "1. As I have loved you,\r\nLove one another.\r\nThis new commandment:\r\nLove one another.\r\nBy this shall men know\r\nYe are my disciples,\r\nIf ye have love\r\nOne to another.", "question": "Children's Songbook 136: 1"}, {"answer": "1. I have a fam\u2019ly here on earth.\r\nThey are so good to me.\r\nI want to share my life with them through all eternity.\r\nFam\u2019lies can be together forever\r\nThrough Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s plan.\r\nI always want to be with my own family,\r\nAnd the Lord has shown me how I can.\r\nThe Lord has shown me how I can.", "question": "Children's Songbook 188: 1"}, {"answer": "2. While I am in my early years,\r\nI\u2019ll prepare most carefully,\r\nSo I can marry in God\u2019s temple for eternity.\r\nFam\u2019lies can be together forever\r\nThrough Heav\u2019nly Father\u2019s plan.\r\nI always want to be with my own family,\r\nAnd the Lord has shown me how I can.\r\nThe Lord has shown me how I can.", "question": "Children's Songbook 188: 2"}, {"answer": "2. We are His children; we are His children,\r\nand we must be tested to show we are true.\r\nHold to His promises;\r\nHold to His promises,\r\nHeeding the prophets:\r\nKeep the commandments.\r\nIn this there is safety and peace.", "question": "Children's Songbook 146: 2"}, {"answer": "1. I know my Father lives and loves me too.\r\nThe Spirit whispers this to me and tells me it is true,\r\nAnd tells me it is true.", "question": "Hymns 302: 1"}, {"answer": "2. He sent me here to earth, by faith to live his plan.\r\nThe Spirit whispers this to me and tells me that I can,\r\nAnd tells me that I can.", "question": "Hymns 302: 2"}, {"answer": "1. Keep the commandments; keep the commandments!\r\nIn this there is safety; in this there is peace.\r\nHe will send blessings;\r\nHe will send blessings.\r\nWords of a prophet:\r\nKeep the commandments.\r\nIn this there is safety and peace.", "question": "Children's Songbook 146: 1"}, {"answer": "25 Husbands, love your wives, even as Christ also loved the church, and gave himself for it;", "question": "Ephesians 5: 25"}, {"answer": "19 Husbands, love your wives, and be not bitter against them.", "question": "Colossians 3: 19"}]